<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="NRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-258"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-258"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#nevada-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-nv"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="258"/>
          <FRBRname value="NRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-258/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-258/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-258/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-258/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="nevada-legislature" href="https://www.leg.state.nv.us" showAs="Nevada State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_258">
        <num>258</num>
        <heading>CONSTABLES</heading>
        <section eId="sec_258-001">
          <num>258.001</num>
          <heading>Definitions.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>As
used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires, the words and
terms defined inNRS 258.002to258.004, inclusive, have the meanings
ascribed to them in those sections.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2013,
2946; A2019,
1554)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-002">
          <num>258.002</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Category I peace officerï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Category
I peace officerï¿½ has the meaning ascribed to it inNRS 289.460.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2013,
2946)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-003">
          <num>258.003</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Category II peace officerï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Category
II peace officerï¿½ has the meaning ascribed to it inNRS 289.470.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2013,
2946)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-0035">
          <num>258.0035</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Enterprise fundï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Enterprise
fundï¿½ has the meaning ascribed to it inNRS
354.517.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2019,
1554)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-004">
          <num>258.004</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Peace officerï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Peace
officerï¿½ has the meaning ascribed to it inNRS
289.010.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2013,
2946)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-005">
          <num>258.005</num>
          <heading>General qualifications.</heading>
          <subsection eId="258-005__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>No person is eligible to the office of
constable unless the person:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="258-005__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Will have attained the age of 21 years on the
date he or she would take office if so elected or appointed; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="258-005__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Is a qualified elector.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-005__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who has been convicted of a
felony in this state or any other state is not qualified to be a candidate for
or elected or appointed to the office of constable regardless of whether the
person has been restored to his or her civil rights.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2003,
2135,2696)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-007">
          <num>258.007</num>
          <heading>Certification as category I or category II peace officer
required in certain townships; forfeiture of office.</heading>
          <subsection eId="258-007__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 2, each constable of a township whose population is 15,000 or more
or a township that has within its boundaries a city whose population is 15,000
or more shall become certified by the Peace Officersï¿½ Standards and Training
Commission as a category I or category II peace officer within 1 year after the
date on which the constable commences his or her term of office or appointment
unless the Commission, for good cause shown, grants in writing an extension of
time, which must not exceed 6 months.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-007__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person who is a candidate for the
office of constable in a township whose population is 100,000 or more must be
certified by the Peace Officersï¿½ Standards and Training Commission as a
category I or category II peace officer before filing a declaration of
candidacy for the office. A person who does not comply with the provisions of
this subsection is not eligible to be a candidate for the office of constable.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-007__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A constable forfeits his or her office
and a vacancy is created which must be filled in accordance withNRS 258.030if the constable:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="258-007__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Does not become certified by the Peace
Officersï¿½ Standards and Training Commission as required pursuant to subsection
1; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="258-007__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Does not maintain the certification by the
Peace Officersï¿½ Standards and Training Commission required pursuant to
subsection 1 or 2 during his or her term of office.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2013,
2946; A2015,
2516;2019,
1554)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-010">
          <num>258.010</num>
          <heading>Election; appointment of sheriff to serve ex officio; term of
office; abolition of office.</heading>
          <subsection eId="258-010__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in subsections
2 and 3:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="258-010__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Constables must be elected by the qualified
electors of their respective townships.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="258-010__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The constables of the several townships of
the State must be chosen at the general election of 1966, and shall enter upon
the duties of their offices on the first Monday of January next succeeding
their election, and hold their offices for the term of 4 years thereafter,
until their successors are elected and qualified.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="258-010__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Constables must receive certificates of
election from the boards of county commissioners of their respective counties.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-010__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In a county which includes only one
township, the board of county commissioners may, by resolution, appoint the
sheriff ex officio constable to serve without additional compensation. The
resolution must not become effective until the completion of the term of office
for which a constable may have been elected.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-010__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In a county whose population:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="258-010__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Is less than 700,000, which includes more
than one township, if the board of county commissioners determines that the
office of constable is not necessary in one or more townships within the
county, it may, by ordinance, abolish the office of constable in those
townships.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="258-010__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Is 700,000 or more, if the board of county
commissioners determines that the office of constable is not necessary in one
or more townships within the county, it may, by ordinance, abolish the office
in those townships.
ï¿½For a
township in which the office of constable has been abolished, the board of
county commissioners may, by resolution, appoint the sheriff ex officio
constable to serve without additional compensation.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 1:108:1866; B ï¿½ 2599; BH ï¿½ 1636; C ï¿½ 1782; RL ï¿½
2765; NCL ï¿½ 4765] + [Part 9:108:1866; B ï¿½ 2607; BH ï¿½ 1644; C ï¿½ 1790; RL ï¿½ 2773;
NCL ï¿½ 4773] + [Part 18:108:1866; B ï¿½ 2616; BH ï¿½ 1653; C ï¿½ 1799; RL ï¿½ 2782; NCL
ï¿½ 4782] + [Part 30:108:1866; B ï¿½ 2628; BH ï¿½ 1665; C ï¿½ 1811; RL ï¿½ 2794; NCL ï¿½
4794]—(NRS A1965,
724;1967,
455;1975,
1421;1979,
524,1729;1989,
1906;1997,
218;2011,
1129;2015,
2516)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-020">
          <num>258.020</num>
          <heading>Oath and bond.</heading>
          <subsection eId="258-020__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Take the oath prescribed by law. The
oath must be filed and recorded in a book provided for that purpose in the
office of the recorder of the county within which the constable legally holds
and exercises his or her office.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-020__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Execute a bond to the State of Nevada,
to be approved by the board of county commissioners, in the penal sum of not
less than $1,000 nor more than $3,000, as may be designated by the board of
county commissioners. The bond must be conditioned for the faithful performance
of the duties of his or her office and must be filed in the county clerkï¿½s
office.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [2:7:1873; B ï¿½ 2979; BH ï¿½ 2255; C ï¿½ 2422; RL ï¿½ 4928; NCL
ï¿½ 8475]—(NRS A2013,
2947)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-030">
          <num>258.030</num>
          <heading>Vacancy when office not abolished: Applicable law governing
appointment.</heading>
          <subsection eId="258-030__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The clerk of the board of county
commissioners shall certify the vacancy to the Secretary of State not later
than 10 days after the vacancy occurs; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-030__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The board of county commissioners shall
appoint a person to fill the vacancy pursuant toNRS 245.170not later than 60 days after
the vacancy occurs.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 49:108:1866; A1933,
165;1939,
146; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 4813]—(NRS A1975,
1422;1997,
1292;2019,
1555)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-040">
          <num>258.040</num>
          <heading>Compensation.</heading>
          <subsection eId="258-040__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The several boards of county
commissioners of each county, at the regular meeting in July of any year in
which an election of constables is held, shall fix the minimum compensation of
the constables within their respective townships for the ensuing term, either
by stated salaries, payable monthly, semimonthly or at regular 26-week
intervals, or by fees, as provided by law, or both, and they may thereafter
increase or change such compensation during the term but shall not reduce it
below the minimum so established.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-040__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If it becomes necessary to appoint a
constable at any time, the board of county commissioners in the county in which
such appointment is made shall fix the compensation, either by salary or by
fees, as provided by law, or both, for the term for which the constable is
appointed.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 1:12:1929; A1953,
202] + [Part 2:12:1929; NCL ï¿½ 2202] + [Part 3:12:1929; NCL ï¿½ 2203]—(NRS A1973,
292)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-050">
          <num>258.050</num>
          <heading>Expenses; claims.</heading>
          <subsection eId="258-050__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When any constable shall be entitled to
receive necessary traveling expenses for the transaction of public business,
such expenses shall include the constableï¿½s actual living expenses, but the
amount allowed for traveling by private conveyance shall not exceed the amount
charged by public conveyance.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-050__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Where it appears to the satisfaction of
the board of county commissioners that travel by private conveyance is more
economical, or where it appears that, owing to train, airplane or bus schedule
or for other reasons, travel by public conveyance is impractical, or in case a
part of the route traveled is not covered by public conveyance, the board of
county commissioners is authorized to allow for traveling by private conveyance
an amount not to exceed the maximum per-mile allowance for travel by private
conveyance established by the State Board of Examiners for state officers and
employees generally.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-050__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any constable presenting a claim to the
county for any expenses allowed by law shall attach itemized vouchers and
receipts for the same to his or her claim, and the boards of county
commissioners of the several counties are hereby prohibited from allowing such
claim unless accompanied by vouchers and receipts as required by this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 1:16:1928; A1939,
31;1953,
69;1955,
596]—(NRS A1973,
1675;2007,
601)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-060">
          <num>258.060</num>
          <heading>Deputies; certification of deputy as category I or category II
peace officer required in certain townships.</heading>
          <subsection eId="258-060__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>All constables may appoint deputies,
who are authorized to transact all official business pertaining to the office
to the same extent as their principals. A person must not be appointed as a
deputy constable unless the person has been a resident of the State of Nevada
for at least 6 months before the date of the appointment. A person who is
appointed as a deputy constable in a township whose population is 15,000 or
more or a township that has within its boundaries a city whose population is
15,000 or more may not commence employment as a deputy constable until the
person is certified by the Peace Officersï¿½ Standards and Training Commission as
a category I or category II peace officer. The appointment of a deputy
constable must not be construed to confer upon that deputy policymaking
authority for the office of the county constable or the county by which the
deputy constable is employed.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-060__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Constables are responsible for the
compensation of their deputies and are responsible on their official bonds for
all official malfeasance or nonfeasance of the same. Bonds for the faithful
performance of their official duties may be required of the deputies by the
constables.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-060__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a constable of an office established
by the board of county commissioners as an enterprise fund appoints a deputy,
the compensation of the deputy must be approved by the board of county
commissioners.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-060__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>All appointments of deputies under the
provisions of this section must be in writing and must, together with the oath
of office of the deputies, be filed and recorded within 30 days after the
appointment in a book provided for that purpose in the office of the recorder
of the county within which the constable legally holds and exercises his or her
office. Revocations of such appointments must also be filed and recorded as
provided in this section within 30 days after the revocation of the
appointment. From the time of the filing of the appointments or revocations
therein, persons shall be deemed to have notice of the same.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 1:101:1864; A1905,
33;1913,
108; 1919 RL ï¿½ 2848; NCL ï¿½ 4848] + [Part 2:101:1864; B ï¿½ 3068; BH ï¿½ 2280; C
ï¿½ 2452; RL ï¿½ 2849; NCL ï¿½ 4849] + [3:101:1864; B ï¿½ 3069; BH ï¿½ 2281; C ï¿½ 2453; RL
ï¿½ 2850; NCL ï¿½ 4850]—(NRS A2005,
683;2013,
2947;2015,
2516;2019,
1555)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-065">
          <num>258.065</num>
          <heading>Clerical and operational staff: Appointment; powers; oath; bond;
compensation; duties.</heading>
          <subsection eId="258-065__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The constable of a township may,
subject to the approval of the board of county commissioners, appoint such
clerical and operational staff as the work of the constable requires. The
compensation of any person so appointed must be fixed by the board of county
commissioners.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-065__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who is employed as clerical or
operational staff of a constable:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="258-065__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Does not have the powers of a peace officer;
and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="258-065__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>May not possess a weapon or carry a firearm,
regardless of whether the person possesses a permit to carry a concealed
firearm issued pursuant toNRS 202.3653to202.369, inclusive, while performing
the duties of the office of the constable.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-065__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The board of county commissioners may
appoint for the constable of a township a reasonable number of clerks. The
compensation of any clerk so appointed must be fixed by the board of county
commissioners.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-065__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A constableï¿½s clerk shall take the
constitutional oath of office and give bond in the sum of $2,000 for the
faithful discharge of the duties of the office, and in the same manner as is or
may be required of other officers of that township and county.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-065__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A constableï¿½s clerk shall do all
clerical work in connection with keeping the records and files of the office,
and shall perform such other duties in connection with the office as the
constable shall prescribe.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1957,
35; A1963,
454,1297;1979,
525;1981,
171;2013,
2947;2015,
2517;2019,
1555)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-070">
          <num>258.070</num>
          <heading>Duties and powers of constable or deputy; circumstances under
which constable or deputy has powers of peace officer and may carry firearm;
certain constables and deputies required to wear badges; duties and powers of
sheriff or deputy.</heading>
          <subsection eId="258-070__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Subject to the provisions of
subsections 2 and 3, each constable shall:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="258-070__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Be a peace officer.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="258-070__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Execute the process, writs or warrants of
courts of justice, judicial officers and coroners, when delivered to the
constable for that purpose.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="258-070__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Discharge such other duties as are or may be
prescribed by law.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-070__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Subject to the provisions of subsection
3, a constable or deputy constable has the powers of a peace officer:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="258-070__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For the discharge of duties as are or may be
prescribed by law;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="258-070__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For the purpose of arresting a person for a
public offense committed or attempted in the presence of the constable or
deputy constable, if the constable or deputy constable has reasonable cause to
believe that the arrest is necessary to prevent harm to other persons or the
escape of the person who committed or attempted the public offense; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="258-070__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In addition to the circumstances described in
paragraphs</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="258-070__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="258-070__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="258-070__subsec_2__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>In an area within the limits of an
incorporated city, for the purposes authorized by and with the consent of the
chief of police of the city; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="258-070__subsec_2__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>In an area that is not within the
limits of an incorporated city, for the purposes authorized by and with the
consent of the sheriff of the county.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-070__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The constable and each deputy constable
of a township shall not carry a firearm in the performance of his or her duties
unless:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="258-070__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The constable has adopted a written policy on
the use of deadly force by the constable and each deputy constable; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="258-070__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The constable and each deputy constable has
received training regarding the policy.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-070__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A constable or deputy constable
authorized to carry a firearm pursuant to subsection 3 must receive training
approved by the Peace Officersï¿½ Standards and Training Commission in the use of
firearms at least once every 6 months.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-070__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A constable or deputy constable who
wears a uniform in the performance of his or her duties shall display
prominently as part of that uniform a badge, nameplate or other uniform piece
which clearly displays the name or an identification number of the constable or
deputy constable.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-070__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Pursuant to the procedures and subject
to the limitations set forth inchapters 482and484Ato484E,
inclusive, of NRS, a constable may issue a citation to an owner or driver, as
appropriate, of a vehicle which is located in his or her township at the time
the citation is issued and which is required to be registered in this State if
the constable determines that the vehicle is not properly registered. Upon the
imposition of punishment pursuant toNRS
482.385on the person to whom the citation is issued, the constable is
entitled to charge and collect a fee of $100 from the person to whom the
citation is issued, which:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="258-070__subsec_6__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Must be collected by a court that imposes
punishment pursuant toNRS 482.385on
behalf of the constable who issued the citation and forwarded by the court to
the constable; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="258-070__subsec_6__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>May be retained by the constable as
compensation.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-070__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a sheriff or the sheriffï¿½s deputy in
any county in this State arrests a person charged with a criminal offense or in
the commission of an offense, the sheriff or the sheriffï¿½s deputy shall serve
all process, whether mesne or final, and attend the court executing the order
thereof in the prosecution of the person so arrested, whether in a justice
court or a district court, to the conclusion, and whether the offense is an
offense of which a justice of the peace has jurisdiction, or whether the
proceeding is a preliminary examination or hearing. The sheriff or the
sheriffï¿½s deputy shall collect the same fees and in the same manner therefor as
the constable of the township in which the justice court is held would receive
for the same service.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [6:82:1861; A1887,
134; C ï¿½ 2321; RL ï¿½ 1692; NCL ï¿½ 2192]—(NRS A1991,
408;2001,
1456;2009,
3012;2013,
2948;2015,
2517;2019,
1556)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-0703">
          <num>258.0703</num>
          <heading>Processes, writs and orders: Endorsement and memorandum of
receipt.</heading>
          <subsection eId="258-0703__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Forthwith endorse upon it the year,
month, day and hour of its receipt.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-0703__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Give to the person delivering it, if
required, on payment of his or her fee, a written memorandum signed by him or
her, stating the names of the parties in the process or order, the nature
thereof and the time it was received. He or she shall deliver to the party
served a copy thereof, if required to do so, without charge to such party.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2015,
2514)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-0705">
          <num>258.0705</num>
          <heading>Processes, writs and orders: Service or execution; return;
liability for damages.</heading>
          <subsection eId="258-0705__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A constable to whom any process, writ,
order or paper is delivered shall:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="258-0705__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Execute the same with diligence, according to
its command or as required by law.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="258-0705__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Return it without delay to the proper court
or officer, with his or her certificate endorsed thereon of the manner of its
service or execution, or, if not served or executed, the reasons for his or her
failure.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-0705__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A constable who fails to comply with
subsection 1 is liable to the party aggrieved for all damages sustained by the
party on account of such neglect.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2015,
2515)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-0707">
          <num>258.0707</num>
          <heading>Liability for neglect or refusal to attach, levy upon or sell
property pursuant to writ of execution or attachment.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If
the constable to whom a writ of execution or writ of attachment is delivered
neglects or refuses, after being required by the creditor or the creditorï¿½s
attorney to attach, or to levy upon or sell, any property of the party charged
in the writ which is liable to be attached or levied upon and sold, the
constable is liable on his or her official bond to the creditor for the value
of such property.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2015,
2515)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-075">
          <num>258.075</num>
          <heading>Report of deaths to public administrator or certain other person
in certain counties.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>In counties
having a population of less than 100,000, every constable shall report
immediately to the public administrator or a person employed or contracted with
pursuant toNRS 253.125, as applicable,
all deaths which the constable gains knowledge of in the performance of his or
her duties.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1971,
508; A1979,
525;2019,
1543)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-080">
          <num>258.080</num>
          <heading>Duties in new township.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>When
any constable, by the formation of a new township, shall be brought within the
limits thereof, the constable shall continue to act as constable for such new
township, and shall continue in office until the expiration of the term for
which he or she was elected.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [21:108:1866; B ï¿½ 2619; BH ï¿½ 1656; C ï¿½ 1802; RL ï¿½
2785; NCL ï¿½ 4785]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-090">
          <num>258.090</num>
          <heading>Liability on bond: Tender of fees and indemnity bond.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>No constable shall be liable for any damages
for neglecting or refusing to serve any civil process, unless the constableï¿½s
legal fees (and an indemnifying bond in cases where the constable has doubts as
to the ownership of the property sought to be levied upon or attached, if the
same shall be required by the constable) are first tendered him or her.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [17:38:1861; A1935,
119; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 2160]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-110">
          <num>258.110</num>
          <heading>Unlawful failure to arrest offender; penalty.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Any constable who willfully refuses to arrest
any person charged with a criminal offense is guilty of a gross misdemeanor and
shall be removed from office.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 67:108:1866; B ï¿½ 2665; BH ï¿½ 1702; C ï¿½ 1848; RL
ï¿½ 2820; NCL ï¿½ 4820]—(NRS A1967,
542;2013,
2948;2015,
2519)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-120">
          <num>258.120</num>
          <heading>Purchasing judgment prohibited; penalty.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If any constable shall, directly or
indirectly, purchase any judgment, or any part thereof, on the docket of any
justice of the peace of the same township, the constable is guilty of a
misdemeanor.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 68:108:1866; B ï¿½ 2666; BH ï¿½ 1703; C ï¿½ 1849; RL
ï¿½ 2821; NCL ï¿½ 4821]—(NRS A1967,
542)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-125">
          <num>258.125</num>
          <heading>Fees; expenses; accounting.</heading>
          <subsection eId="258-125__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Constables are entitled to the
following fees for their services:
For serving a summons
or any other process in civil cases............................ $17
For summoning a jury
before a justice of the peace............................................. 7
For taking a bond or
undertaking............................................................................. 5
For serving an
attachment against the property of a defendant........................ 15
For serving subpoenas,
for each witness.............................................................. 15
For a copy of any
writ, process or order or other paper, when demanded or required by law, per
folioï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ 3
For drawing and
executing every constableï¿½s deed, to be paid by the grantee, who must also pay
for the acknowledgment thereof.................................................................................................................. 20
For each certificate
of sale of real property under execution.............................. 5
For levying any writ
of execution or writ of garnishment, or executing an order of arrest in civil
cases, order for delivery of personal property or any other order in a civil
case, except an order of eviction, with traveling fees as for summons............................................................................................................................... 15
For serving one
notice required by law before the commencement of a proceeding for any type of
evictionï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ 26
For serving not fewer
than 2 nor more than 10 such notices to the same location, each noticeï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ 20
For serving not fewer
than 11 nor more than 24 such notices to the same location, each noticeï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ 17
For serving 25 or
more such notices to the same location, each notice.......... 15
Except as otherwise
provided in subsection 3, for mileage in serving such a notice, for each mile
necessarily and actually traveled in going only.......................................................................................... 2
But if two or more
notices are served at the same general location during the same period, mileage
may only be charged for the service of one notice.
For each service in a
summary eviction, except service of any notice required by law before
commencement of the proceeding, and for serving notice of and executing a writ
of restitution 21
For making and
posting notices, and advertising property for sale on execution, not to include
the cost of publication in a newspaper.................................................................................................... 15
For each warrant
lawfully executed, unless a higher amount is established by the board of county
commissioners............................................................................................................................... 48
For mailing a notice
of a writ of execution............................................................. 2
Except as otherwise
provided in subsection 3, for mileage in serving summons, attachment,
execution, order, venire, subpoena, notice, summary eviction, writ of
restitution or other process in civil suits, for each mile necessarily and
actually traveled, in going only.......................................................................... 2
But when two or more
persons are served in the same suit, mileage may only be charged for the most
distant, if they live in the same direction.
Except as otherwise
provided in subsection 3, for mileage in making a diligent but unsuccessful
effort to serve a summons, attachment, execution, order, venire, subpoena or
other process in civil suits, for each mile necessarily and actually traveled,
in going only.................................................................. 2
But mileage may not
exceed $20 for any unsuccessful effort to serve such process.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-125__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A constable is also entitled to
receive:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="258-125__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For receiving and taking care of property on
execution, attachment or order, and for executing an order of arrest in civil
cases, compensation for the constableï¿½s trouble and expense, to be allowed by
the court which issued the writ or order, upon the affidavit of the constable
that the charges are correct and the expenses necessarily incurred.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="258-125__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For collecting all sums on execution or writ,
to be charged against the defendant, on the first $3,500, 2 percent thereof,
and on all amounts over that sum, 1 percent.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="258-125__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For service in criminal cases, the same fees
as are allowed sheriffs for like services, to be allowed, audited and paid as
are other claims against the county.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="258-125__subsec_2__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For removing or causing the removal of,
pursuant toNRS 487.230, a vehicle that
has been abandoned on public property, $100.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="258-125__subsec_2__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For providing any other service authorized by
law for which no fee is established by this chapter, the fee provided for by
ordinance by the board of county commissioners.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-125__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>For each service for which a constable
is otherwise entitled pursuant to subsection 1 to a fee based on the mileage
necessarily and actually traveled in performing the service, a board of county
commissioners may provide by ordinance for the constable to be entitled, at the
option of the person paying the fee, to a flat fee for the travel costs of that
service.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-125__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Deputy sheriffs acting as constables
are not entitled to retain for their own use any fees collected by them, but
the fees must be paid into the county treasury on or before the fifth working
day of the month next succeeding the month in which the fees were collected.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-125__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 6, constables shall, on or before the fifth working day of each
month, account for and pay to the county treasurer all fees collected during
the preceding month, except fees which may be retained as compensation.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-125__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every 5 business days, constables in an
office established by the board of county commissioners as an enterprise fund
shall account for and pay to the county treasurer any fee collected during the
preceding period.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1959,
610; A1961,
685;1973,
1642;1975,
313;1979,
1032;1981,
365;1985,
1009;1987,
651;1991,
408;1993,
266;2001,
3212; 2007,104;2009,
3013;2015,
2519;2017,
1055;2019,
1557)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-135">
          <num>258.135</num>
          <heading>Acceptance of credit card, debit card or electronic transfer of
money for payment of fees owed constable; convenience fee.</heading>
          <subsection eId="258-135__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A constable may enter into contracts
with issuers of credit cards or debit cards or operators of systems that
provide for the electronic transfer of money to provide for the acceptance of
credit cards, debit cards or electronic transfers of money by the constable for
the payment of fees to which the constable is entitled.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-135__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the issuer or operator charges the
constable a fee for each use of a credit card or debit card or for each
electronic transfer of money, the constable may require the cardholder or the
person requesting the electronic transfer of money to pay a convenience fee.
The total convenience fees charged by the constable in a fiscal year must not
exceed the total amount of fees charged to the constable by the issuer or
operator in that fiscal year.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-135__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="258-135__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Cardholderï¿½ means the person or organization
named on the face of a credit card or debit card to whom or for whose benefit
the credit card or debit card is issued by an issuer.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="258-135__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Convenience feeï¿½ means a fee paid by a
cardholder or person requesting the electronic transfer of money to a constable
for the convenience of using the credit card or debit card or the electronic
transfer of money to make such payment.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="258-135__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Credit cardï¿½ means any instrument or device,
whether known as a credit card or credit plate or by any other name, issued
with or without a fee by an issuer for the use of the cardholder in obtaining
money, property, goods, services or anything else of value on credit.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="258-135__subsec_3__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Debit cardï¿½ means any instrument or device,
whether known as a debit card or by any other name, issued with or without a
fee by an issuer for the use of the cardholder in depositing, obtaining or
transferring funds.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="258-135__subsec_3__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Electronic transfer of moneyï¿½ has the
meaning ascribed to it inNRS 463.01473.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="258-135__subsec_3__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Issuerï¿½ means a business organization,
financial institution or authorized agent of a business organization or
financial institution that issues a credit card or debit card.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2015,
2515)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-170">
          <num>258.170</num>
          <heading>No other fees to be charged.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>No
other fees shall be charged by constables than those specifically set forth in
this chapter, nor shall fees be charged for any other services than those
mentioned in this chapter.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 17:49:1883; BH ï¿½ 2358; C ï¿½ 2482; RL ï¿½ 2019; NCL
ï¿½ 2950]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-180">
          <num>258.180</num>
          <heading>Fee book.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Every
constable shall keep in his or her office a fee book in which the constable
shall enter in detail the title of the matter, proceeding or action, and the
fees charged therein. The fee book shall be open to public inspection.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 18:49:1883; BH ï¿½ 2359; C ï¿½ 2483; RL ï¿½ 2020; NCL
ï¿½ 2951]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-190">
          <num>258.190</num>
          <heading>Quarterly financial statements.</heading>
          <subsection eId="258-190__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In each calendar year, on the first
Monday of January, April, July and October, the constables who receive fees
under the provisions of this chapter shall make out and file with the boards of
county commissioners of their several counties a full and correct statement
under oath of all fees or compensation, of whatever nature or kind, received in
their several official capacities during the preceding 3 months. In the
statement they shall set forth the cause in which, and the services for which,
such fees or compensation were received.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="258-190__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Nothing in this section shall be so
construed as to require personal attendance in filing statements, which may be
transmitted by mail or otherwise directed to the clerk of the board of county
commissioners.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 19:49:1883; BH ï¿½ 2360; C ï¿½ 2484; RL ï¿½ 2021; NCL
ï¿½ 2952]—(NRS A2013,
2949)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-200">
          <num>258.200</num>
          <heading>Failure to comply with certain statutory requirements: Penalty.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Any constable who shall violate any of the
provisions ofNRS 258.170,258.180and258.190shall be fined not more than
$1,000.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 21:49:1883; BH ï¿½ 2362; C ï¿½ 2486; RL ï¿½ 2023; NCL
ï¿½ 2954]—(NRS A1967,
542)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-205">
          <num>258.205</num>
          <heading>Penalties for failure of constable to file report, oath or other
document with county or Peace Officersï¿½ Standards and Training Commission.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to any fine imposed pursuant toNRS 258.200, a board of county
commissioners may establish, by resolution or ordinance, penalties for the
failure of the constable of a township in the county to file any report, oath
or other document required by statute to be filed with the county or the Peace
Officersï¿½ Standards and Training Commission.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2013,
2947)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-210">
          <num>258.210</num>
          <heading>Punishment for taking excessive fees.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If
any constable shall take more or greater fees than are allowed by law, the
constable shall be liable to indictment, and on conviction shall be removed
from office and fined in any sum not exceeding $1,000.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 22:49:1883; BH ï¿½ 2363; C ï¿½ 2487; RL ï¿½ 2024; NCL
ï¿½ 2955]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-220">
          <num>258.220</num>
          <heading>Table of fees to be posted; penalties.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Any
constable receiving fees as provided by law shall publish and set up in some
conspicuous place in his or her office a fee table for public inspection. A sum
not exceeding $20 for each day of the constableï¿½s omission so to do shall be
forfeited, which sum with costs may be recovered by any person by an action
before any justice of the peace of the same county.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 23:49:1883; BH ï¿½ 2364; C ï¿½ 2488; RL ï¿½ 2025; NCL
ï¿½ 2956]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-230">
          <num>258.230</num>
          <heading>Fees payable in advance; execution.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Except
with respect to the fees described in paragraphs (a) and (d) of subsection 2 ofNRS 258.125, all fees prescribed in this
chapter shall be payable in advance, if demanded. If a constable shall not have
received any or all of his or her fees, which may be due the constable for
services rendered by him or her in any suit or proceedings, the constable may
have execution therefor in his or her own name against the party or parties
from whom they are due, to be issued from the court where the action is
pending, upon the order of the justice of the peace or court upon affidavit filed.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 25:49:1883; BH ï¿½ 2366; C ï¿½ 2490; RL ï¿½ 2027; NCL
ï¿½ 2958]—(NRS A2007,
105;2011,
1908)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_258-240">
          <num>258.240</num>
          <heading>Limitation on mileage.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>When
any constable serves more than one process in the same cause, not requiring
more than one journey from his or her office, the constable shall receive
mileage only for the most distant service.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 35:49:1883; BH ï¿½ 2376; C ï¿½ 2500; RL ï¿½ 2037; NCL
ï¿½ 2968]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>