<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="NRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-575"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-575"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#nevada-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-nv"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="575"/>
          <FRBRname value="NRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-575/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-575/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-575/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-575/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="nevada-legislature" href="https://www.leg.state.nv.us" showAs="Nevada State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_575">
        <num>575</num>
        <heading>MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS;</heading>
        <section eId="sec_575-010">
          <num>575.010</num>
          <heading>Working horse, mule or cattle without consent of owner.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If any person shall use or work any horse or
horses, mule or mules, or work cattle without first obtaining the consent of
the owner thereof, the person shall be guilty of a misdemeanor.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 479; RL ï¿½ 6744; NCL ï¿½ 10428]—(NRS A1967,
618)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_575-015">
          <num>575.015</num>
          <heading>Contracts for care or shelter of livestock: Notice of
termination; removal of livestock; disposition of livestock; collection of
costs; waiver of provisions and rights conferred; exclusive remedies.</heading>
          <subsection eId="575-015__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who enters into a contract with
an owner of livestock to provide care or shelter for the livestock on the
personï¿½s property shall give the owner of the livestock at least 30 daysï¿½
notice before terminating the contract.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-015__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>After receiving the notice, if the
owner of the livestock fails to remove the livestock from the property before
the termination of the contract, the livestock shall be deemed abandoned and
the person providing care or shelter for the livestock may remove the livestock
from his or her property as provided in subsection 3 if:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="575-015__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The person notifies the owner of the
livestock in writing of the personï¿½s intention to remove the livestock from the
property if the owner fails to remove the livestock before the date the
contract is terminated; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="575-015__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Fourteen days have elapsed since the notice
was mailed to the owner of the livestock. The notice must be mailed, by
certified mail, return receipt requested, to the owner of the livestock at the
ownerï¿½s present address, and if that address is unknown, then at the ownerï¿½s
last known address.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-015__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any livestock is deemed abandoned
pursuant to subsection 2, a person providing care or shelter for that livestock
may:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="575-015__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Sell the livestock;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="575-015__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Give the livestock to a society for the
prevention of cruelty to animals;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="575-015__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Return the livestock to the owner at the
ownerï¿½s present address;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="575-015__subsec_3__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Transfer the livestock to another facility
which is able to provide care and shelter for the livestock; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="575-015__subsec_3__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Bring a civil action in a court of competent
jurisdiction to require the owner to remove the livestock from the personï¿½s
property.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-015__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the owner of the livestock fails to
remove the livestock pursuant to subsection 2, the person providing care and
shelter for the livestock may charge and collect any reasonable and actual
costs he or she incurs in removing the livestock pursuant to subsection 3.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-015__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 6, the provisions of this section may be varied by agreement, and
the rights conferred by this section may be waived.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-015__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The remedies provided for in this section
are the exclusive remedies for an action brought pursuant to this section. If a
person pursues a remedy not provided for in this section including, without
limitation, a civil action for breach of contract or trespass, the provisions
of this section do not apply, and the remedies provided for in this section are
not available.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-015__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, ï¿½livestockï¿½
means:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="575-015__subsec_7__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>All cattle or animals of the bovine species;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="575-015__subsec_7__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>All horses, mules, burros and asses or
animals of the equine species;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="575-015__subsec_7__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>All swine or animals of the porcine species;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="575-015__subsec_7__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>All goats or animals of the caprine species;
and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="575-015__subsec_7__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>All sheep or animals of the ovine species.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2011,
2619)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_575-020">
          <num>575.020</num>
          <heading>Allowing vicious animal to escape or run at large; penalty;
vicious animal may be killed; liability of person having care or custody of
animal which chases, worries, injures or kills livestock of another.</heading>
          <subsection eId="575-020__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every person having the care or custody
of any animal known to possess any vicious or dangerous tendencies, who allows
it to escape or run at large in any place or manner liable to endanger the
safety of any person, is guilty of a misdemeanor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-020__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person may lawfully and without
liability for damages kill such an animal when reasonably necessary to protect
his or her own safety or the public safety, or if the animal chases, worries,
injures or kills the personï¿½s livestock on the land of any person other than
that of the owner of the animal.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-020__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every person having the care or custody
of an animal which chases, worries, injures or kills the livestock of another
on land other than his or her own is liable to the owner of the livestock for
damage to it.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-020__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, ï¿½livestockï¿½
means all animals of the bovine, caprine, equine, ovine and porcine species,
and all domesticated fowl and rabbits.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 326; RL ï¿½ 6591; NCL ï¿½ 10274]—(NRS A1979,
1395)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_575-040">
          <num>575.040</num>
          <heading>Liability for damages caused by poisonous or injurious liquid.</heading>
          <subsection eId="575-040__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person who maintains, dumps, turns
or flows, or causes to be maintained, dumped, turned or flowed, any solution,
compound, waste, water or anything of a liquid nature poisonous or injurious to
or which might or does kill livestock, into an open ditch, cut, flume, pond,
reservoir or any other place, unless the ditch, cut, flume, pond, reservoir or
place is enclosed by fence or otherwise safeguarded sufficiently to prevent livestock
gaining access thereto, is liable for all damages caused by or the result of
such act or acts.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-040__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person violating subsection 1, or
who fails properly to enclose and safeguard any solution, compound, waste,
water or anything of a liquid nature injurious to or which might or does kill
livestock, maintained, dumped or flowed by the person, is liable to the owner
of livestock affected for all damages the result of the personï¿½s failure to
enclose and safeguard the solution, compound, waste, water or anything of a
liquid nature, together with costs of suit and counsel fees in a reasonable
amount, to be fixed by the court trying an action therefor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1:61:1919; 1919 RL p. 2917; NCL ï¿½ 5636] +
[2:61:1919; 1919 RL p. 2917; NCL ï¿½ 5637] + [3:61:1919; 1919 RL p. 2917; NCL ï¿½
5638]—(NRS A1985,
528)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_575-050">
          <num>575.050</num>
          <heading>Governor authorized to enter into agreements with United States
concerning financial aid; Livestock Aid Fund.</heading>
          <subsection eId="575-050__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Governor may enter into agreements
with the United States, its departments or agencies, respecting the granting
and extending of financial aid, or any other form of benefits, to the State for
the benefit of persons, firms or corporations engaged in the livestock or
agriculture industry.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-050__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Before any such agreement is entered
into, the Governor, after diligent inquiry, shall determine by proclamation
that such an emergency exists as in the interests of the livestock or
agriculture industry of the State warrants a request for federal aid, money or
such other type of benefit as may be available. After issuing the proclamation,
the Governor may match available federal money, or benefits, from the Livestock
Aid Fund, not to exceed the total sum of $30,000. If an emergency has been
proclaimed by the Governor, the Director of the State Department of Agriculture
may expend money in the Livestock Aid Fund, as the interests of the livestock
or agriculture industry of the State may require, without federal participation
in the form of aid, money or other benefits.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-050__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>There is hereby created in the State
Treasury the Livestock Aid Fund. Money for the Livestock Aid Fund must be
provided as needed by the State Board of Examiners from its Emergency Fund, and
may be used only to carry out the provisions of this section.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-050__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Governor, or such commission,
department or agency of the State of Nevada as the Governor may designate and
entrust with the disbursement of the money or benefits made available, may
adopt such regulations as may be necessary for the proper administration
thereof, and if the benefits are in the form of money, each expenditure from
the Fund must be approved by the State Board of Examiners in the manner
provided generally for the payment of claims against the State.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-050__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The State of Nevada, through the acts
of its Governor, in accepting the agreements entered into, is obligated to
perform the agreements fully as to all the terms thereof for the duration of
the agreements.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1:9:1954] + [2:9:1954] + [3:9:1954] + [4:9:1954] +
[5:9:1954]—(NRS A1961,
555;1963,
101;1971,
123;1977,
329;1993,
1759;1999,
3699)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_575-060">
          <num>575.060</num>
          <heading>Impounding and sale by State Department of Agriculture of
cattle, horses and mules found in possession of person without evidence of
ownership; disposition of proceeds.</heading>
          <subsection eId="575-060__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, unless the
context otherwise requires, ï¿½Departmentï¿½ means the State Department of
Agriculture.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-060__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any cattle, horses or mules found by
the Department or an authorized representative of the Department to be in the
possession of any person who does not have satisfactory evidence of the
ownership or right to possession thereof may be impounded by the Department or
its representative without liability at the expense of the owner, until the
ownership of the animal is established.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-060__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>After the expiration of 10 days after
the date the animal is impounded, if the Department cannot with reasonable
diligence determine the lawful owner thereof, the animal may be sold by the
Department in the manner provided inchapter 569of NRS. All expenses incurred by the Department in the keeping of the animal
and in the sale thereof must be paid out of the proceeds of the sale.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-060__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 5, the net proceeds of any such sale must be held for 1 year,
subject to the claim of any person who can establish legal title to any animal
concerned. All money remaining unclaimed must be deposited in the Livestock
Inspection Account after 1 year. The Department may disallow all claims if it
deems the claims illegal or if satisfactory evidence of title is not shown.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-060__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the animal is consigned to a public
livestock market for sale at that market, the proceeds of the sale must be kept
by the Department or, if the Department deems it advisable, by the public
livestock market, for 30 days, to permit the consignor to prove his or her
legal ownership or the consignorï¿½s right to sell the animal. If the consignor
is unable to prove his or her ownership to or the consignorï¿½s right to sell the
animal, the proceeds must be disposed of in the manner provided in subsection
4.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1960,
376; A1961,
556;1991,
1796;1993,
1760;1999,
3700)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_575-080">
          <num>575.080</num>
          <heading>Definitions.</heading>
          <subsection eId="575-080__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>ï¿½Boardï¿½ means the State Board of
Agriculture.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-080__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>ï¿½Departmentï¿½ means the State Department
of Agriculture.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-080__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>ï¿½Livestockï¿½ means the animals subject
to the taxes levied pursuant toNRS 575.185.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-080__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>ï¿½Sheepï¿½ means the animals subject to
the taxes levied pursuant toNRS 562.170and567.110.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-080__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>ï¿½Taxï¿½ means any of the taxes levied
pursuant toNRS 562.170,567.110and575.185.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1985,
741; A1993,
1761;1999,
3701;2001,
1568;2003,
2162;2013,
1324)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_575-120">
          <num>575.120</num>
          <heading>Declaration of average number, kind and classification of
livestock and sheep.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The
Department shall provide a declaration of livestock and sheep on which an owner
of livestock or sheep shall declare the average number, kind and classification
of all livestock and sheep in the State owned by him or her during the year
immediately preceding the date the declaration is made.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1985,
742; A1993,
1761;1999,
2780,3701;2001,
279,1568;2015,
3613)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_575-130">
          <num>575.130</num>
          <heading>Provision of declaration to owners of livestock or sheep;
administrative penalty for failure to complete declaration.</heading>
          <subsection eId="575-130__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department shall provide the
declaration to each owner of livestock or sheep listed in its most current
report of such owners.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-130__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An owner of livestock or sheep who
fails to complete a declaration within 30 days after the date it was provided
to him or her is subject to a penalty of $5 assessed by the Department.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1985,
742; A1999,
2781;2001,
281,1568;2015,
3614)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_575-150">
          <num>575.150</num>
          <heading>Estimation of livestock and sheep owned by persons failing to
return declarations; review of completed declarations to determine accuracy;
changes; notification of changes and of right to challenge accuracy.</heading>
          <subsection eId="575-150__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon receipt of the declaration of
livestock and sheep and the report of owners of livestock and sheep, the
Department shall:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="575-150__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Make an estimate of the number, kind and
classification of all livestock and sheep owned by any person failing to return
the declaration of livestock and sheep and include that information on the
report; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="575-150__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Examine each completed declaration of
livestock and sheep and the report to determine its accuracy, and if there is
any evidence that any information is inaccurate or incomplete, may change and
correct any listing as to number, kind, classification, ownership or location
by adding thereto or deducting therefrom as necessary to make the report
complete and accurate.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-150__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department may verify the number of
livestock or sheep by any reasonable means, including actual count at any
reasonable time.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-150__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the Department changes the listings
on the report of owners of livestock and sheep for any owner and the listing
for that owner does not conform to the listings on the declaration completed by
that owner, the Department shall notify the owner of the change within 15 days
after the change is made. The notification must contain a statement explaining
the ownerï¿½s right to challenge the accuracy of the report made by the
Department.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1985,
743; A1999,
2781;2001,
1568;2015,
3614)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_575-160">
          <num>575.160</num>
          <heading>Exemption from tax if less than cost of collection.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If the Department determines that the amount
of tax to be collected from an owner of livestock or sheep is less than the
cost of collecting the tax, it may exempt that owner from the tax.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1985,
743; A2001,
1569)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_575-170">
          <num>575.170</num>
          <heading>Challenge of report as changed: Filing of statement; review;
appeal to State Board of Agriculture.</heading>
          <subsection eId="575-170__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An owner of sheep or livestock who
wishes to challenge the accuracy of the report as changed by the Department
may, within 15 days after receiving notice of the change, file a statement with
the Department for assessing livestock for the ownerï¿½s county specifying the
alleged inaccuracy.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-170__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon receipt of the statement under
subsection 1, the Department shall review the allegations and may make any
changes it considers necessary to make the report accurate and complete. An
owner of sheep or livestock or the Board may appeal from any decision of the
Department to and in the manner prescribed by the Board.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1985,
743; A1993,
1762;1999,
3702;2001,
1569;2003,
2163)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_575-180">
          <num>575.180</num>
          <heading>Approval of report; copy; notification of change resulting from
challenge of accuracy.</heading>
          <subsection eId="575-180__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When the report of owners of livestock
and sheep is approved by the Department as complete and accurate, the approval
must be noted on the report. A copy of the approved report must be sent to the
Board.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-180__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If, as the result of a challenge of the
accuracy of the report, any change is ordered in the report of owners of
livestock and sheep after it has been approved by the Department, each recipient
of a copy of the report must be notified of the change.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1985,
744; A1993,
1762;1999,
2781,3702;2001,
279,1569;2003,
2163,2164)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_575-185">
          <num>575.185</num>
          <heading>Maximum rate of tax; minimum tax; deposit in Livestock
Inspection Account.</heading>
          <subsection eId="575-185__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon approval of the report of owners
of livestock and sheep pursuant toNRS
575.180, the Department shall fix the amount of the annual special tax on
each head of the following specified classes of livestock, which, except as
otherwise provided in subsection 2, must not exceed the following rates per
head for each class:
Classï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ Rate
per head
Stock cattle........................................................................................................... $0.50
Dairy cattle............................................................................................................... 
.60
Horses....................................................................................................................... 
.75
Mules......................................................................................................................... 
.75
Burros or asses........................................................................................................ 
.75
Hogs and pigs.......................................................................................................... 
.30
Goats......................................................................................................................... 
.10
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-185__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The minimum special tax due annually
pursuant to this section from each owner of livestock is $10.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-185__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon the receipt of payment of the
special tax and the report thereof by the State Controller, the Department
shall credit the amount of the tax as paid on its records.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-185__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The special taxes paid by an owner of
livestock, when transmitted to the State Treasurer, must be deposited in the
Livestock Inspection Account.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-185__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="575-185__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Dairy cattleï¿½ are bulls, cows and heifers of
the dairy breeds that are more than 6 months old.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="575-185__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Stock cattleï¿½ are:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="575-185__subsec_5__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Steers of any breed and other weaned
calves of the beef breeds that are more than 6 months old; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="575-185__subsec_5__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Bulls, cows and older heifers of the
beef breeds.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="575-185__subsec_5__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The classes consisting of horses, mules, and
burros and asses exclude animals that are less than 1 year old.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2013,
1323; A2013,
2470)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_575-190">
          <num>575.190</num>
          <heading>Calculation of total taxes due.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Using
the tax levies from the Board and from the Department, the Department shall
calculate the total taxes due from each owner of livestock or sheep based on
the report of owners of livestock or sheep approved by the Department.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1985,
744; A1993,
1762;1999,
2782,3702;2001,
279,1569;2003,
53,2164)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_575-200">
          <num>575.200</num>
          <heading>Billing of owners; failure to receive bill not excuse from
payment.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The Department shall mail
to each owner of livestock or sheep a bill for the total taxes due from that
owner. Failure to receive a tax bill does not excuse the taxpayer from the
timely payment of his or her taxes.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1985,
744; A1999,
2782;2001,
1569)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_575-205">
          <num>575.205</num>
          <heading>Assessment of certain past due special taxes on specified
livestock; penalty and interest for failure to pay such taxes; waiver or
reduction of interest or penalty; disclosure of waiver or reduction; taxes,
penalties and interest constitute lien until paid; inspection and other
services not provided when certain special taxes delinquent.</heading>
          <subsection eId="575-205__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the Department determines that an
owner of livestock was not assessed the tax required pursuant toNRS 575.185in any year in which the tax
became due, the Department may assess the tax at any time within 5 years after
the date on which the tax became due.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-205__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 3, any person who fails to pay the tax levied by the Department
pursuant toNRS 575.185, within the time
required, shall pay, in addition to the tax, a penalty equal to 20 percent of
the amount of the tax that is owed for each year the person fails to pay the
tax, plus interest at the rate of 1.5 percent per month, or fraction of a
month, from the date the tax was due until the date of payment.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-205__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department may waive or reduce the
payment of the interest or penalty, or both, that is required to be paid
pursuant to subsection 2, if the Department finds extenuating circumstances
sufficient to justify the waiver or reduction. The Department shall, upon the
request of any person, disclose:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="575-205__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The name of the person whose interest or
penalty was waived or reduced; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="575-205__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The amount so waived or the amount of the
reduction.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-205__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>All taxes levied by the Department on
livestock pursuant toNRS 575.185, and
all penalties and interest accrued thereon, constitute a lien upon the
livestock until paid.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="575-205__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided inNRS 575.230, the Department shall not
provide inspection or other services to an owner of livestock who is delinquent
in the payment of the tax levied by the Department pursuant toNRS 575.185.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2001,
1567; A2013,
1324,2470)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_575-210">
          <num>575.210</num>
          <heading>Department to transmit revenue from taxes, penalties and
interest to State Controller.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever
any taxes, or penalties or interest for delinquencies pursuant toNRS 562.175,575.130or575.205are paid to the Department, the
Department shall record the payment and the date thereof with the name of the
person liable therefor, and the amount of taxes, penalties and interest
collected pursuant toNRS 562.170,562.175,567.110,575.130,575.185and575.205, and transmit the revenue thereof
to the State Controller for deposit into the appropriate account or fund in the
State Treasury.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1985,
744; A1991,
1797;1995,
213;2001,
1570;2003,
53,2164;2013,
1324)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_575-220">
          <num>575.220</num>
          <heading>Report of certain delinquent taxes.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The
Department shall report to the Board any taxes delinquent, if the taxes were
levied pursuant toNRS 562.170and567.110.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1985,
744; A1993,
1762;1999,
3702;2001,
1570;2003,
2164)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_575-230">
          <num>575.230</num>
          <heading>Payment of delinquent tax required for issuance of brand
inspection clearance certificate; notification of collection.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>A brand inspection clearance certificate
described inNRS 562.460or565.120must not be issued for the movement
of any sheep or livestock owned by a person delinquent in the payment of a tax.
The Department may collect any delinquent tax and the penalty and interest
thereon at the time of a brand or health inspection. The appropriate county
authority must be notified if the tax is so collected.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1985,
744; A1993,
1762;1995,
213;1999,
3702;2003,
2164)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>