<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="NRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-12"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-12"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#nevada-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-nv"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12"/>
          <FRBRname value="NRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-12/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-12/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-12/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-12/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="nevada-legislature" href="https://www.leg.state.nv.us" showAs="Nevada State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_12">
        <num>12</num>
        <heading>PARTIES</heading>
        <section eId="sec_12-010">
          <num>12.010</num>
          <heading>Assignment of thing in action not to prejudice defense.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Except as provided for secured transactions inchapters 104to104C,
inclusive, of NRS, in the case of an assignment of a thing in action, the
action by the assignee shall be without prejudice to any setoff or other
defense existing at the time of, or before notice of, the assignment; but this
section shall not apply to a negotiable promissory note, or bill of exchange,
transferred in good faith and upon good consideration before due.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 CPA ï¿½ 46; RL ï¿½ 4988; NCL ï¿½ 8545]—(NRS A1965,
913)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_12-015">
          <num>12.015</num>
          <heading>Actions involving indigent persons.</heading>
          <subsection eId="12-015__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person who desires to prosecute or
defend a civil action without paying the costs for prosecuting or defending the
action may:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12-015__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>File, on a form provided by the court, an
application to proceed as an indigent litigant, which must include a
declaration that complies with the provisions ofNRS 53.045; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12-015__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the person is a client of a program for
legal aid, submit to the court a statement of representation or otherwise
indicate to the court that the person is a client of a program for legal aid.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12-015__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court shall allow a person to
commence or defend the action without costs and file or issue any necessary
writ, process, pleading or paper without charge if:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12-015__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Based on its review of an application filed
pursuant to paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12-015__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 1, the court determines that the
application should be granted and the person may proceed as an indigent
litigant because the person:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="12-015__subsec_2__subsec_a__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Is receiving benefits provided by a
federal or state program of public assistance;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12-015__subsec_2__subsec_a__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Has a household net income which is
equal to or less than 150 percent of the federally designated level signifying
poverty as provided in the most recent federal poverty guidelines published in
the Federal Register by the United States Department of Health and Human
Services;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12-015__subsec_2__subsec_a__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Has expenses for the necessities of
life that exceed his or her income; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="12-015__subsec_2__subsec_a__subsec_4">
                <num>(4)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Has otherwise shown compelling reasons
that he or she cannot pay the costs of prosecuting or defending the action.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12-015__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The person has submitted a statement of
representation or otherwise indicated to the court that the person is a client
of a program for legal aid pursuant to paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12-015__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 1.
ï¿½The sheriff
or another appropriate public officer within this State shall make personal
service of any necessary writ, process, pleading or paper without charge for an
applicant whose application has been granted or a person who has submitted a
statement of legal representation or otherwise indicated to the court that the
person is a client of a program for legal aid.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12-015__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the person is required to have
proceedings reported or recorded, or if the court determines that the
reporting, recording or transcription of proceedings would be helpful to the
adjudication or appellate review of the case, the court shall order that the
reporting, recording or transcription be performed at the expense of the county
in which the action is pending but at a reduced rate as set by the county.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12-015__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the person prevails in the action,
the court shall enter its order requiring the losing party to pay into court
within 5 days the costs which would have been incurred by the prevailing party,
and those costs must then be paid as provided by law.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12-015__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If an applicant files an application to
proceed as an indigent litigant pursuant to paragraph</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12-015__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 1 to
defend an action, the running of the time within which to appear and answer or
otherwise defend the action is tolled during the period between the filing of
the application and the decision of the court to grant or deny the application.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12-015__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The filing of an application to proceed
as an indigent litigant pursuant to paragraph</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12-015__subsec_6__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 1 and any
application or request filed with the application and the submission of a
statement of legal representation or other indication to the court that the
person is a client of a program for legal aid pursuant to paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12-015__subsec_6__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of
subsection 1 do not constitute a general appearance before the court by the
applicant or person or give the court personal jurisdiction over the applicant
or person.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12-015__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The decision of a court granting or
denying an application to proceed as an indigent litigant filed pursuant to
paragraph</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12-015__subsec_7__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 1 is not appealable.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12-015__subsec_8">
            <num>8.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, ï¿½client of a
program for legal aidï¿½ means a person:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12-015__subsec_8__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Who is represented by an attorney who is
employed by or volunteering for a program for legal aid organized under the
auspices of the State Bar of Nevada, a county or local bar association, a
county or municipal program for legal services or other program funded by this
State or the United States to provide legal assistance to indigent persons; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12-015__subsec_8__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Whose eligibility for such representation is
based upon indigency.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1209; A1989,
201;1991,
455;2005,
197;2021,
489)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_12-020">
          <num>12.020</num>
          <heading>Actions by married couple.</heading>
          <subsection eId="12-020__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When the action is for personal
injuries, the spouse having sustained personal injuries is a necessary party;
and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12-020__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When the action is for compensation for
services rendered, the spouse having rendered the services is a necessary
party.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 CPA ï¿½ 47; A1937,
29; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 8546]—(NRS A1975,
557;2017,
774)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_12-030">
          <num>12.030</num>
          <heading>Defense of actions against married couple.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If a married couple is sued together, either
or both may defend, and if either neglects to defend, the other may defend for
both.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 CPA ï¿½ 48; RL ï¿½ 4990; NCL ï¿½ 8547]—(NRS A1975,
558;2017,
775)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_12-040">
          <num>12.040</num>
          <heading>Deserted spouse as a party.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>When
a spouse has deserted his or her family, the other spouse may prosecute or
defend in his or her name any action which he or she might have prosecuted or
defended, and shall have the same powers and rights therein as he or she might
have.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 CPA ï¿½ 49; RL ï¿½ 4991; NCL ï¿½ 8548]—(NRS A2017,
775)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_12-050">
          <num>12.050</num>
          <heading>Appointment of guardian ad litem.</heading>
          <subsection eId="12-050__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When the infant is plaintiff, upon the
application of the infant if the infant be of the age of 14 years, or, if under
that age, upon the application of a relative or friend of the infant.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12-050__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When the infant is defendant, upon the
application of the infant if the infant be of the age of 14 years and apply
within 10 days after the service of the summons, or, if under that age or if
the infant neglect to so apply, then upon the application of a relative or
friend of the infant, or any other party to the action.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12-050__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When an insane or incompetent person is
a party to an action or proceeding, upon the application of a relative or
friend of such insane or incompetent person, or of any other party to the
action or proceeding.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 CPA ï¿½ 51; RL ï¿½ 4993; NCL ï¿½ 8550]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_12-070">
          <num>12.070</num>
          <heading>Parent or guardian may maintain action for seduction.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Either of the parents or the guardian of a
male or female minor child under the age of 16 years may, on behalf of that
child, bring an action for the seduction of that child, against a person 3 or
more years older than the child. The parent or guardian, as plaintiff, need not
show that the child was living with the parent or guardian or was in the
service of the parent or guardian at the time of the seduction or later, or
that the parent or guardian suffered a loss of service.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 CPA ï¿½ 53; A1913,
27; NCL ï¿½ 8552]—(NRS A1979,
1171)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_12-080">
          <num>12.080</num>
          <heading>Parent or guardian may maintain action for injury of minor
child.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The parents jointly, or
either parent, without preference to either, may maintain an action for the
injury of a minor child who has not been emancipated, if the injury is caused
by the wrongful act or neglect of another. A guardian may maintain an action
for the injury of his or her unemancipated ward, if the injury is caused by the
wrongful act or neglect of another, the action by the guardian to be prosecuted
for the benefit of the ward. Any such action may be maintained against the
person causing the injury, or, if the person is employed by another person who
is responsible for his or her conduct, also against that other person.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 CPA ï¿½ 54; A1913,
27; NCL ï¿½ 8553]—(NRS A1960,
321;1969,
891;1971,
151;1987,
1281;2017,
775)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_12-100">
          <num>12.100</num>
          <heading>Action not to abate by death of any party after verdict.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>After verdict shall have been rendered in any
action for a wrong, such action shall not abate by the death of any party, but
the case shall proceed thereafter in the same manner as in cases where the
cause of action now survives by law.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 1911 CPA ï¿½ 62; RL ï¿½ 5004; NCL ï¿½ 8561]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_12-105">
          <num>12.105</num>
          <heading>State and local governmental agencies may be sued without naming
members of their governing bodies; service.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Any
political subdivision, public corporation, special district, or other agency of
state or local government which is capable of being sued in its own name may be
sued by naming it as the party without naming the individual members of its
governing body in their representative capacity. In addition to any other
method which may be provided by statute or rule of court, service may be made
upon the clerk or secretary of the political subdivision, corporation or
agency.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1979,
394)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_12-107">
          <num>12.107</num>
          <heading>Limitation on commencement of lawsuit against manufacturer or
distributor of firearm or ammunition or trade association related to firearms
or ammunition; exception for breach of contract or warranty.</heading>
          <subsection eId="12-107__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 2, the State of Nevada is the only governmental entity in this state
that may commence a lawsuit against a manufacturer or distributor of a firearm
or ammunition or a trade association related to firearms or ammunition for
damages, abatement or injunctive relief resulting from or relating to the
lawful design or manufacture of a firearm or ammunition or the marketing or
sale of a firearm or ammunition to the public.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12-107__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of this section do not
prohibit a county, city, local government or other political subdivision of
this state or an agency thereof from commencing a lawsuit against a
manufacturer or distributor of a firearm or ammunition for breach of contract
or warranty concerning a firearm or ammunition purchased by the county, city,
local government or other political subdivision of this state or agency
thereof.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1999,
1411)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_12-110">
          <num>12.110</num>
          <heading>Associates may be sued by name of association; summons; judgment
to bind joint property.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>When two
or more persons, associated in any business, transact such business under a
common name, whether it comprise the names of such persons or not, the
associates may be sued by such common name, the summons in such cases being
served on one or more of the associates; and the judgment in the action shall
bind the joint property of all the associates, in the same manner as if all had
been made defendants and had been sued upon their joint liability.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 CPA ï¿½ 65; RL ï¿½ 5007; NCL ï¿½ 8564]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_12-120">
          <num>12.120</num>
          <heading>Unknown heirs to real property may be made parties; allegations
and proof that names and residences of heirs are unknown.</heading>
          <subsection eId="12-120__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In any action in which the title to
real property situate in this state is involved in which the heir or heirs, or
any thereof, of a deceased person may be necessary or proper party or parties
defendant and the name or names and place or places of residence of which heir
or heirs are unknown to the plaintiff or plaintiffs, such heir or heirs may be
made a party or parties defendant by being described in the complaint and
summons as the unknown heir or heirs of such deceased person, giving the name
and last place of residence of such deceased person, with any further
description that may be necessary to reasonably identify the deceased person.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12-120__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In any such action the plaintiff or
plaintiffs shall allege in the complaint, and prove at the trial, that diligent
search and inquiry have been made by or in behalf of the plaintiff or
plaintiffs to ascertain the name or names, and place or places of residence of
such heir or heirs, without success, and that the same are and remain unknown
to the plaintiff or plaintiffs.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 CPA ï¿½ 67; RL ï¿½ 5009; NCL ï¿½ 8566] + [1911 CPA ï¿½
68; RL ï¿½ 5010; NCL ï¿½ 8567]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_12-130">
          <num>12.130</num>
          <heading>Intervention: Right to intervention; procedure, determination
and costs; exception.</heading>
          <subsection eId="12-130__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 2:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="12-130__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Before the trial, any person may intervene in
an action or proceeding, who has an interest in the matter in litigation, in
the success of either of the parties, or an interest against both.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12-130__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An intervention takes place when a third
person is permitted to become a party to an action or proceeding between other
persons, either by joining the plaintiff in claiming what is sought by the
complaint, or by uniting with the defendant in resisting the claims of the
plaintiff, or by demanding anything adversely to both the plaintiff and the
defendant.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12-130__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Intervention is made as provided by the
Nevada Rules of Civil Procedure.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="12-130__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The court shall determine upon the
intervention at the same time that the action is decided. If the claim of the
party intervening is not sustained, the party intervening shall pay all costs
incurred by the intervention.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="12-130__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of this section do not
apply to intervention in an action or proceeding by the Legislature pursuant toNRS 218F.720.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 1911 CPA ï¿½ 64; RL ï¿½ 5006; NCL ï¿½ 8563]—(NRS A2009,
1566)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>