<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="NRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-122"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-122"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#nevada-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-nv"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="122"/>
          <FRBRname value="NRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-122/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-122/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-122/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-122/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="nevada-legislature" href="https://www.leg.state.nv.us" showAs="Nevada State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_122">
        <num>122</num>
        <heading>MARRIAGE</heading>
        <section eId="sec_122-001">
          <num>122.001</num>
          <heading>Definitions.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>As
used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires, the words and
terms defined inNRS 122.0015to122.006, inclusive, have the meanings
ascribed to them in those sections.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2009,
722; A2011,
2044;2013,
341;2017,
1024)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-0015">
          <num>122.0015</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Commercial wedding chapelï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Commercial
wedding chapelï¿½ means a permanently affixed structure which operates a business
principally for the performance of weddings and which is licensed for that
purpose.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2011,
2043; A2013,
341)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-002">
          <num>122.002</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Commissioner townshipï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Commissioner
townshipï¿½ means a township whose population is 15,500 or more, as most recently
certified by the Governor pursuant toNRS
360.285, and which is located in a county whose population is 100,000 or
more.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
765; A1971,
1552;1995,
247;1997,
178;2009,
723)—(Substituted in revision for NRS 122.171)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-004">
          <num>122.004</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Marriage officiantï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Marriage
officiantï¿½ means a person, other than a minister, other church or religious
official authorized to solemnize a marriage or notary public, who obtains a
certificate of permission to perform marriages as provided inNRS 122.062to122.073, inclusive.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2017,
1024)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-006">
          <num>122.006</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Other church or religious official authorized to solemnize a
marriageï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Other church
or religious official authorized to solemnize a marriageï¿½ means a person of any
church or religious organization, other than a minister, who has been
authorized to solemnize a marriage according to the usages of that church or
religious organization.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2009,
722; A2013,
1186)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-010">
          <num>122.010</num>
          <heading>What constitutes marriage; no common-law marriages after March
29, 1943.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-010__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Marriage, so far as its validity in law
is concerned, is a civil contract, to which the consent of the parties capable
in law of contracting is essential. Consent alone will not constitute marriage;
it must be followed by solemnization as authorized and provided by this
chapter.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-010__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of subsection 1
requiring solemnization shall not invalidate any marriage contract in effect
prior to March 29, 1943, to which the consent only of the parties capable in
law of contracting the contract was essential.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1:33:1861; A1943,
279; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 4050]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-020">
          <num>122.020</num>
          <heading>Persons capable of marriage.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-020__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 2 andNRS 122.025, two
persons, regardless of gender, who are at least 18 years of age, not nearer of
kin than second cousins or cousins of the half blood, and not having a spouse
living, may be joined in marriage.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-020__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Two persons, regardless of gender, who
are married to each other may be rejoined in marriage if the record of their
marriage has been lost or destroyed or is otherwise unobtainable.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 2:33:1861; A1867,
88;1891,
15;1947,
445; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 4051]—(NRS A1961,
357;1973,
1578;1975,
1817;1977,
279;1981,
678;2009,
1503;2017,
755;2019,
3660)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-025">
          <num>122.025</num>
          <heading>Marriage of minor who is 17 years of age: Consent of parent or
guardian; authorization by court.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-025__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A minor who is 17 years of age may
marry only if the minor has the consent of:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-025__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Either parent; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-025__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The minorï¿½s legal guardian,
ï¿½and the
minor also obtains authorization from a district court as provided in this
section.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-025__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In extraordinary circumstances, a
district court may authorize the marriage of a minor who is 17 years of age if
the court finds, by clear and convincing evidence, after an evidentiary hearing
in which both parties to the prospective marriage provide sworn testimony,
that:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-025__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Both parties to the prospective marriage are
residents of this State;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-025__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The marriage will serve the best interests of
the minor; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-025__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The minor has the consent required by
paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-025__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-025__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 1.
ï¿½Pregnancy
alone does not establish that the best interests of the minor will be served by
marriage, nor may pregnancy be required by a court as a condition necessary for
its authorization for the marriage of the minor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-025__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In determining the best interests of
the minor for the purposes of subsection 2, the court shall consider, without
limitation:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-025__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The difference in age between the parties to
the prospective marriage;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-025__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The need for the marriage to occur before the
minor reaches 18 years of age; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-025__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The emotional and intellectual maturity of
the minor.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1957,
316; A1975,
1817;1977,
279;2019,
3660)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-030">
          <num>122.030</num>
          <heading>Documents constituting presumptive evidence of marriage.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-030__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>With respect to any marriage solemnized
before January 1, 1971, the original certificate and records of marriage made
by the judge, justice or minister, as prescribed in this chapter, and the
record thereof by the recorder of the county, or a copy or abstract of the
record certified by the recorder, must be received in all courts and places as
presumptive evidence of the fact of the marriage.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-030__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>With respect to any marriage solemnized
on or after January 1, 1971, the original certificate and records of marriage
made by the judge, justice, minister or other church or religious official
authorized to solemnize a marriage, notary public, commissioner of civil
marriages, deputy commissioner of civil marriages, marriage officiant or mayor
of an incorporated city, as prescribed in this chapter, and the record thereof
by the county recorder or the county clerk, as the case may be, or a copy or
abstract of the record certified by the county recorder or the county clerk, as
the case may be, must be received in all courts and places as presumptive
evidence of the fact of the marriage.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [14:33:1861; B ï¿½ 207; BH ï¿½ 483; C ï¿½ 494; RL ï¿½ 2350;
NCL ï¿½ 4062]—(NRS A1969,
763;1991,
69;2007,
887;2009,
723;2013,
1186;2017,
1024,1196)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-040">
          <num>122.040</num>
          <heading>Marriage license: Requirements; issuance by county clerk; waiver
of certain requirements; public records; expiration.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-040__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Before persons may be joined in
marriage, a license must be obtained for that purpose from the county clerk of
any county in the State. Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the
license must be issued at the county seat of that county. The board of county
commissioners:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-040__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In a county whose population is 700,000 or
more may, at the request of the county clerk, designate not more than five
branch offices of the county clerk at which marriage licenses may be issued, if
the designated branch offices are located outside of the county seat.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-040__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In a county whose population is less than
700,000 may, at the request of the county clerk, designate one branch office of
the county clerk at which marriage licenses may be issued, if the designated
branch office is established in a county office building which is located
outside of the county seat.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-040__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in this
section, before issuing a marriage license, the county clerk shall require each
applicant to provide proof of the applicantï¿½s name and age. The county clerk
may accept as proof of the applicantï¿½s name and age an original or certified
copy of any of the following:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-040__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A driverï¿½s license, instruction permit or
identification card issued by this State or another state, the District of
Columbia or any territory of the United States.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-040__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A passport.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-040__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A birth certificate and:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="122-040__subsec_2__subsec_c__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Any secondary document that contains
the name and a photograph of the applicant; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="122-040__subsec_2__subsec_c__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Any document for which identification
must be verified as a condition to receipt of the document.
ï¿½If the birth
certificate is written in a language other than English, the county clerk may
request that the birth certificate be translated into English and notarized.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-040__subsec_2__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A military identification card or military
dependent identification card issued by any branch of the Armed Forces of the
United States.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-040__subsec_2__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A Certificate of Citizenship, Certificate of
Naturalization, Permanent Resident Card or Temporary Resident Card issued by
the United States Citizenship and Immigration Services of the Department of
Homeland Security.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-040__subsec_2__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any other document that provides the
applicantï¿½s name and age. If the applicant clearly appears over the age of 25
years, no documentation of proof of age is required.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-040__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 4, the county clerk issuing the license shall require each applicant
to answer under oath each of the questions contained in the form of license.
The county clerk shall, except as otherwise provided in this subsection,
require each applicant to include the applicantï¿½s social security number on the
affidavit of application for the marriage license. If a person does not have a
social security number, the person must state that fact. The county clerk shall
not require any evidence to verify a social security number. If any of the
information required is unknown to the person, the person must state that the
answer is unknown. The county clerk shall not deny a license to an applicant
who states that the applicant does not have a social security number or who
states that any requested information concerning the applicantï¿½s parents is
unknown.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-040__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon finding that extraordinary
circumstances exist which result in only one applicant being able to appear
before the county clerk, the county clerk may waive the requirements of
subsection 3 with respect to the person who is unable to appear before the
county clerk, or may refer the applicant to the district court. If the
applicant is referred to the district court, the district court may waive the
requirements of subsection 3 with respect to the person who is unable to appear
before the county clerk. If the district court waives the requirements of
subsection 3, the district court shall notify the county clerk in writing. If
the county clerk or the district court waives the requirements of subsection 3,
the county clerk shall require the applicant who is able to appear before the county
clerk to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-040__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Answer under oath each of the questions
contained in the form of license. The applicant shall answer any questions with
reference to the other person named in the license.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-040__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Include the applicantï¿½s social security
number and the social security number of the other person named in the license
on the affidavit of application for the marriage license. If either person does
not have a social security number, the person responding to the question must
state that fact. The county clerk shall not require any evidence to verify a
social security number.
ï¿½If any of
the information required on the application is unknown to the person responding
to the question, the person must state that the answer is unknown. The county
clerk shall not deny a license to an applicant who states that the applicant
does not have a social security number or who states that any requested
information concerning the parents of either the person who is responding to
the question or the person who is unable to appear is unknown.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-040__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When the authorization of a district
court is required because the marriage involves a minor, the county clerk shall
issue the license if that authorization is given to the county clerk in
writing.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-040__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>All records pertaining to marriage
licenses are public records and open to inspection pursuant to the provisions
ofNRS 239.010.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-040__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A marriage license issued on or after
July 1, 1987, expires 1 year after its date of issuance.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 5:33:1861; A1867,
88;1899,
47;1919,
382;1927,
49;1947,
41;1949,
91; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 4053]—(NRS A1959,
484;1961,
332;1975,
144,435;1977,
280;1979,
486;1981,
678;1985,
1211;1987,
1419;1991,
1866;1993,
28,1230;1997,
2287,3323;1999,
547;2007,
1053;2009,
1503;2011,
1146,2044;2013,
341,3665;2017,
1518;2019,
3661;2021,
571;2023,
1307)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-045">
          <num>122.045</num>
          <heading>Preparation of affidavit of correction to correct information in
marriage license; fees.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-045__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 2, if any information in a marriage license is incorrect, the county
clerk may charge and collect from a person a fee of not more than $25 for the
preparation of an affidavit of correction.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-045__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The county clerk may not charge and
collect from a person any fee for the preparation of an affidavit of correction
pursuant to subsection 1 if the only errors to be corrected in the marriage
license are clerical errors that were made by the county clerk.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-045__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>All fees collected by the county clerk
pursuant to this section must be deposited in the county general fund.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1999,
1322)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-050">
          <num>122.050</num>
          <heading>Form of marriage license.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The
marriage license must contain the name of each applicant as shown in the
documents presented pursuant to subsection 2 ofNRS 122.040. The marriage license must be
substantially in the following form:
Marriage License
(Expires 1 Year After Issuance)
State of Nevadaï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ }
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ }ss.
County of................................................ }
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ These presents are to
authorize any minister, other church or religious official authorized to
solemnize a marriage, notary public or marriage officiant who has obtained a
certificate of permission to perform marriages, any Supreme Court justice,
judge of the Court of Appeals or district judge within this State, or justice
of the peace within a township wherein the justice of the peace is permitted to
solemnize marriages or if authorized pursuant to subsection 3 ofNRS 122.080, or a municipal judge if
authorized pursuant to subsection 4 ofNRS
122.080, or any commissioner of civil marriages or his or her deputy within
a commissioner township wherein they are permitted to solemnize marriages or
any mayor if authorized pursuant to subsection 5 ofNRS 122.080, to join in marriage ........
of (City, town or location) ........, State of ........ State of birth (If not
in U.S.A., name of country) ........; Date of birth ........ Name of Parent No.
1 ........ State of birth of Parent No. 1 (If not in U.S.A., name of country)
........ Name of Parent No. 2 ........ State of birth of Parent No. 2 (If not
in U.S.A., name of country) ........ Number of this marriage (1st, 2nd, etc.)
..... Former Spouse: Deceased ........ Divorced ........ Annulled ........ When
........ Where ........ And ........ of (City, town or location) ........,
State of ........ State of birth (If not in U.S.A., name of country) ........;
Date of birth ........ Name of Parent No. 1 ........ State of birth of Parent
No. 1 (If not in U.S.A., name of country) ........ Name of Parent No. 2
........ State of birth of Parent No. 2 (If not in U.S.A., name of country)
........ Number of this marriage (1st, 2nd, etc.) ........ Former Spouse:
Deceased ........ Divorced ........ Annulled ........ When ........ Where
........; and to certify the marriage according to law.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ Witness my hand and the seal
of the county, this ..... day of the month of ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½. of the year ............
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½
(Seal)ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ Clerk
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ Deputy
clerk</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 5:33:1861; A1867,
88;1899,
47;1919,
382;1927,
49;1947,
41;1949,
91; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 4053]—(NRS A1967,
1291;1969,
763;1975,
436;1981,
679;1985,
243;1987,
1420;1993,
1461;2001,
31;2007,
1055;2009,
723;2013,
1186,1746;2017,
756,1025,1197,1521;2023,
1309)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-055">
          <num>122.055</num>
          <heading>Consolidation of forms for marriage; requirements and
limitations on information on reverse of form.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-055__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The county clerk may place the
affidavit of application for a marriage license, the certificate of marriage
and the marriage license on a single form.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-055__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The county clerk shall have printed or
stamped on the reverse of the form:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-055__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Instructions for obtaining a certified copy
or certified abstract of the certificate of marriage.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-055__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Language in black ink and at least 16-point
bold type in a font that is easy to read and that is in substantially the following
form:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ This is a duplicate of your
certificate. This is not a certified copy. After the certificate has been
recorded by the county recorder or filed by the county clerk, you may obtain a
certified copy. For name changes and other legal matters, you will need to
obtain a certified copy.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-055__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Nothing may be printed, stamped or
written on the reverse of the form other than the instructions and language
described in subsection 2 and a time stamp used by the county clerk to signify
that the form has been filed.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1987,
1419; A1991,
69;2007,
887;2011,
1854;2017,
1025)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-060">
          <num>122.060</num>
          <heading>Fees.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-060__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The county clerk is entitled to receive
as his or her fee for issuing a marriage license the sum of $21.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-060__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The county clerk shall also at the time
of issuing the marriage license:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-060__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Collect the sum of $10 and:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="122-060__subsec_2__subsec_a__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If the board of county commissioners
has adopted an ordinance pursuant toNRS
246.100, deposit the sum into the county general fund pursuant toNRS 246.180for filing the originally signed
certificate of marriage described inNRS
122.120.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="122-060__subsec_2__subsec_a__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If the board of county commissioners
has not adopted an ordinance pursuant toNRS
246.100, pay it over to the county recorder as his or her fee for recording
the originally signed certificate of marriage described inNRS 122.120.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-060__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Collect the additional fee described in
subsection 2 ofNRS 246.180, if the board
of county commissioners has adopted an ordinance authorizing the collection of
such fee, and deposit the fee pursuant toNRS
246.190.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-060__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Collect the additional fee imposed pursuant
toNRS 246.075, if the board of county
commissioners has adopted an ordinance imposing the fee.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-060__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The county clerk shall also at the time
of issuing the marriage license collect the additional sum of $4 for the State
of Nevada. The fees collected for the State must be paid over to the county
treasurer by the county clerk on or before the fifth day of each month for the
preceding calendar month, and must be placed to the credit of the State General
Fund. The county treasurer shall remit quarterly all such fees deposited by the
county clerk to the State Controller for credit to the State General Fund.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-060__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The county clerk shall also at the time
of issuing the marriage license collect the additional sum of $50 for the
Account for Aid for Victims of Domestic or Sexual Violence in the State General
Fund. The fees collected for this purpose must be paid over to the county
treasurer by the county clerk on or before the fifth day of each month for the
preceding calendar month, and must be placed to the credit of that Account. The
county treasurer shall, on or before the 15th day of each month, remit those
fees deposited by the county clerk to the State Controller for credit to that
Account.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-060__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any fee charged and collected pursuant
to this section is separate and distinct from any administrative fee charged
and collected by a county clerkï¿½s office, including, without limitation, a fee
for certifying a copy of a marriage license.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 5:33:1861; A1867,
88;1899,
47;1919,
382;1927,
49;1947,
41;1949,
91; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 4053]—(NRS A1957,
347;1959,
740;1960,
72;1967,
1110;1975,
437;1979,
636;1981,
382;1983,
912;1987,
26,1421;1991,
1678,1679;2001,
2918,3216;2003,
227;2007,
887;2009,
263;2013,
3667;2015,
2629;2021,
3257)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-061">
          <num>122.061</num>
          <heading>Office hours for issuance of marriage licenses.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-061__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In any county whose population is
100,000 or more, except as otherwise provided in subsection 3, the main office
of the county clerk where marriage licenses may be issued must be open to the
public for the purpose of issuing such licenses from 8 a.m. to 12 a.m. every
day including holidays, and may remain open at other times. The board of county
commissioners shall determine the hours during which a branch office of the
county clerk where marriage licenses may be issued must remain open to the
public.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-061__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In all other counties, the board of
county commissioners shall determine the hours during which the offices where
marriage licenses may be issued must remain open to the public.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-061__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any office where marriage licenses may
be issued may deviate from the hours of operation required pursuant to this
section if the board of county commissioners approves the plan for the
deviation submitted by the office. Such a plan must be fiscally neutral or
result in cost savings.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1979,
487; A1979,
1333;1993,
29;2009,
1506;2010,
26th Special Session, 50;2011,
2046)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-062">
          <num>122.062</num>
          <heading>Licensed, ordained or appointed ministers, other church or
religious officials authorized to solemnize a marriage, notaries public,
marriage officiants and chaplains of Armed Forces to obtain certificates from
county clerk; temporary replacements; solemnization by minister or other
authorized person who resides in another state or who is retired.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-062__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any licensed, ordained or appointed
minister or other church or religious official authorized to solemnize a
marriage in good standing within his or her church or religious organization,
or either of them, incorporated, organized or established in this State, a
notary public appointed by the Secretary of State pursuant tochapter 240of NRS and in good standing with the
Secretary of State, or a marriage officiant may join together in marriage persons
who present a marriage license obtained from any county clerk of the State, if
the minister, other church or religious official authorized to solemnize a
marriage, notary public or marriage officiant first obtains or renews a
certificate of permission to perform marriages as provided inNRS 122.062to122.073, inclusive. The fact that a
minister or other church or religious official authorized to solemnize a
marriage is retired does not disqualify him or her from obtaining a certificate
of permission to perform marriages if, before retirement, the minister or other
church or religious official authorized to solemnize a marriage had active
charge of a church or religious organization for a period of at least 3 years.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-062__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A temporary replacement for a licensed,
ordained or appointed minister or other church or religious official authorized
to solemnize a marriage certified pursuant toNRS
122.062to122.073, inclusive, may
solemnize marriages pursuant to subsection 1 for a period not to exceed 90 days,
if the requirements of this subsection are satisfied. The minister or other
church or religious official authorized to solemnize a marriage whom he or she
temporarily replaces shall provide him or her with a written authorization
which states the period during which it is effective, and the temporary
replacement shall obtain from the county clerk in the county in which he or she
is a temporary replacement a written authorization to solemnize marriage and
submit to the county clerk an application fee of $25.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-062__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any chaplain who is assigned to duty in
this State by the Armed Forces of the United States may solemnize marriages if
the chaplain obtains a certificate of permission to perform marriages from the
county clerk of the county in which his or her duty station is located. The
county clerk shall issue such a certificate to a chaplain upon proof of his or
her military status as a chaplain and of his or her assignment.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-062__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A licensed, ordained or appointed
minister, other church or religious official authorized to solemnize a
marriage, active or retired, a notary public or person who desires to be a
marriage officiant may submit to the county clerk in the county in which a
marriage is to be performed an application to perform a specific marriage in
the county. The application must:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-062__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Include the full names and addresses of the
persons to be married;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-062__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Include the date and location of the marriage
ceremony;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-062__subsec_4__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Include the information and documents
required pursuant to subsection 1 ofNRS
122.064;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-062__subsec_4__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the county clerk has established a
training course for an applicant seeking to obtain a certificate of permission
to perform marriages or a single marriage in this State, include verification
that the applicant has satisfied the requirements of paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-062__subsec_4__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of
subsection 1 ofNRS 122.064; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-062__subsec_4__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Be accompanied by an application fee of $25.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-062__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A county clerk may grant authorization
to perform a specific marriage to a person who submitted an application
pursuant to subsection 4 if the county clerk is satisfied that the minister or
other church or religious official authorized to solemnize a marriage, whether
he or she is active or retired, is in good standing with his or her church or
religious organization or, in the case of a notary public, if the notary public
is in good standing with the Secretary of State, and, if the county clerk has
established a training course for an applicant seeking to obtain a certificate
of permission to perform marriages or a single marriage in this State, that the
applicant satisfied the requirements of paragraph</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-062__subsec_5__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 1 ofNRS 122.064. The authorization must be in
writing and need not be filed with any other public officer. A separate
authorization is required for each marriage performed. A person may not obtain
more than five authorizations to perform a specific marriage pursuant to this
section in any calendar year and must acknowledge that he or she is subject to
the jurisdiction of the county clerk with respect to the provisions of this
chapter governing the conduct of ministers, other church or religious officials
authorized to solemnize a marriage, notaries public or marriage officiants to
the same extent as if he or she had obtained a certificate of permission to
perform marriages.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1289; A1969,
37;1993,
1462;1997,
2040;1999,
520,541;2009,
724;2013,
1187;2017,
757,1026;2019,
452)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-064">
          <num>122.064</num>
          <heading>Initial application for or renewal of certificate: Form;
required information; fees. [Effective until the date of the repeal of 42
U.S.C. ï¿½ 666, the federal law requiring each state to establish procedures for
withholding, suspending and restricting the professional, occupational and
recreational licenses for child support arrearages and for noncompliance with
certain processes relating to paternity or child support proceedings.]</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-064__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A certificate of permission to perform
marriages or a renewal of such a certificate may be obtained only from the
county clerk of the county in which the minister, other church or religious
official authorized to solemnize a marriage, notary public or person who
desires to be a marriage officiant resides, after the filing of a proper
application. The initial application or application for renewal must:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-064__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Be in writing and be verified by the
applicant.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-064__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the applicant is a minister or other
church or religious official authorized to solemnize a marriage:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="122-064__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Include the date of licensure,
ordination or appointment of the minister or other church or religious official
authorized to solemnize a marriage, and the name of the church or religious
organization with which he or she is affiliated; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="122-064__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Be accompanied by one copy of the
affidavit of authority to solemnize marriages described in subsection 5.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-064__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the applicant is a notary public:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="122-064__subsec_1__subsec_c__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Include the date of the appointment of
the notary public by the Secretary of State; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="122-064__subsec_1__subsec_c__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Be accompanied by a verification
issued by the Secretary of State within the 3 months immediately preceding the
date of the application which states that the applicant has been appointed as a
notary public by the Secretary of State pursuant tochapter
240of NRS and is in good standing with the Secretary of State. The county
clerk must refuse to issue a certificate of permission if the appointment of
the notary public is suspended or revoked and may refuse to issue a certificate
of permission if the notary public has committed any violations ofchapter 240of NRS.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-064__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the county clerk has established a
training course for an applicant seeking to obtain a certificate of permission
to perform marriages or a single marriage in this State:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="122-064__subsec_1__subsec_d__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Include an additional fee not to
exceed $100 for the course; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="122-064__subsec_1__subsec_d__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Be accompanied by verification that
the applicant successfully completed the course.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-064__subsec_1__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Include the social security number of the
applicant.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-064__subsec_1__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Be accompanied by an application fee of $25.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-064__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>To determine the qualifications of any
minister, other church or religious official authorized to solemnize a
marriage, notary public or person who desires to be a marriage officiant who
has filed an application for a certificate of permission, the county clerk with
whom the application has been filed may require:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-064__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The church or religious organization of the
minister or other church or religious official authorized to solemnize a
marriage to furnish any evidence which the county clerk considers necessary or
helpful.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-064__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An investigation of the background and
present activities of the minister, other church or religious official
authorized to solemnize a marriage, notary public or person who desires to be a
marriage officiant. The cost of an investigation conducted pursuant to this
paragraph must be charged to the applicant.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-064__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In addition to the requirement of good
standing, the county clerk shall, before approving an initial application,
satisfy himself or herself that:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-064__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the applicant is a minister or other
church or religious official authorized to solemnize a marriage, the
applicantï¿½s ministry is one of service to his or her church or religious
organization or, in the case of a retired minister or other church or religious
official authorized to solemnize a marriage, that his or her active ministry
was of such a nature.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-064__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>No certificate previously issued to the
applicant has been cancelled for a knowing violation of the laws of this State
or of the United States.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-064__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The applicant has not been convicted of a
felony, released from confinement or completed his or her parole or probation,
whichever occurs later, within 10 years before the date of the application.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-064__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The county clerk may require any
applicant to submit information in addition to that required by this section.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-064__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The affidavit of authority to solemnize
marriages required by subparagraph (2) of paragraph</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-064__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 1 must be
in substantially the following form:
AFFIDAVIT
OF AUTHORITY TO SOLEMNIZE MARRIAGES FOR CHURCHES AND RELIGIOUS ORGANIZATIONS
State of Nevadaï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ }
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ }ss.
County of ............... }
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ The..................................................
(name of church or religious organization) is organized and carries on its work
in the State of Nevada. Its active meetings are located
at.................................................. (street address, city or town).
The.................................................. (name of church or
religious organization) hereby finds
that.................................................. (name of minister or
other person authorized to solemnize marriages) is in good standing and is
authorized by the.................................................. (name of
church or religious organization) to solemnize a marriage.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ I am duly authorized
by.................................................. (name of church or
religious organization) to complete and submit this affidavit.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½
Signature of Official
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½
Name of Official
(type or print name)
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½
Title of Official
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½
Address
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½
City, State and Zip Code
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½
Telephone Number
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ Signed and sworn to (or
affirmed) before me this.......... day of the month of.................... of
the year...........
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½
Notary Public for
..............................
County, Nevada.
My appointment
expires..............................
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-064__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Not later than 30 days after issuing or
renewing a certificate of permission to perform marriages to a notary public,
the county clerk must submit to the Secretary of State the name of the notary
public to whom the certificate has been issued.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-064__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a licensed, ordained or appointed
minister, other church or religious official authorized to solemnize a marriage
or marriage officiant who holds a certificate of permission to perform
marriages changes his or her mailing address, the minister, other church or
religious official authorized to solemnize a marriage or marriage officiant
must notify the county clerk who issued the certificate of his or her new
mailing address not later than 30 days after the change. Pursuant toNRS 122.068, a county clerk may revoke the
certificate of permission to perform marriages of a licensed, ordained or
appointed minister, other church or religious official authorized to solemnize
a marriage or marriage officiant who fails to notify the county clerk of his or
her new mailing address within 30 days after the change. If a notary public who
holds a certificate of permission to perform marriages changes his or her
mailing address, the notary public must submit to the Secretary of State a
request for an amended certificate of appointment pursuant toNRS 240.036.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-064__subsec_8">
            <num>8.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The fees collected by the county clerk
pursuant to paragraph</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-064__subsec_8__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 1 must be deposited in the account
established pursuant toNRS 19.016.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1290; A1969,
91;1977,
457;1997,
2041;2009,
725;2013,
1188;2017,
1027;2019,
454)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-065">
          <num>122.065</num>
          <heading>Payment of child support: Statement by applicant for
certificate; grounds for denial of certificate; duty of county clerk.
[Effective until the date of the repeal of 42 U.S.C. ï¿½ 666, the federal law
requiring each state to establish procedures for withholding, suspending and
restricting the professional, occupational and recreational licenses for child
support arrearages and for noncompliance with certain processes relating to
paternity or child support proceedings.]</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-065__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An applicant for the issuance of a
certificate of permission shall submit to the county clerk the statement
prescribed by the Division of Welfare and Supportive Services of the Department
of Health and Human Services pursuant toNRS
425.520. The statement must be completed and signed by the applicant.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-065__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The county clerk shall include the
statement required pursuant to subsection 1 in:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-065__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The application or any other forms that must
be submitted for the issuance of the certificate of permission; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-065__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A separate form prescribed by the county
clerk.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-065__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A certificate of permission may not be
issued by the county clerk if the applicant:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-065__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Fails to submit the statement required
pursuant to subsection 1; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-065__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Indicates on the statement submitted pursuant
to subsection 1 that the applicant is subject to a court order for the support
of a child and is not in compliance with the order or a plan approved by the
district attorney or other public agency enforcing the order for the repayment
of the amount owed pursuant to the order.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-065__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If an applicant indicates on the
statement submitted pursuant to subsection 1 that the applicant is subject to a
court order for the support of a child and is not in compliance with the order
or a plan approved by the district attorney or other public agency enforcing
the order for the repayment of the amount owed pursuant to the order, the
county clerk shall advise the applicant to contact the district attorney or
other public agency enforcing the order to determine the actions that the
applicant may take to satisfy the arrearage.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1997,
2039)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-066">
          <num>122.066</num>
          <heading>Database of ministers, other church or religious officials
authorized to solemnize a marriage, notaries public or marriage officiants who
have been issued certificate of permission to perform marriages; maintenance of
database by Secretary of State; entry of certain information into database by
county clerk; approval of application for or renewal of certificate; validity
of certificate; expiration; removal of authority to solemnize marriage.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-066__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Secretary of State shall establish
and maintain a statewide database of ministers, other church or religious
officials authorized to solemnize a marriage, notaries public or marriage
officiants who have been issued a certificate of permission to perform
marriages or whose certificate has been renewed. The database must:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-066__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Serve as the official list of ministers,
other church or religious officials authorized to solemnize a marriage,
notaries public or marriage officiants approved to perform marriages in this
State;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-066__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Provide for a single method of storing and
managing the official list;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-066__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Be a uniform, centralized and interactive
database;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-066__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Be electronically secure and accessible to
each county clerk in this State;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-066__subsec_1__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Contain the name, mailing address and other
pertinent information of each minister, other church or religious official
authorized to solemnize a marriage, notary public or marriage officiant as
prescribed by the Secretary of State; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-066__subsec_1__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Include a unique identifier assigned by the
Secretary of State to each minister, other church or religious official
authorized to solemnize a marriage, notary public or marriage officiant.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-066__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the county clerk approves an
application for a certificate of permission to perform marriages or for the
renewal of a certificate, the county clerk shall:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-066__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Enter all information contained in the
application into the electronic statewide database of ministers, other church
or religious officials authorized to solemnize a marriage, notaries public or
marriage officiants maintained by the Secretary of State not later than 10 days
after the certificate of permission to perform marriages or the renewal of a
certificate is approved by the county clerk; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-066__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Provide to the Secretary of State all information
related to the minister, other church or religious official authorized to
solemnize a marriage, notary public or marriage officiant pursuant to paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-066__subsec_2__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 1.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-066__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon approval of an application
pursuant to subsection 2, the minister, other church or religious official
authorized to solemnize a marriage, notary public or marriage officiant:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-066__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Shall comply with the laws of this State
governing the solemnization of marriage and conduct of ministers, other church
or religious officials authorized to solemnize a marriage, notaries public or
marriage officiants;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-066__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Is subject to further review or investigation
by the county clerk to ensure that he or she continues to meet the statutory
requirements for a person authorized to solemnize a marriage; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-066__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Shall provide the county clerk with any
changes to his or her status or information, including, without limitation, the
address or telephone number of the church or religious organization, if
applicable, or any other information pertaining to certification within 30 days
after such a change. If a notary public to whom a certificate of permission to
perform marriages has been issued or renewed changes his or her address, the
notary public must submit to the Secretary of State a request for an amended
certificate of appointment in accordance withNRS
240.036.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-066__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In addition to the circumstances set
forth in this section in which a certificate of permission to perform marriages
is no longer valid or expires, a county clerk may, in his or her discretion,
establish a policy providing that a certificate of permission expires 5 years
after the date it was issued or renewed. If a county clerk does not establish
such a policy, the certificate of permission remains valid unless and until it
becomes invalid or expires pursuant to this section.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-066__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A certificate of permission is valid
until:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-066__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the certificate is issued to a minister or
other church or religious official authorized to solemnize a marriage, the
county clerk has received an affidavit of removal of authority to solemnize
marriages pursuant toNRS 122.0665or
the certificate of permission is revoked pursuant toNRS 122.068.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-066__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the certificate is issued to a notary public,
the appointment as a notary public has expired or has been cancelled, revoked
or suspended. If, after the expiration of his or her appointment, a notary
public receives a new appointment, the notary public may reapply for a
certificate of permission to perform marriages.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-066__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An affidavit of removal of authority to
solemnize marriages that is received pursuant to paragraph</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-066__subsec_6__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 5
must be sent to the county clerk within 5 days after the minister or other
church or religious official authorized to solemnize a marriage ceased to be a
member of the church or religious organization in good standing or ceased to be
a minister or other church or religious official authorized to solemnize a
marriage for the church or religious organization.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-066__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the county clerk in the county where
the certificate of permission was issued has reason to believe that:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-066__subsec_7__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The minister or other church or religious
official authorized to solemnize a marriage is no longer in good standing
within his or her church or religious organization, or that he or she is no
longer a minister or other church or religious official authorized to solemnize
a marriage, or that such church or religious organization no longer exists;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-066__subsec_7__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The notary public is no longer in good
standing with the Secretary of State or that the appointment of the notary
public has expired; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-066__subsec_7__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The marriage officiant is no longer in good
standing with the county clerk,
ï¿½the county
clerk may require satisfactory proof of the good standing of the minister,
other church or religious official authorized to solemnize a marriage, notary
public or marriage officiant. If such proof is not presented within 15 days,
the county clerk shall remove the certificate of permission by amending the
electronic record of the minister, other church or religious official
authorized to solemnize a marriage, notary public or marriage officiant in the
statewide database pursuant to subsection 1.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-066__subsec_8">
            <num>8.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 9, if any minister or other church or religious official authorized
to solemnize a marriage to whom a certificate of permission has been issued
severs ties with his or her church or religious organization or moves from the
county in which his or her certificate was issued, the certificate shall expire
immediately upon such severance or move, and the church or religious
organization shall, within 5 days after the severance or move, file an
affidavit of removal of authority to solemnize marriages pursuant toNRS 122.0665. If the minister or other
church or religious official authorized to solemnize a marriage voluntarily
advises the county clerk of the county in which his or her certificate was
issued of his or her severance with his or her church or religious
organization, or that he or she has moved from the county, the certificate
shall expire immediately upon such severance or move without any notification
to the county clerk by the church or religious organization.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-066__subsec_9">
            <num>9.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any minister or other church or
religious official authorized to solemnize a marriage, who is retired and to
whom a certificate of permission has been issued, moves from the county in
which his or her certificate was issued to another county in this State, the
certificate remains valid until such time as the certificate otherwise expires
or is removed or revoked as prescribed by law. The minister or other church or
religious official authorized to solemnize a marriage must provide his or her
new address to the county clerk in the county to which the minister or other
church or religious official authorized to solemnize a marriage has moved.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-066__subsec_10">
            <num>10.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any notary public or marriage
officiant to whom a certificate of permission has been issued or renewed moves
from the county in which his or her certificate was issued, the certificate
shall expire immediately upon such move.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-066__subsec_11">
            <num>11.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Secretary of State may adopt
regulations concerning the creation and administration of the statewide
database. This section does not prohibit the Secretary of State from making the
database publicly accessible for the purpose of viewing ministers, other church
or religious officials who are authorized to solemnize a marriage, notaries
public or marriage officiants to whom a certificate of permission to perform
marriages has been issued or renewed in this State.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1290; A1969,
92;1971,
1550;2009,
728;2011,
1855;2013,
1191,3668;2017,
1030)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-0665">
          <num>122.0665</num>
          <heading>Affidavit of removal of authority to solemnize marriages: Form
of affidavit; filing by church or religious organization that authorized
official to solemnize marriages.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-0665__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a minister or other church or
religious official authorized to solemnize a marriage is no longer authorized
to solemnize a marriage by the church or religious organization that authorized
the minister or other church or religious official to solemnize marriages when
he or she applied for a certificate of permission to perform marriages pursuant
toNRS 122.064, the church or religious
organization shall, within 5 days after the authorization is terminated, file
an affidavit of removal of authority to solemnize marriages with the county
clerk of the county where the original affidavit of authority to solemnize
marriages was filed.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-0665__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The affidavit of removal of authority
to solemnize marriages must be in substantially the following form:
AFFIDAVIT
OF REMOVAL OF AUTHORITY TO SOLEMNIZE MARRIAGES FOR CHURCHES OR RELIGIOUS
ORGANIZATIONS
State of Nevadaï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ }
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ }ss.
County of ............... }
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ The........................................
(name of church or religious organization) is organized and carries on its work
in the State of Nevada. Its active meetings are located
at........................................ (street address, city or town).
The........................................ (name of church or religious
organization) hereby removes the authority
of........................................ (name of minister or other church or
religious official authorized to solemnize marriages), filed in the County
of........................................, on the.......... day of the month
of...................., of the year.........., to solemnize marriages.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ I am duly authorized
by........................................ (name of church or religious
organization) to complete and submit this affidavit.
..........................................
Signature of Official
..........................................
Name of Official
(type or print name)
..........................................
Title of Official
..........................................
Address
..........................................
City, State and Zip Code
..........................................
Telephone Number
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ Signed and sworn to (or
affirmed) before me this.......... day of the month of.................... of
the year...........
..........................................
Notary Public for
..............................
County, Nevada.
My appointment
expires..............................</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2009,
722; A2013,
1193,3670)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-067">
          <num>122.067</num>
          <heading>Suspension of certificate for failure to pay child support or
comply with certain subpoenas or warrants; reinstatement of certificate.
[Effective until the date of the repeal of 42 U.S.C. ï¿½ 666, the federal law
requiring each state to establish procedures for withholding, suspending and
restricting the professional, occupational and recreational licenses for child
support arrearages and for noncompliance with certain processes relating to
paternity or child support proceedings.]</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-067__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a county clerk receives a copy of a
court order issued pursuant toNRS 425.540that provides for the suspension of all professional, occupational and
recreational licenses, certificates and permits issued to a person who is the
holder of a certificate of permission, the county clerk shall deem the
certificate of permission issued to that person to be suspended at the end of
the 30th day after the date on which the court order was issued unless the
county clerk receives a letter issued to the holder of the certificate of
permission by the district attorney or other public agency pursuant toNRS 425.550stating that the holder of the
certificate of permission has complied with the subpoena or warrant or has
satisfied the arrearage pursuant toNRS
425.560.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-067__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A county clerk shall reinstate a
certificate of permission that has been suspended by a district court pursuant
toNRS 425.540if the county clerk
receives a letter issued by the district attorney or other public agency
pursuant toNRS 425.550to the person
whose certificate of permission was suspended stating that the person whose
certificate of permission was suspended has complied with the subpoena or
warrant or has satisfied the arrearage pursuant toNRS 425.560.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1997,
2040)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-068">
          <num>122.068</num>
          <heading>Revocation of certificates and removal of authority to solemnize
marriages; hearing; duties of Secretary of State.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-068__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any county clerk who has issued or
renewed a certificate of permission to perform marriages to a minister, other
church or religious official authorized to solemnize a marriage, notary public
or marriage officiant pursuant toNRS
122.062to122.073, inclusive, may
revoke the certificate for good cause shown after a hearing.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-068__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the certificate of permission to
perform marriages of any minister, other church or religious official
authorized to solemnize a marriage, notary public or marriage officiant is
revoked or if the county clerk has received an affidavit of removal of authority
to solemnize marriages pursuant toNRS
122.0665, the county clerk shall inform the Secretary of State of that
fact, and the Secretary of State shall immediately remove the name of the
minister, other church or religious official authorized to solemnize a
marriage, notary public or marriage officiant from the official list contained
in the database of ministers, other church or religious officials authorized to
solemnize a marriage, notaries public or marriage officiants and shall notify
each county clerk and county recorder in the State of the revocation or removal
of authority.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1291; A2009,
730;2013,
1194,3671;2017,
1032)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-071">
          <num>122.071</num>
          <heading>Judicial review.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Any
minister, other church or religious official authorized to solemnize a
marriage, notary public or marriage officiant whose application for a
certificate of permission to perform marriages or renewal of such certificate
is denied, or whose certificate of permission is revoked, is entitled to
judicial review of such action in the district court of the county in which
such action was taken.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1291; A2009,
731;2013,
1195;2017,
1033)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-073">
          <num>122.073</num>
          <heading>Additional regulations by county clerk.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Each
county clerk may prescribe additional regulations, which shall not conflict
with the provisions of this chapter, relating to the issuance and revocation of
certificates of permission to perform marriages.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1291; A2009,
731)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-080">
          <num>122.080</num>
          <heading>Solemnization of marriage by Supreme Court justice, appellate
judge, district judge, justice of the peace, municipal judge, commissioner and
deputy commissioner of civil marriages and mayor; unlawful acts.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-080__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>After receipt of the marriage license
previously issued to persons wishing to be married as provided inNRS 122.040and122.050, it is lawful for any justice of
the Supreme Court, any judge of the Court of Appeals, any judge of the district
court, any justice of the peace in his or her township if it is not a
commissioner township, any justice of the peace in a commissioner township if
authorized pursuant to subsection 3, any municipal judge if authorized pursuant
to subsection 4, any commissioner of civil marriages within his or her county
and within a commissioner township therein, any deputy commissioner of civil
marriages within the county of his or her appointment and within a commissioner
township therein or any mayor if authorized pursuant to subsection 5, to join
together in marriage all persons not prohibited by this chapter.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-080__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>This section does not prohibit:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-080__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A justice of the peace of one township, while
acting in the place and stead of the justice of the peace of any other
township, from performing marriage ceremonies within the other township, if
such other township is not a commissioner township.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-080__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A justice of the peace of one township
performing marriages in another township of the same county where there is no
duly qualified and acting justice of the peace, if such other township is not a
commissioner township or if he or she is authorized to perform the marriage
pursuant to subsection 3.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-080__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In any calendar year, a justice of the
peace may perform not more than 20 marriage ceremonies in commissioner
townships if he or she does not accept any fee, gratuity, gift, honorarium or
anything of value for or in connection with solemnizing the marriage other than
a nonmonetary gift that is of nominal value.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-080__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In any calendar year, a municipal judge
may perform not more than 20 marriage ceremonies in this State if he or she
does not accept any fee, gratuity, gift, honorarium or anything of value for or
in connection with solemnizing the marriage other than a nonmonetary gift that
is of nominal value.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-080__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A mayor of an incorporated city may
perform a marriage ceremony if he or she is:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-080__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The mayor of a city organized under general
law; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-080__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Authorized by the city council or other
governing body of a city organized under a special charter.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-080__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any mayor who performs a marriage
ceremony shall not accept any fee, gratuity, gift, honorarium or anything of
value for or in connection with solemnizing the marriage other than a
nonmonetary gift that is of nominal value.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-080__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any justice of the peace who performs a
marriage ceremony in a commissioner township or any municipal judge or mayor
who performs a marriage ceremony in this State and who, in violation of this
section, accepts any fee, gratuity, gift, honorarium or anything of value for
or in connection with solemnizing the marriage is guilty of a misdemeanor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 4:33:1861; A1867,
88;1899,
47;1901,
19;1911,
317;1925,
232;1933,
42; R1937,
72; A1943,
175;1947,
830;1951,
431]—(NRS A1969,
764;1993,
1463;1999,
1323;2013,
1747;2017,
758,1197)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-090">
          <num>122.090</num>
          <heading>Marriage solemnized by unauthorized person: When valid.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>No marriage solemnized before any person
professing to be a judge, justice, minister or other church or religious
official authorized to solemnize a marriage, notary public or marriage
officiant to whom a certificate of permission to perform marriages or a renewal
of a certificate has been issued, commissioner of civil marriages, deputy
commissioner of civil marriages or mayor shall be deemed or adjudged to be
void, nor shall the validity thereof be in any way affected on account of any
want of jurisdiction or authority, provided it be consummated with a full
belief on the part of the persons so married, or either of them, that they have
been lawfully joined in marriage.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [13:33:1861; B ï¿½ 206; BH ï¿½ 482; C ï¿½ 493; RL ï¿½ 2349;
NCL ï¿½ 4061]—(NRS A1969,
764;2009,
731;2013,
1195;2017,
1033,1198)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-100">
          <num>122.100</num>
          <heading>Marriages solemnized between March 3, 1937, and March 24, 1943,
validated.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>All marriages
solemnized since March 3, 1937, and performed in the manner prescribed and
required by section 4 of chapter 33, Statutes of Nevada 1861, prior to its
repeal on March 3, 1937, are hereby expressly validated. All such marriages so
solemnized and performed between March 3, 1937, and March 24, 1943, are hereby
declared to be valid to all intents and purposes to the same extent as if
section 4 of chapter 33, Statutes of Nevada 1861, had not been repealed on
March 3, 1937.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [4a:33:1861; added1943,
208; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 4052]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-103">
          <num>122.103</num>
          <heading>Marriages solemnized by certain ministers before May 20, 1967,
validated.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>All marriages
solemnized by ministers holding certificates of permission issued pursuant to
formerNRS 122.070are
hereby expressly validated.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1291)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-110">
          <num>122.110</num>
          <heading>No particular form of solemnization required; witness.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-110__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In the solemnization of marriage, no
particular form is required except that the parties shall declare, in the
presence of the justice, judge, minister or other church or religious official
authorized to solemnize a marriage, notary public or marriage officiant to whom
a certificate of permission to perform marriages or a renewal of a certificate
has been issued, justice of the peace, commissioner of civil marriages, deputy
commissioner of civil marriages or mayor, and the attending witness, that they
take each other as spouses.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-110__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In every case, there shall be at least
one witness present besides the person performing the ceremony.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [6:33:1861; B ï¿½ 199; BH ï¿½ 475; C ï¿½ 486; RL ï¿½ 2342;
NCL ï¿½ 4054]—(NRS A1969,
764;1977,
470;2009,
731;2013,
1195;2017,
759,1033,1199)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-120">
          <num>122.120</num>
          <heading>Certificate of marriage: Form.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-120__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>After a marriage is solemnized, the
person solemnizing the marriage shall give to each couple being married an
uncertified copy of a certificate of marriage.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-120__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The certificate of marriage must
contain the date of birth of each applicant as contained in the form of
marriage license pursuant toNRS 122.050.
If two persons, regardless of gender, who are spouses of each other are being
rejoined in marriage pursuant to subsection 2 ofNRS 122.020, the certificate of marriage
must state that the persons were rejoined in marriage and that the certificate
is replacing a record of marriage which was lost or destroyed or is otherwise
unobtainable. The certificate of marriage must be in substantially the
following form:
State of Nevada
Marriage Certificate
State of Nevadaï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ }
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ }ss.
County of............................................ }
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ This is to certify that the
undersigned, ................................ (a minister or other church or
religious official authorized to solemnize a marriage, notary public, judge,
justice of the peace of ................................ County, commissioner
of civil marriages, deputy commissioner of civil marriages, marriage officiant
or mayor, as the case may be), did on the ................ day of the month of
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½. of the year ..............., at ................ (address or church),
................ (city), Nevada, join or rejoin, as the case may be, in lawful
wedlock ................ (name), of ................ (city), State of
................, date of birth ................, and ................ (name),
of ................(city), State of ................, date of birth
................, with their mutual consent, in the presence of
................ and ................ (witnesses). (If two persons, regardless
of gender, who are the spouses of each other are being rejoined in marriage
pursuant to subsection 2 ofNRS 122.020,
this certificate replaces the record of the marriage of the persons who are
being rejoined in marriage.)
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ .........................................................................
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ Signature
of person performing
(Seal of County Clerk)ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ the
marriage
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ .........................................................................
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ Name
under signature typewritten
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ or
printed in black ink
......................................................
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ County Clerk
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ .........................................................................
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ Official
title of person performing
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ the
marriage
......................................................
......................................................
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ Coupleï¿½s mailing address
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-120__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>All information contained in the
certificate of marriage must be typewritten or legibly printed in black ink,
except the signatures. The signature of the person performing the marriage must
be an original signature.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [7:33:1861; A1867,
88; BH ï¿½ 476; C ï¿½ 487; RL ï¿½ 2343; NCL ï¿½ 4055]—(NRS A1977,
470;1987,
1421;2001,
32;2007,
1056;2009,
731,1506;2013,
1195;2017,
759,1033,1199,1522;2023,
1310)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-130">
          <num>122.130</num>
          <heading>Certificate of marriage: Recording; loss or destruction before
recording; replacement certificate; fees.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-130__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each person who solemnizes a marriage
shall make a record of it and, within 10 days after the marriage, shall deliver
to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-130__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the board of county commissioners has
adopted an ordinance pursuant toNRS 246.100,
the county clerk of the county where the license was issued the original
certificate of marriage required byNRS
122.120.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-130__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the board of county commissioners has not
adopted an ordinance pursuant toNRS 246.100,
the county recorder of the county where the license was issued the original
certificate of marriage required byNRS
122.120.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-130__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the original certificate of marriage
that is held by the person who solemnizes the marriage is lost or destroyed
before it is delivered pursuant to subsection 1, the county clerk may charge
and collect from the person who solemnizes the marriage a fee of not more than
$15 for the preparation of an affidavit of loss or destruction and the issuance
of a replacement certificate. All fees collected by the county clerk pursuant
to this subsection must be deposited in the county general fund.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-130__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>All original certificates must be
recorded by the county recorder or filed by the county clerk in a book to be
kept by him or her for that purpose. For recording or filing the original
certificates, the county recorder or county clerk is entitled to the fees
designated in subsection 2 ofNRS 122.060and subsection 3 ofNRS 122.135. All
such fees must be deposited in the county general fund.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [8:33:1861; A1899,
47; C ï¿½ 488; RL ï¿½ 2344; NCL ï¿½ 4056] + [9:33:1861; A1899,
47; C ï¿½ 489; RL ï¿½ 2345; NCL ï¿½ 4057]—(NRS A1965,
1253;1967,
1110;1969,
764,1462;1977,
470;1983,
348;1987,
1423;1999,
1323;2007,
888;2013,
3671)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-135">
          <num>122.135</num>
          <heading>Preparation of affidavit of correction to correct information in
certificate of marriage; fees.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-135__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 2, if any information in a certificate of marriage is incorrect, the
county clerk or the county recorder may charge and collect from a person a fee
of not more than $25 for the preparation of an affidavit of correction.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-135__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Neither the county clerk nor the county
recorder may charge and collect from a person any fee for the preparation of an
affidavit of correction pursuant to subsection 1 if the only errors to be
corrected in the certificate of marriage are clerical errors that were made by
the county clerk.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-135__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Whether or not a person is required to
pay any fee for the preparation of an affidavit of correction pursuant to
subsection 1:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-135__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The county clerk shall charge and collect
from the person a fee in an amount equal to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="122-135__subsec_3__subsec_a__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If the board of county commissioners
has adopted an ordinance pursuant toNRS
246.100, the amount that the county clerk is required to charge and collect
pursuant toNRS 246.180for filing the
corrected certificate of marriage; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="122-135__subsec_3__subsec_a__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If the board of county commissioners
has not adopted an ordinance pursuant toNRS
246.100, the amount that the county recorder is required to charge and
collect pursuant toNRS 247.305, and the
county clerk shall pay the fee over to the county recorder as his or her fee
for recording the corrected certificate of marriage; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-135__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The county recorder shall charge and collect
from the person a fee in an amount equal to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="122-135__subsec_3__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If the board of county commissioners
has adopted an ordinance pursuant toNRS
246.100, the amount that the county clerk is required to charge and collect
pursuant toNRS 246.180, and the county
recorder shall pay the fee over to the county clerk as his or her fee for
recording the corrected certificate of marriage; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="122-135__subsec_3__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If the board of county commissioners
has not adopted an ordinance pursuant toNRS
246.100, the amount that the county recorder is required to charge and
collect pursuant toNRS 247.305for
recording the corrected certificate of marriage.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-135__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>All fees collected pursuant to this
section must be deposited in the county general fund.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1999,
1322; A2007,
889)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-137">
          <num>122.137</num>
          <heading>Amended certificate of marriage: Issuance for name change;
requirements; fee.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-137__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a marriage was solemnized in this
State and a party to the marriage receives a certified copy of a court order
from a court of this State or another state, the District of Columbia or any
territory of the United States changing the name of the party, the county clerk
of the county where the original marriage license was issued to the party shall
issue an amended certificate of marriage to that party that sets forth the new
name of the party, upon receipt by the county clerk of:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-137__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A certified copy of the original certificate
of marriage;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-137__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A certified copy of the court order;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-137__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A notarized affidavit of amendment prepared
by the county clerk and executed by the parties to the marriage; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-137__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The fees required pursuant to subsection 2.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-137__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The county clerk may charge and collect
a fee of not more than $25 for the preparation of the affidavit of amendment
pursuant to paragraph</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-137__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 1. The party requesting the amended
certificate of marriage must also pay any fee required pursuant toNRS 246.180orNRS 247.305, as applicable, for the filing
or recording of the amended certificate of marriage.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-137__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon compliance with subsection 1, the
county clerk shall issue the amended certificate of marriage to the parties to
the marriage.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-137__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The county clerk or county recorder, as
applicable, shall maintain as a public record the original certificate of
marriage and the amended certificate of marriage issued pursuant to this
section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2023,
1306)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-138">
          <num>122.138</num>
          <heading>Amended certificate of marriage: Form.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-138__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An amended certificate of marriage
issued pursuant toNRS 122.137must be
substantially in the following form:
State of Nevada
Amended Certificate of Marriage
State of Nevadaï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ }
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ }ss.
County of ........................................... }
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ This is to acknowledge that a
marriage officiant, did on the ........ day of the month of ........ of the
year ........, at ................ (address or church), ................
(city), Nevada, join in lawful wedlock ............... (name), of
................ (city), State of ................, date of birth ..........,
and ................ (name), of ............... (city), State of
................, date of birth ........, with their mutual consent, in the
presence of at least one witness.
(Seal of County Clerk)
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ This certificate is issued to
reflect an amendment made pursuant to Instrument No. ............ on file at
the Office of the ................ County [Clerk or Recorder] and the court
order issued in ................ County, State of ................, Case No.
..........
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ The original Certificate of
Marriage No. .........., recorded or filed as Instrument No. .........., is on
file at the Office of the ................ County [Clerk or Recorder].
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-138__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>All information contained in the
amended certificate of marriage must be typewritten or legibly printed in black
ink, except the signatures.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2023,
1306)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-139">
          <num>122.139</num>
          <heading>Amended certificate of marriage: Filing or recording.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-139__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a county clerk issues an amended
certificate of marriage pursuant toNRS
122.137and the board of county commissioners:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-139__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Has adopted an ordinance pursuant toNRS 246.100, the county clerk shall, within
10 days after its issuance, file the amended certificate of marriage in the
office of the county clerk.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-139__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Has not adopted an ordinance pursuant toNRS 246.100, the party to whom the amended
certificate of marriage is issued shall, within 10 days after receipt, file the
amended certificate of marriage with the county recorder where the original
certificate of marriage was recorded.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-139__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the recording or filing of an
amended certificate of marriage pursuant to this section, the county recorder
or county clerk is entitled to the fees designated in subsection 2 ofNRS 122.137.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2023,
1307)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-140">
          <num>122.140</num>
          <heading>Illegitimate children legitimatized.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Illegitimate
children shall become legitimatized by the subsequent marriage of their parents
with each other.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [15:33:1861; B ï¿½ 208; BH ï¿½ 484; C ï¿½ 495; RL ï¿½ 2351;
NCL ï¿½ 4063]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-150">
          <num>122.150</num>
          <heading>Forms used by Friends or Quakers valid.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>All
marriages solemnized among the people called ï¿½Friendsï¿½ or ï¿½Quakers,ï¿½ in the
forms heretofore practiced and in use in their meetings, shall be good and
valid.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [17:33:1861; B ï¿½ 210; BH ï¿½ 486; C ï¿½ 497; RL ï¿½ 2353;
NCL ï¿½ 4065]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-160">
          <num>122.160</num>
          <heading>Marriages between Indians performed by tribal custom on
reservation or in colony: Validity; certificate of declaration.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-160__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Marriages between Indians performed in
accordance with tribal customs within closed Indian reservations and Indian
colonies have the same validity as marriages performed in any other manner
provided for by the laws of this State, if there is recorded or filed in the
county in which the marriage takes place, within 30 days after the performance
of the tribal marriage, a certificate declaring the marriage to have been
performed.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-160__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The certificate of declaration required
to be recorded or filed by subsection 1 must include the names of the persons
married, their ages, tribe, and place and date of marriage. The certificate
must be signed by an official of the tribe, reservation or colony.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-160__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The certificate must be:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-160__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the board of county commissioners has
adopted an ordinance pursuant toNRS 246.100,
filed with the county clerk of the county in which the marriage was performed
and filed by the county clerk without charge.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-160__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the board of county commissioners has not
adopted an ordinance pursuant toNRS 246.100,
recorded with the county recorder of the county in which the marriage was
performed and recorded by the county recorder without charge.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1:188:1943; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 4072] + [2:188:1943; 1943 NCL
ï¿½ 4072.01] + [3:188:1943; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 4072.02]—(NRS A1997,
2288;2001,
1755;2007,
889,1313)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-170">
          <num>122.170</num>
          <heading>Marriages between Indians consummated in accordance with tribal
customs valid: Certificate of marriage; contents; recording.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-170__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Marriages between Indians heretofore or
hereafter consummated in accordance with tribal custom have the same validity as
marriages performed in any other manner provided for by the laws of the State
of Nevada.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-170__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A certificate of any such marriage may
be signed by:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-170__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An official of the tribe of which at least
one of the parties is a member;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-170__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An official of the reservation or colony in
or upon which at least one of the parties shall at the time reside; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-170__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The superintendent of an Indian agency
legally established in this State by the United States.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-170__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The certificate may be:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-170__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the board of county commissioners has
adopted an ordinance pursuant toNRS 246.100,
filed in the office of the county clerk of the county where such marriage took
place, and within 30 days thereafter; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-170__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the board of county commissioners has not
adopted an ordinance pursuant toNRS 246.100,
recorded in the office of the recorder of the county where such marriage took place,
and within 30 days thereafter,
ï¿½and such
certificate or a certified copy thereof is prima facie evidence of the facts
therein recited.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-170__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The certificate must give the names of
the parties married, their ages, tribe, and the place and date of the marriage,
and must show the official status of the person signing the same.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-170__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any certificate, affidavit or other
type of proof recognized by the United States, or any department thereof, as
proof of a valid tribal marriage, regardless of when or where the tribal
marriage was entered into, is proof of the validity of the tribal marriage in
the State of Nevada.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1:97:1945; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 4072.03] + [2:97:1945; 1943
NCL ï¿½ 4072.04] + [3:97:1945; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 4072.05]—(NRS A2007,
890)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-173">
          <num>122.173</num>
          <heading>Commissioner of civil marriages: County clerk is ex officio in
larger counties; appointment of county clerk in smaller counties; solemnization
of marriages; no additional compensation.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-173__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In a county whose population is 700,000
or more and in which a commissioner township is located, the county clerk
shall:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-173__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Be commissioner of civil marriages for such
township; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-173__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Solemnize marriages within each commissioner
township located within his or her county.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-173__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In a county whose population is less
than 700,000 and in which a commissioner township is located, the board of
county commissioners may, by ordinance, appoint the county clerk to act as the
commissioner of civil marriages. Such an ordinance may authorize the
commissioner of civil marriages to solemnize marriages within each commissioner
township located within the county.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-173__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The county clerk is not entitled to
receive additional compensation for acting in the capacity of commissioner of
civil marriages.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
765; A1993,
34;2011,
1148)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-175">
          <num>122.175</num>
          <heading>Deputy commissioners of civil marriages: Appointment; powers and
duties; compensation; limitation on number on duty.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-175__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In a county whose population is 700,000
or more, the commissioner of civil marriages may appoint deputy commissioners
of civil marriages. Such deputies shall:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-175__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Solemnize marriages in commissioner townships
under the direction of the commissioner; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-175__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Perform such other duties as the commissioner
may direct.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-175__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In a county whose population is less
than 700,000 and in which the board of county commissioners has appointed the
county clerk to act as the commissioner of civil marriages, the board may, by
ordinance, establish the number of deputy commissioners of civil marriages
which may be appointed by the commissioner of civil marriages to carry out the
duties set forth in subsection 1.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-175__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>No deputy commissioner of civil
marriages may solemnize marriages at any time other than during the working
hours or shift during which the deputy commissioner is employed.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-175__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The deputy commissioners of civil
marriages are employees of the county clerkï¿½s office and are entitled to be
compensated by a salary and by such other benefits as are available to other
county personnel regularly employed in the same county clerkï¿½s office. The
compensation of any deputy commissioner of civil marriages must not be based in
any manner upon the number or volume of marriages that the deputy commissioner
may solemnize in the performance of his or her duties.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-175__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In counties in which deputy
commissioners of civil marriages are employed, no more than two deputy
commissioners may be on duty within the courthouse of such a county for the
purpose of solemnizing marriages at any one time.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
765; A1993,
34;2011,
1149)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-177">
          <num>122.177</num>
          <heading>Area for solemnizing marriages.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-177__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The county shall provide a suitable area
separate from the marriage license bureau or other place where marriage
licenses are issued for the solemnizing of marriages.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-177__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The area shall be:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-177__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Appropriately furnished by the county to
provide a tranquil atmosphere and the solemnizing ceremony shall be privately
conducted in a dignified manner without haste; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-177__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Situated in a building entirely separate from
and unconnected with any building in which marriage licenses are issued.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
766; A1979,
637)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-179">
          <num>122.179</num>
          <heading>Clerical personnel, supplies and equipment to be provided by
county.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-179__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The county shall provide suitable
office space, office equipment, office supplies, and secretarial or other
clerical personnel necessary for the proper operation of the office of the
commissioner of civil marriages.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-179__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The county clerk shall establish the
office of the commissioner of civil marriages as a separate office and shall
maintain separate records for that office.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
766; A1977,
576)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-181">
          <num>122.181</num>
          <heading>Fees for solemnizing marriages: Amounts; disposition.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-181__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner of civil marriages or
his or her deputy commissioner of civil marriages is entitled to receive as his
or her fee for solemnizing a marriage $70. The fee must be deposited in the
county general fund.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-181__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner of civil marriages or
his or her deputy commissioner of civil marriages shall also at the time of
solemnizing a marriage collect the additional sum of $5 for the Account for Aid
for Victims of Domestic or Sexual Violence in the State General Fund. The fees
collected for this purpose must be paid over to the county treasurer by the
county clerk on or before the fifth day of each month for the preceding
calendar month, and must be credited to that Account. The county treasurer
shall, on or before the 15th day of each month, remit those fees deposited by
the clerk to the State Controller for credit to that Account.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
766; A1975,
540;1991,
1867;2001,
3217;2013,
1196)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-183">
          <num>122.183</num>
          <heading>Hours of operation for office.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The board of
county commissioners may, by ordinance, determine the hours of operation for
the office of the commissioner of civil marriages.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
766; A1979,
637;1993,
29,35,2261,2262;2003,
341)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-185">
          <num>122.185</num>
          <heading>Signs required in office and rooms; contents.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-185__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>That the solemnization of the marriage
by the commissioner of civil marriages is not necessary for a valid marriage
and that the parties wishing to be married may have a justice of the peace
within a township where such justice of the peace is permitted to perform
marriages, or any minister, other church or religious official authorized to
solemnize a marriage or notary public of their choice who holds a valid
certificate of permission to perform marriages within the State, perform the
ceremony;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-185__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The amount of the fee to be charged for
solemnization of a marriage in the office of the commissioner of civil
marriages;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-185__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>That all fees charged are paid into the
county general fund of the particular county involved;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-185__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>That other than the statutory fee, the
commissioner of civil marriages and the deputy commissioners of civil marriages
are precluded by law from receiving any gratuity fee or remuneration whatsoever
for solemnizing a marriage; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-185__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>That if the commissioner of civil
marriages, any deputy commissioner of civil marriages, or any other employee in
the office of the commissioner or in the office of the county clerk solicits
such an extra gratuity fee or other remuneration, the matter should be reported
to the district attorney for such county.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
766; A2009,
732;2013,
1196,3671)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-187">
          <num>122.187</num>
          <heading>Receipt of additional fees prohibited.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>No
other fee may be charged or received by the commissioner of civil marriages for
solemnizing a marriage or for any other pertinent service other than the fee
established byNRS 122.181.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
767)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-189">
          <num>122.189</num>
          <heading>Prohibited acts.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-189__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Solicit, accept or receive any
gratuity, remuneration or fee whatsoever for the solemnizing of marriages;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-189__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Participate in or receive the benefits
of any fees solicited or received by any other person; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-189__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Influence or attempt to influence any
person to have a marriage solemnized in the office of the commissioner of civil
marriages.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
767; A1977,
576)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-191">
          <num>122.191</num>
          <heading>Display and contents of signs indicating location of office.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Signs may be displayed to inform any person of
the location of the office of the commissioner of civil marriages. Such signs
shall have printed thereon only the following words: ï¿½Office of the
Commissioner of Civil Marriages.ï¿½ Such signs shall be displayed in a
conservative manner commensurate with the dignified function of the office of
the commissioner of civil marriages.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
767)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-193">
          <num>122.193</num>
          <heading>Penalty.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Any person
who violates any provision ofNRS 122.173to122.193, inclusive, is guilty of a
misdemeanor.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
767)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-200">
          <num>122.200</num>
          <heading>False statement to procure marriage license.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Any person who shall make a false statement in
procuring a marriage license with reference to any matter required byNRS 122.040and122.050to be stated under oath shall be
guilty of a gross misdemeanor.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 5:33:1861; A1867,
88;1899,
47;1919,
382;1927,
49;1947,
41;1949,
91; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 4053]—(NRS A1967,
530)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-210">
          <num>122.210</num>
          <heading>Unauthorized issuance of marriage license by county clerk.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If any county clerk shall issue or sign any
marriage license in any manner other than is authorized by this chapter, the
county clerk shall forfeit and pay a sum not exceeding $1,000 to and for the
use of the person aggrieved.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 5:33:1861; A1867,
88;1899,
47;1919,
382;1927,
49;1947,
41;1949,
91; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 4053]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-215">
          <num>122.215</num>
          <heading>Solicitation to perform marriage prohibited on county property
where marriage licenses are issued; civil penalty.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>It
is unlawful for any county employee, commercial wedding chapel employee or
other person to solicit or otherwise influence, while on county property where
marriage licenses are issued, any person to be married by a marriage
commissioner or justice of the peace or at a commercial wedding chapel. Any
person who violates this section is subject to a civil penalty of not more than
$500 for each violation. A board of county commissioners may, at the request of
the county clerk, enact an ordinance delegating to a hearing officer the
authority to determine violations of this section and to levy civil penalties
for such violations.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1977,
577; A2013,
3672;2019,
457)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-220">
          <num>122.220</num>
          <heading>Solemnizing marriage without exhibition of marriage license.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-220__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is unlawful for any Supreme Court
justice, judge of the Court of Appeals, judge of a district court, justice of
the peace, municipal judge, minister or other church or religious official
authorized to solemnize a marriage, notary public, commissioner of civil
marriages, deputy commissioner of civil marriages, marriage officiant or mayor
to join together as spouses persons allowed by law to be joined in marriage,
until the persons proposing such marriage exhibit to him or her a license from
the county clerk as provided by law.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-220__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any Supreme Court justice, judge of the
Court of Appeals, judge of a district court, justice of the peace, municipal
judge, minister or other church or religious official authorized to solemnize a
marriage, notary public, commissioner of civil marriages, deputy commissioner
of civil marriages, marriage officiant or mayor who violates the provisions of
subsection 1 is guilty of a misdemeanor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 214; RL ï¿½ 6479; NCL ï¿½ 10162] + [1911
C&amp;P ï¿½ 215; RL ï¿½ 6480; NCL ï¿½ 10163]—(NRS A1967,
530;1969,
765;1993,
1463;2009,
733;2013,
1197,1747;2017,
760,1035,1200)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-230">
          <num>122.230</num>
          <heading>Failure of person solemnizing marriage to make and deliver
certificate to county clerk or county recorder.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-230__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the board of county commissioners
has adopted an ordinance pursuant toNRS
246.100, the county clerk; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-230__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the board of county commissioners
has not adopted an ordinance pursuant toNRS
246.100, the county recorder,
ï¿½is guilty of
a misdemeanor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 10:33:1861; A1903,
70; RL ï¿½ 2346; NCL ï¿½ 4058]—(NRS A1967,
530;1987,
1423;2007,
890;2013,
3672)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-240">
          <num>122.240</num>
          <heading>Failure of county recorder or county clerk to record certificate
of marriage.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Every county recorder
or county clerk who fails or neglects to record or file a certificate of
marriage as required by this chapter is guilty of a misdemeanor.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 10:33:1861; A1903,
70; RL ï¿½ 2346; NCL ï¿½ 4058]—(NRS A1967,
530;1987,
1423;2007,
890;2013,
3672)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-250">
          <num>122.250</num>
          <heading>Willful making of false certificate of marriage.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If any person shall willfully make any false
certificate of any marriage or pretended marriage, the person is guilty of a
gross misdemeanor.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [11:33:1861; B ï¿½ 204; BH ï¿½ 480; C ï¿½ 491; RL ï¿½ 2347;
NCL ï¿½ 4059]—(NRS A1967,
530)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-260">
          <num>122.260</num>
          <heading>Solemnization of marriage by unauthorized person or where legal
impediment known; civil penalty; delegation of authority to hearing officer to
determine violations and levy penalties.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If
any person undertakes to join others in marriage and is not lawfully authorized
so to do, or knows of the existence of any legal impediment to the proposed
marriage, the person shall be punished by a civil penalty of not more than
$1,500. A board of county commissioners may enact an ordinance delegating to a
hearing officer the authority to determine violations of this section and to
levy civil penalties for those violations.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [12:33:1861; B ï¿½ 205; BH ï¿½ 481; C ï¿½ 492; RL ï¿½ 2348;
NCL ï¿½ 4060]—(NRS A1967,
530;2017,
1035;2019,
457)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-270">
          <num>122.270</num>
          <heading>Recovery of forfeitures by civil actions.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>In all cases when a violation of the
provisions of this chapter is not declared a misdemeanor or gross misdemeanor,
the fines and forfeitures shall be recovered by a civil action, to be brought
by any person aggrieved or by the county treasurer.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [16:33:1861; B ï¿½ 209; BH ï¿½ 485; C ï¿½ 496; RL ï¿½ 2352;
NCL ï¿½ 4064]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-280">
          <num>122.280</num>
          <heading>Display of information.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>In
each county whose population is 100,000 or more, the county may provide a space
at each office and branch office of the county clerk in which a commercial
wedding chapel, a licensed business which operates principally for the
performance of weddings in the county or a church or religious organization
incorporated, organized or established in this State may display printed or
digital information.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2015,
2629; A2021,
573)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_122-290">
          <num>122.290</num>
          <heading>Certificate of vow renewal: Establishment of program; form; fee.</heading>
          <subsection eId="122-290__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A county clerk may, in his or her
discretion, establish a program to provide for the issuance of a certificate of
vow renewal. If a county clerk establishes such a program, upon the request of
a couple who desires to renew their marriage vows, the county clerk shall issue
a certificate of vow renewal.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-290__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The request for a certificate of vow
renewal must be made on a form prescribed by the county clerk and must include
the date of the vow renewal and the county in which the vow renewal occurred.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-290__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The certificate of vow renewal must
contain:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="122-290__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The date of the vow renewal;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-290__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The county in which the vow renewal occurred;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-290__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The name of the persons to whom the
certificate of vow renewal is issued; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="122-290__subsec_3__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A statement that the certificate of vow
renewal is not a record of marriage.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-290__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>This section may not be used to
establish a record of marriage.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-290__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A county clerk may charge and collect a
fee in the same amount as the fee collected for the issuance of a marriage
license pursuant toNRS 122.060to cover
the cost of preparing the certificate furnished pursuant to this section.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="122-290__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of
law to the contrary, a certificate of vow renewal is exempt from any schedule
for the retention of records that applies to records in the office of the
county clerk.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2017,
1024)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>