<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="NRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-475"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-475"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#nevada-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-nv"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="475"/>
          <FRBRname value="NRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-475/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-475/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-475/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-475/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="nevada-legislature" href="https://www.leg.state.nv.us" showAs="Nevada State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_475">
        <num>475</num>
        <heading>CRIMES AND RESPONSIBILITIES</heading>
        <section eId="sec_475-010">
          <num>475.010</num>
          <heading>Willful or negligent failure to guard or extinguish fire;
penalty.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Every person who
willfully or negligently sets or fails to guard carefully or extinguish any
fire, whether on the personï¿½s own land or the land of another, whereby the
timber or property of another is endangered is guilty of a misdemeanor.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 314; RL ï¿½ 6579; NCL ï¿½ 10262]—(NRS A1971,
1458;1979,
1480)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_475-020">
          <num>475.020</num>
          <heading>Willful or negligent leaving of fire burning or unexhausted in
campsite or in open; penalty.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Every
person who, upon departing from camp or from any fire started by the person in
the open, willfully or negligently leaves the fire or fires burning or
unexhausted, or fails to extinguish them thoroughly, is guilty of a
misdemeanor.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 367; RL ï¿½ 6632; NCL ï¿½ 10317]—(NRS A1971,
1458;1979,
1480)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_475-030">
          <num>475.030</num>
          <heading>Willful or negligent throwing or placing of burning cigarette or
other material; throwing burning cigarette or other material from moving
vehicle; penalty.</heading>
          <subsection eId="475-030__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is unlawful for any person willfully
or negligently:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="475-030__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>To throw or place any lighted cigarette,
cigar, ashes, match or other material which may cause a fire in any place where
such lighted cigarette, cigar, match, ashes or other material may start a fire.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="475-030__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>To throw or otherwise discard from a moving
vehicle any lighted cigarette, cigar, ash or other material which may cause a
fire.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="475-030__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person violating any of the
provisions of this section is guilty of a misdemeanor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1:134:1929; A1947,
458; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 10558]—(NRS A1967,
589;1971,
1458;1979,
1480)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_475-040">
          <num>475.040</num>
          <heading>Destruction of timber, crops or vegetation by fire caused by
gross negligence; criminal penalty; civil action.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Every
person who, with gross negligence, lights a fire for any purpose along the road
through any woodland, or upon the same, or at any other place in the open, and
thereby, or by any other means, sets fire to any growing timber or forest,
shrubbery, crops, grass or vegetation, and thereby causes the destruction of
any timber, forest, crops, grass, vegetation or property not his or her own, is
guilty of a public offense, as prescribed inNRS
193.155, proportionate to the value of the loss resulting therefrom, in
addition to being liable to the owner of such property for the full value
thereof in a civil action.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 368; RL ï¿½ 6633; NCL ï¿½ 10318]—(NRS A1967,
589;1979,
329)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_475-050">
          <num>475.050</num>
          <heading>Smoking in building on which notice posted prohibiting smoking;
penalty.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Every person who lights a
pipe, cigar or cigarette in, or who enters with a lighted pipe, cigar or
cigarette, any mill or other building on which is posted in a conspicuous place
over and near each principal entrance a notice in plain, legible characters
stating that no smoking is allowed in such building is guilty of a misdemeanor.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 313; RL ï¿½ 6578; NCL ï¿½ 10261]—(NRS A1971,
1459;1979,
1480)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_475-060">
          <num>475.060</num>
          <heading>Operation of internal combustion engine without spark arrestor;
penalty; exceptions.</heading>
          <subsection eId="475-060__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every person, firm, corporation or
association which uses or permits to be used any internal combustion engine
which is operated on hydrocarbon fuels on any grass, brush or forest-covered
land without providing, and maintaining in effective order, a spark arrestor
attached to the exhaust system is guilty of a misdemeanor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="475-060__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the purposes of this section, a
spark arrestor is a device constructed of nonflammable material specifically
for the purpose of removing or retaining carbon and other flammable materials
over 0.023 inch in size from the exhaust flow of an internal combustion engine
that is operated on hydrocarbon fuels.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="475-060__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Motortrucks, truck tractors, buses and
passenger vehicles, except motorcycles, are not subject to the provisions of
this section if the exhaust system is equipped with an adequate and properly
maintained muffler in constant operation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 315; RL ï¿½ 6580; NCL ï¿½ 10263]—(NRS A1967,
750;1971,
1459;1979,
1480)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_475-070">
          <num>475.070</num>
          <heading>Interference with peace officer, firefighter or member of search
and rescue organization; disobedience of orders; penalty.</heading>
          <subsection eId="475-070__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every person who, at any fire:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="475-070__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Disobeys the lawful order of any peace
officer or firefighter, or a member of a search and rescue organization who is
under the direction of the sheriff;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="475-070__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Resists or interferes with any lawful effort
to extinguish the fire; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="475-070__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Engages in any conduct likely to interfere
with the extinguishment of the fire,
ï¿½is guilty of
a misdemeanor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="475-070__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every person who, at the scene of an
emergency, other than a fire, disobeys any of the lawful orders of a peace
officer or firefighter, or a member of a search and rescue organization who is
under the direction of the sheriff, or resists or interferes with the lawful
efforts of any firefighters or company of firefighters, or members of a search
and rescue organization who are under the direction of the sheriff, to control
or handle the emergency, or acts in a disorderly manner likely to interfere
with the control or handling thereof, or who forbids, prevents or dissuades
others from assisting to control or handle the emergency, is guilty of a
misdemeanor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 312; RL ï¿½ 6577; NCL ï¿½ 10260]—(NRS A1971,
1459;1979,
1481;1987,
990;2005,
337)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_475-075">
          <num>475.075</num>
          <heading>Intentional prevention or obstruction of search and rescue
organization; penalty.</heading>
          <subsection eId="475-075__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who, with intent to prevent or
obstruct the response to an emergency, damages, removes or hinders the
operation of any vehicle, apparatus, equipment or animal being used or which may
be used in an emergency by a member of a search and rescue organization, is
guilty of a public offense, as prescribed inNRS
193.155, proportionate to the value of the loss resulting therefrom, but in
no event less than a misdemeanor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="475-075__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, ï¿½vehicleï¿½
means any device in, upon, or by which any person or property is or may be
transported.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1987,
989)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_475-080">
          <num>475.080</num>
          <heading>Intentional prevention or obstruction of extinguishment of fire;
penalties.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Every person who, with
intent to prevent or obstruct the extinguishment of any fire, cuts, damages or
removes any bell rope, wire or other apparatus for communicating an alarm of
fire, or cuts, injures or destroys any engine, hose or other fire apparatus, or
otherwise prevents or obstructs the extinguishment of any fire, is guilty of a
public offense, as prescribed inNRS 193.155,
proportionate to the value of the loss resulting therefrom and in no event less
than a misdemeanor.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 311; RL ï¿½ 6576; NCL ï¿½ 10259]—(NRS A1967,
589;1971,
1459;1979,
1481)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_475-090">
          <num>475.090</num>
          <heading>Willful and malicious removal, damage or destruction of fire
equipment or apparatus; penalty.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Every
person who willfully and maliciously removes, damages or destroys any engine,
hose, hose cart, truck, ladder, extinguisher or other apparatus used by any
fire company or fire department is guilty of a misdemeanor.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 487; RL ï¿½ 6752; NCL ï¿½
10434]—(NRS A1971,
1460;1979,
1481)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_475-100">
          <num>475.100</num>
          <heading>False fire alarms; penalties; exception.</heading>
          <subsection eId="475-100__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is unlawful for a person
intentionally to give or cause to be given, or turn in or cause to be turned
in, any false alarm of fire.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="475-100__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who violates any of the
provisions of this section shall be punished:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="475-100__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the act is malicious and another person
suffers death or substantial bodily harm as a result, for a category D felony
as provided inNRS 193.130.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="475-100__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Otherwise, for a gross misdemeanor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="475-100__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>This section does not apply to alarms
given for practice by any chief of a fire department or by any other person
properly authorized to give such alarms, nor to alarms given by a person to
attract attention of police, firefighters or other people to acts of violence,
disorder or menace.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 336; RL ï¿½ 6601; NCL ï¿½ 10284] + [1911
C&amp;P ï¿½ 337; RL ï¿½ 6602; NCL ï¿½ 10285]—(NRS A1967,
590;1971,
1460;1979,
1482;1987,
1476;1995,
1296;2005,
337)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_475-105">
          <num>475.105</num>
          <heading>Theft of device to prevent, control, extinguish or give warning
of fire; penalties.</heading>
          <subsection eId="475-105__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the device has a value of less than
$1,200, is guilty of a misdemeanor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="475-105__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the device has a value of $1,200 or
more, is guilty of a category D felony and shall be punished as provided inNRS 193.130.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1985,
751; A1989,
1441;1995,
1296;1997,
347;2011,
176;2019,
4478)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_475-110">
          <num>475.110</num>
          <heading>Able-bodied males subject to fire-fighting duty for certain period
during any 1 year; penalty for refusal; compensation and benefits.</heading>
          <subsection eId="475-110__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>All sheriffs, their deputies,
firewardens or other peace officers or any national forest officer may call
upon able-bodied male persons within the State of Nevada who are between the
ages of 16 years and 50 years for assistance in extinguishing fires in timber
or in brush.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="475-110__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Persons who refuse to obey the summons
or who refuse to assist in fighting fire for the period stated in subsection 3,
unless they present sufficient reasons, are guilty of a misdemeanor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="475-110__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>No male person may be required to fight
fires a total of more than 5 days during any 1 year.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="475-110__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The board of county commissioners may
fix the amount of compensation to be paid to male persons drafted to fight
fires as provided in this section, and the sums so fixed must be allowed and
paid as other claims against the county are paid.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="475-110__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the purpose of obtaining the
benefits of the Nevada Industrial Insurance Act, male persons drafted to fight
fires must be considered employees of the county demanding their services, and
they are entitled to receive for disability incurred by reason thereof the
benefits under the Nevada Industrial Insurance Act. The county shall report and
pay premiums to a private carrier authorized to provide industrial insurance in
this State for persons so engaged.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1:45:1927; NCL ï¿½ 1982] + [Part 2:45:1927; NCL ï¿½
1983]—(NRS A1967,
590;1981,
1528;1995,
2046;1999,
1826)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_475-115">
          <num>475.115</num>
          <heading>Volunteer firefighters: Discharge from employment prohibited;
civil action; attorneyï¿½s fees; disclosure to employer.</heading>
          <subsection eId="475-115__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person, corporation, partnership,
association or other entity who is an employer or is vested with the power to
discharge or recommend the discharge of a person who serves as a volunteer
firefighter shall not deprive the person performing such service of his or her
employment as a consequence of his or her action.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="475-115__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person discharged in violation of
subsection 1 may commence a civil action against his or her employer and
obtain:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="475-115__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Wages and benefits lost as a result of the
violation;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="475-115__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An order of reinstatement without loss of
position, seniority or benefits;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="475-115__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Damages equal to the amount of lost wages and
benefits; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="475-115__subsec_2__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Reasonable attorneyï¿½s fees fixed by the
court.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="475-115__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any applicant for employment who is,
and any employee who becomes, a volunteer firefighter must disclose that fact
to his or her prospective or present employer, as the case may be.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
919; A2005,
337)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_475-125">
          <num>475.125</num>
          <heading>Investigation of fires resulting in property damage, death or
injury.</heading>
          <subsection eId="475-125__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The cause, origin and circumstances of
each fire which occurs within its jurisdiction and which results in the
destruction of or damage to property, loss of life, or injury to any person.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="475-125__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any report received pursuant toNRS 629.045to determine the origin of the
fire which caused the injury.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1979,
171; A1991,
1897;2021,
1080)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_475-210">
          <num>475.210</num>
          <heading>Governor may close land or prohibit burning in areas which are
fire hazards.</heading>
          <subsection eId="475-210__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Whenever the Governor finds that
conditions of extreme fire hazard exist, either in or out of the fire hazard
season, the Governor may by proclamation close or partially close such land or
areas as the Governor may find to be in such condition of extreme hazard to the
general public and prohibit or limit burning and other acts thereon to such
degree and in such ways as he or she deems necessary to reduce the danger of
forest and other wild land fires.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="475-210__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Governor shall declare the end of
any such emergency only upon a finding that the conditions of extreme fire
hazard no longer exist.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1965,
306)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_475-220">
          <num>475.220</num>
          <heading>Dumps: Safe operation; regulations of State Forester Firewarden.</heading>
          <subsection eId="475-220__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any county, municipality, public
institution, agency, corporation, person or persons, or other entity
maintaining or operating a dump shall provide such devices and conditions
therefor as will reasonably promote the safe operation thereof and guard
against the escape of fire therefrom.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="475-220__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The State Forester Firewarden shall
have power to make rules and regulations for the implementation of this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1965,
306)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_475-230">
          <num>475.230</num>
          <heading>Claim by fire department to recover direct expenses and losses
incurred while fighting fire on property of State.</heading>
          <subsection eId="475-230__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any fire department which engages in
fighting a fire on property owned by the State within the jurisdictional limits
of the fire department may submit a claim to the State Board of Examiners to
recover any direct expenses and losses incurred as a result of fighting that
fire.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="475-230__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The claim must include:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="475-230__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The name, address and jurisdictional limits
of the fire department;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="475-230__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The name, address and telephone number of the
person making the claim on behalf of the fire department;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="475-230__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The name and address, if known, of the state
agency having jurisdiction over the property on which the fire occurred;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="475-230__subsec_2__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The exact location of the fire;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="475-230__subsec_2__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A description of the property burned;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="475-230__subsec_2__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The number and classification of the
personnel and the number and type of equipment used to fight the fire;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="475-230__subsec_2__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A copy of the fire report; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="475-230__subsec_2__subsec_h">
              <num>(h)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An itemized list of direct expenses and
losses incurred while fighting the fire, including the purchase cost, estimated
cost of repairs and a statement of depreciated value immediately preceding and
after the damage to or destruction of any equipment and the extent of any
insurance coverage.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="475-230__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, ï¿½direct
expenses and lossesï¿½ means certain expenses and losses which were incurred
while fighting a fire on property owned by the State. The term is limited to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="475-230__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The depreciated value, if any, of any
equipment or vehicle which was damaged or destroyed; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="475-230__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the employer maintains a plan which
supplements coverage for workersï¿½ compensation provided pursuant tochapters 616Ato616D,
inclusive, or chapter617of NRS by a private
carrier and, if the benefits are provided from public money and not by an
insurer, any injury or death benefits which would have been paid by the
employer from public money.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1979,
1165; A1981,
1528;1995,
2047;1999,
236,1826;2001,
1082)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_475-235">
          <num>475.235</num>
          <heading>Disposition of claims by State Board of Examiners.</heading>
          <subsection eId="475-235__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The State Board of Examiners may submit
a copy of the claim to the State Fire Marshal for review. The State Fire
Marshal shall make his or her recommendations to the State Board of Examiners
who shall make a final determination of the disposition of the claim.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="475-235__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>All claims approved by the State Board
of Examiners must be paid as other claims against the State are paid.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1979,
1166)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>