<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="NRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-171"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-171"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#nevada-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-nv"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="171"/>
          <FRBRname value="NRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-171/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-171/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-171/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-171/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="nevada-legislature" href="https://www.leg.state.nv.us" showAs="Nevada State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_171">
        <num>171</num>
        <heading>PROCEEDINGS TO COMMITMENT</heading>
        <section eId="sec_171-010">
          <num>171.010</num>
          <heading>Jurisdiction of offense committed in State.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Every person, whether an inhabitant of this
state, or any other state, or of a territory or district of the United States,
is liable to punishment by the laws of this state for a public offense
committed therein, except where it is by law cognizable exclusively in the
courts of the United States.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 Cr. Prac. ï¿½ 58; RL ï¿½ 6908; NCL ï¿½ 10705]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-015">
          <num>171.015</num>
          <heading>Jurisdiction of offense commenced without, but consummated
within, this State; consummation through agent.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>When
the commission of a public offense, commenced without the State, is consummated
within its boundaries, the defendant is liable to punishment therefor in this
State, though the defendant was out of the State at the time of the commission
of the offense charged. If the defendant consummated it in this State, through
the intervention of an innocent or guilty agent, or any other means proceeding
directly from the defendant, in such case the jurisdiction is in the county in
which the offense is consummated.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 Cr. Prac. ï¿½ 59; RL ï¿½ 6909; NCL ï¿½ 10706]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-020">
          <num>171.020</num>
          <heading>Act within this State culminating in crime in this or another
state.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever a person, with
intent to commit a crime, does any act within this State in execution or part
execution of such intent, which culminates in the commission of a crime, either
within or without this State, such person is punishable for such crime in this
State in the same manner as if the same had been committed entirely within this
State.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 Cr. Prac. ï¿½ 59a; added1927,
87; NCL ï¿½ 10707]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-025">
          <num>171.025</num>
          <heading>Death by dueling.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>When
an inhabitant or resident of this state, by previous appointment or engagement,
fights a duel or is concerned as second therein, out of the jurisdiction of
this state, and in the duel a wound is inflicted upon a person, whereof the
person dies in this state, the jurisdiction of the offense is in the county
where the death happens.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 Cr. Prac. ï¿½ 60; RL ï¿½ 6910; NCL ï¿½ 10708]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-030">
          <num>171.030</num>
          <heading>Offense committed partly in one county and partly in another.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>When a public offense is committed in part in
one county and in part in another or the acts or effects thereof constituting
or requisite to the consummation of the offense occur in two or more counties,
the venue is in either county.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 Cr. Prac. ï¿½ 61; RL ï¿½ 6911; NCL ï¿½ 10709]—(NRS A1963,
47)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-035">
          <num>171.035</num>
          <heading>Offense committed on or near boundary.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>When
an offense is committed on the boundary of two or more counties, or within 500
yards thereof, the venue is in either county.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 Cr. Prac. ï¿½ 62; RL ï¿½ 6912; NCL ï¿½ 10710]—(NRS A1963,
47)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-040">
          <num>171.040</num>
          <heading>Offense committed on vessel in state waters, common carrier or
private motor vehicle or aircraft.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-040__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>On board a vessel navigating a river,
slough, lake or canal, or lying therein, in the prosecution of a voyage, the
venue is in any county through which the vessel is navigated in the course of
the voyage, or in the county where the voyage terminates;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-040__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>On a railroad train, car, stage or
other public conveyance, or on a private motor vehicle, prosecuting its trip,
the venue is in any county through which the train, car, stage or other public
conveyance, or private motor vehicle, passes in the course of its trip, or in
the county where the trip terminates; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-040__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>On an aircraft prosecuting its trip,
the venue is in any county over which the aircraft passes in the course of its
trip, or in the county where the trip terminates. However, venue under this
subsection shall be only in a county over or into which the aircraft passes
prior to the first landing of such aircraft after the crime is discovered by or
reported to the person in charge of such aircraft.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 Cr. Prac. ï¿½ 63; RL ï¿½ 6913; NCL ï¿½ 10711]—(NRS A1959,
215;1963,
47)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-045">
          <num>171.045</num>
          <heading>Offenses concerning animals ranging in two or more counties.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>When a public offense concerns any neat
cattle, horse, mule or other animal running at large upon any range which
extends into more than one county of this state, such offense may be prosecuted
in either of the counties, and, upon the trial of any such offense, proof that
such animal is the property of the owner, or person occupying the range, and
was at the time the offense was committed running at large upon the range,
shall be prima facie evidence that the offense was committed within the
jurisdiction of the court.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 Cr. Prac. ï¿½ 64; RL ï¿½ 6914; NCL ï¿½ 10712]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-055">
          <num>171.055</num>
          <heading>Bigamy and incest.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>When
the offense, either of bigamy or incest, is committed in one county and the
defendant is apprehended in another, the venue is in either county.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 Cr. Prac. ï¿½ 66; RL ï¿½ 6916; NCL ï¿½ 10714]—(NRS A1963,
47)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-060">
          <num>171.060</num>
          <heading>Burglary, robbery, larceny or embezzlement: Venue when property
is taken in one county and brought into another.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>When
property taken in one county by burglary, robbery, larceny or embezzlement has
been brought into another, the venue of the offense is in either county, but
if, at any time before the conviction of the defendant in the latter, the
defendant is indicted in the former county, the sheriff of the latter county
must, upon demand, deliver the defendant to the sheriff of the former.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 Cr. Prac. ï¿½ 67; RL ï¿½ 6917; NCL ï¿½ 10715]—(NRS A1963,
47)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-065">
          <num>171.065</num>
          <heading>Accessory: Venue in either county where offense of accessory was
committed or where principal offense committed.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>In
the case of an accessory in the commission of a public offense, the venue is in
either the county where the offense of the accessory was committed, or where
the principal offense was committed.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 Cr. Prac. ï¿½ 68; RL ï¿½ 6918; NCL ï¿½ 10716]—(NRS A1963,
48)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-070">
          <num>171.070</num>
          <heading>Conviction or acquittal in another state or territory is bar
where jurisdiction is concurrent.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>When
an act charged as a public offense is within the jurisdiction of another state
or territory, as well as of this state, a conviction or acquittal thereof in
the former is a bar to the prosecution or indictment therefor in this state.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 Cr. Prac. ï¿½ 69; RL ï¿½ 6919; NCL ï¿½ 10717]—(NRS A2009,
2734)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-075">
          <num>171.075</num>
          <heading>Conviction or acquittal in another county is bar where venue is
concurrent.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>When an offense is
within the venue of two or more counties, a conviction or acquittal thereof in
one county is a bar to the prosecution or indictment therefor in another.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 Cr. Prac. ï¿½ 70; RL ï¿½ 6920; NCL ï¿½ 10718]—(NRS A1963,
48)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-076">
          <num>171.076</num>
          <heading>Enactment.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The
California-Nevada Compact for Jurisdiction on Interstate Waters, set forth in
full inNRS 171.077, is hereby enacted
into law.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1987,
309)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-077">
          <num>171.077</num>
          <heading>Text of Compact. [Effective until proclamation by the Governor
of this State of the enactment by the State of California of amendments that
are substantially similar to the Compact, as amended by section 2 of chapter
82,Statutes of Nevada 2019, at page 447.]</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-077__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Legislature finds that law
enforcement has been impaired in sections of Lake Tahoe and Topaz Lake forming
an interstate boundary between California and Nevada because of difficulty in
determining precisely where a criminal act was committed.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-077__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Legislature intends that a person
committing an act which is illegal in both states not be freed merely because
neither state could establish that a crime was committed within its boundaries.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-077__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The California-Nevada Compact for
Jurisdiction on Interstate Waters is enacted to provide for enforcement of the
laws of this state with regard to certain acts committed on Lake Tahoe or Topaz
Lake, on either side of the boundary line between California and Nevada.
ARTICLE
II—Definitions
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ As used in this compact, unless the context otherwise
requires, ï¿½party stateï¿½ means a state which has enacted this compact.
ARTICLE
III—Concurrent Jurisdiction
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-077__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If conduct is prohibited by the party
states, courts and law enforcement officers in either state who have
jurisdiction over criminal offenses committed in a county where Lake Tahoe or
Topaz Lake forms a common interstate boundary have concurrent jurisdiction to
arrest, prosecute and try offenders for the prohibited conduct committed
anywhere on the body of water forming a boundary between the two states.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-077__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>This compact does not authorize:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-077__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Prosecution of any person for conduct which
is lawful in the state where it was committed.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-077__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any conduct prohibited by a party state.
ARTICLE
IV—Ratification
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ This compact is ratified by enactment of the language
of this compact, or substantially similar language expressing the same purpose,
by the State of California and the State of Nevada.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1987,
309)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-078">
          <num>171.078</num>
          <heading>Enactment.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The
Interstate Compact for Jurisdiction on the Colorado River, set forth in full inNRS 171.079, is hereby enacted into law.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1987,
378)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-079">
          <num>171.079</num>
          <heading>Text of Compact.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-079__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Legislature finds that law
enforcement has been impaired in sections of the Colorado River forming an
interstate boundary because of difficulty in determining precisely where a criminal
act was committed.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-079__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Legislature intends that a person
committing an act which is illegal in both states not be freed merely because
neither state could establish that a crime was committed within its boundaries.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-079__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Interstate Compact for Jurisdiction
on the Colorado River is enacted to provide for enforcement of the laws of this
State with regard to certain acts committed on the Colorado River, or any lake
formed by or a part of the Colorado River, on either side of the boundary line with
an adjoining state.
ARTICLE
II—Definitions
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ As used in this Compact, unless the context otherwise
requires, ï¿½party stateï¿½ means a state which has enacted this Compact.
ARTICLE
III—Concurrent Jurisdiction
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-079__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If conduct is prohibited by two
adjoining party states, courts and law enforcement officers in either state who
have jurisdiction over criminal offenses committed in a county where the
Colorado River, or any lake formed by or a part of the Colorado River, forms a
common interstate boundary have concurrent jurisdiction to arrest, prosecute
and try offenders for the prohibited conduct committed anywhere on the body of
water forming a boundary between the two states and concurrent jurisdiction to
arrest offenders for the prohibited conduct committed on any land mass within 5
air miles of the Colorado River or any lake formed by or a part of the Colorado
River.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-079__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>This Compact does not authorize:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-079__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Prosecution of any person for conduct which
is lawful in the state where it was committed.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-079__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any conduct prohibited by a party state.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-079__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any claim, including a counterclaim
or cross-claim, is brought in a civil action which is filed in a party state
and which is:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-079__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Brought against a present or former officer
or employee of another party state or an agency or political subdivision of
that other party state; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-079__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Based on any alleged act or omission that is
related to his or her official duties or employment and conducted under the
authority of this Compact,
ï¿½the claim is
subject to the conditions and limitations on civil actions, including, without
limitation, the provisions regarding sovereign immunity, established by the
party state in which that officer or employee is or was an officer or employee.
ARTICLE
IV—Ratification
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ This Compact is ratified by enactment of the language
of this Compact, or substantially similar language expressing the same purpose,
by at least two states of which the Colorado River forms a common boundary.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1987,
378; A2005,
303)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-080">
          <num>171.080</num>
          <heading>No statute of limitation for murder, sexual assault arising out
of same facts and circumstances as murder or terrorism.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-080__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Murder, or a sexual assault arising out
of the same facts and circumstances as a murder, must be commenced. It may be
commenced at any time after the death of the person killed.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-080__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A violation ofNRS 202.445must be commenced. It may be
commenced at any time after the violation is committed.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 Cr. Prac. ï¿½ 71; RL ï¿½ 6921; NCL ï¿½ 10719]—(NRS A2003,
2952;2019,
464)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-082">
          <num>171.082</num>
          <heading>No limitation for sexual assault if identity of accused person
is established by conducting genetic marker analysis of biological specimen and
obtaining DNA profile.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-082__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the identity of a person who is
accused of committing a sexual assault is established by conducting a genetic
marker analysis of a biological specimen and obtaining a DNA profile, the
period of limitation prescribed inNRS
171.085is removed and there is no limitation of the time within which a
prosecution for the sexual assault must be commenced.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-082__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-082__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Biological specimenï¿½ has the meaning
ascribed to it inNRS 176.09112.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-082__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½DNA profileï¿½ has the meaning ascribed to it
inNRS 176.09115.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-082__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Genetic marker analysisï¿½ has the meaning
ascribed to it inNRS 176.09118.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2019,
1498)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-083">
          <num>171.083</num>
          <heading>No limitation for sexual assault or sex trafficking if written
report filed with law enforcement officer during period of limitation; effect
of disability on period of limitation.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-083__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided inNRS 171.080, if, at any time during the
period of limitation prescribed inNRS
171.085and171.095, a victim of a
sexual assault, a person authorized to act on behalf of a victim of a sexual
assault, or a victim of sex trafficking or a person authorized to act on behalf
of a victim of sex trafficking, files with a law enforcement officer a written
report concerning the sexual assault or sex trafficking, the period of
limitation prescribed inNRS 171.085and171.095is removed and there is no
limitation of the time within which a prosecution for the sexual assault or sex
trafficking must be commenced.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-083__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a written report is filed with a law
enforcement officer pursuant to subsection 1, the law enforcement officer shall
provide a copy of the written report to the victim or the person authorized to
act on behalf of the victim.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-083__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a victim of a sexual assault or sex
trafficking is under a disability during any part of the period of limitation
prescribed inNRS 171.085and171.095and a written report concerning the
sexual assault or sex trafficking is not otherwise filed pursuant to subsection
1, the period during which the victim is under the disability must be excluded
from any calculation of the period of limitation prescribed inNRS 171.085and171.095.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-083__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the purposes of this section, a
victim of a sexual assault or sex trafficking is under a disability if the
victim is insane, intellectually disabled, mentally incompetent or in a
medically comatose or vegetative state.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-083__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, ï¿½law
enforcement officerï¿½ means:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-083__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A prosecuting attorney;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-083__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A sheriff of a county or the sheriffï¿½s
deputy;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-083__subsec_5__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An officer of a metropolitan police
department or a police department of an incorporated city; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-083__subsec_5__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any other person upon whom some or all of the
powers of a peace officer are conferred pursuant toNRS 289.150to289.360, inclusive.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1997,
890; A2013,
683,2418;2019,
464)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-084">
          <num>171.084</num>
          <heading>Limitation for kidnapping or attempted murder extended if
written report filed with law enforcement officer during period of limitation.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-084__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If, at any time during the period of
limitation prescribed inNRS 171.085and171.095, a victim of kidnapping or
attempted murder, or a person authorized to act on behalf of such a victim,
files with a law enforcement officer a written report concerning the offense,
the period of limitation prescribed inNRS
171.085and171.095is extended for
5 years.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-084__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a written report is filed with a law
enforcement officer pursuant to subsection 1, the law enforcement officer shall
provide a copy of the written report to the victim or the person authorized to
act on behalf of the victim.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-084__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, ï¿½law
enforcement officerï¿½ has the meaning ascribed to it inNRS 171.083.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2001,
3031)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-085">
          <num>171.085</num>
          <heading>Limitations for felonies.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-085__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Theft, robbery, burglary, forgery,
arson, a violation ofNRS 90.570, a
violation punishable pursuant to paragraphs</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-085__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>to</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-085__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>, inclusive, of
subsection 3 ofNRS 598.0999or a
violation ofNRS 205.377must be found,
or an information or complaint filed, within 4 years after the commission of
the offense.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-085__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Sexual assault must be found, or an
information or complaint filed, within 20 years after the commission of the
offense.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-085__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Sex trafficking must be found, or an
information or complaint filed, within 6 years after the commission of the
offense.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-085__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any felony other than the felonies
listed in subsections 1, 2 and 3 must be found, or an information or complaint
filed, within 3 years after the commission of the offense.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 Cr. Prac. ï¿½ 72; RL ï¿½ 6922; NCL ï¿½ 10720]—(NRS A1963,
371;1977,
1630;1985,
2167;1997,
890;2001,
3031;2003,
20th Special Session, 273;2005,
1426;2009,
146;2013,
2418;2015,
583;2019,
1498;2021,
834;2023,
1194)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-090">
          <num>171.090</num>
          <heading>Limitations for gross and simple misdemeanors.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-090__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A gross misdemeanor must be found, or
an information or complaint filed, within 2 years after the commission of the
offense.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-090__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any other misdemeanor must be found, or
an information or complaint filed, within 1 year after the commission of the
offense.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 Cr. Prac. ï¿½ 73; RL ï¿½ 6923; NCL ï¿½ 10721]—(NRS A1981,
771;1985,
2167;1999,
3525;2005,
1209)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-095">
          <num>171.095</num>
          <heading>Limitations for offenses committed in secret manner, offenses
constituting sexual abuse or sex trafficking of child and offenses regarding
personal identifying information.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-095__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 2 andNRS 171.082,171.083and171.084:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-095__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If a felony, gross misdemeanor or misdemeanor
is committed in a secret manner, an indictment for the offense must be found,
or an information or complaint filed, within the periods of limitation
prescribed inNRS 171.085,171.090and624.800after the discovery of the offense,
unless a longer period is allowed by paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-095__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-095__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>or the provisions ofNRS 202.885.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-095__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An indictment must be found, or an
information or complaint filed, for any offense constituting sexual abuse of a
child as defined inNRS 432B.100or
sex trafficking of a child as defined inNRS
201.300, before the victim is:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="171-095__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Thirty-six years old if the victim
discovers or reasonably should have discovered that he or she was a victim of
the sexual abuse or sex trafficking by the date on which the victim reaches
that age; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-095__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Forty-three years old if the victim
does not discover and reasonably should not have discovered that he or she was
a victim of the sexual abuse or sex trafficking by the date on which the victim
reaches 36 years of age.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-095__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If a felony is committed pursuant toNRS 205.461to205.4657, inclusive, against a victim who
is less than 18 years of age at the time of the commission of the offense, an
indictment for the offense must be found, or an information or complaint filed,
within 4 years after the victim discovers or reasonably should have discovered
the offense.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-095__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any indictment found, or an
information or complaint filed, within the time prescribed in subsection 1 is
defective so that no judgment can be given thereon, another prosecution may be
instituted for the same offense within 6 months after the first is abandoned.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 Cr. Prac. ï¿½ 74; RL ï¿½ 6924; NCL ï¿½ 10722]—(NRS A1981,
771;1985,
2167;1989,
1443;1993,
305;1997,
891;1999,
3525;2001,
3031;2005,
1209;2011,
131;2013,
247,2419;2019,
1499)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-100">
          <num>171.100</num>
          <heading>Indictment found when it is presented and filed.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>An indictment is found, within the meaning of
this chapter, when it is presented by the grand jury in open court, and there
received and filed.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 Cr. Prac. ï¿½ 75; RL ï¿½ 6925; NCL ï¿½ 10723]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-101">
          <num>171.101</num>
          <heading>ï¿½No-knock warrantï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-101__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Knocking on the door or ringing the
doorbell and identifying the presence of the peace officer; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-101__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Identifying the presence of the peace
officer and stating the intended purpose of the peace officer for entering the
premises.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2021,
192)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-102">
          <num>171.102</num>
          <heading>Complaint defined; oath or declaration required.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-102__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Oath before a magistrate or a notary
public; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-102__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Declaration which is made subject to
the penalty for perjury.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1400; A1969,
387;1983,
446)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-103">
          <num>171.103</num>
          <heading>Court clerk may accept complaint filed electronically;
procedure; service.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-103__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A court clerk may accept a complaint
filed pursuant to this chapter that is filed electronically. A complaint that
is filed electronically must contain an image of the signature of the
prosecuting attorney.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-103__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a court clerk accepts a complaint
that is filed electronically pursuant to subsection 1, the court clerk shall
acknowledge receipt of the complaint by an electronic time stamp and shall
electronically return the complaint with the electronic time stamp to the
prosecuting attorney. A complaint that is filed and time-stamped electronically
pursuant to this section may be converted into a printed document and served
upon a defendant in the same manner as a complaint that is not filed
electronically.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1997,
892)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-104">
          <num>171.104</num>
          <heading>Arrest defined; by whom made.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>An
arrest is the taking of a person into custody, in a case and in the manner
authorized by law. An arrest may be made by a peace officer or by a private
person.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1400)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-106">
          <num>171.106</num>
          <heading>Issuance of warrant or summons upon application, complaint or
citation; no-knock warrants.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-106__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If it appears from an affidavit or
affidavits filed with an application for a warrant that there is probable cause
to believe that an offense, triable within the county, has been committed and
that the defendant has committed it, a warrant for the arrest of the defendant
must be issued by the magistrate to any peace officer. Upon the request of the
district attorney, a summons instead of a warrant must be issued.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-106__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If it appears from an affidavit or
affidavits filed with a complaint or citation issued pursuant toNRS 484A.730,488.920or501.386that there is probable cause to
believe that an offense, triable within the county, has been committed and that
the defendant has committed it, the magistrate may issue to any peace officer:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-106__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A warrant; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-106__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A summons.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-106__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A magistrate may not issue a warrant
that is a no-knock warrant pursuant to subsection 1 or 2 unless an affidavit
filed with the application, complaint or citation, as applicable:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-106__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Demonstrates that:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="171-106__subsec_3__subsec_a__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The underlying offense:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (I) Is punishable as a felony; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (II) Involves a significant and
imminent threat to public safety; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-106__subsec_3__subsec_a__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Identifying the presence of the peace
officer before entering the premises is likely to create an imminent threat of
substantial bodily harm to the peace officer or another person;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-106__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Describes with specificity the factual
circumstances as to why there are no reasonable alternatives to effectuate the
arrest of the defendant other than in the manner prescribed by the no-knock
warrant;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-106__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>States whether the no-knock warrant can be
executed during the day and, if it cannot, describes with specificity the
factual circumstances that preclude the no-knock warrant from being executed
during the day; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-106__subsec_3__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Certifies that the no-knock warrant will be
executed under the guidance of a peace officer who is trained in the execution
of warrants.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-106__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>More than one warrant or summons may be
issued on the same application, complaint or citation.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-106__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a defendant fails to appear in response
to a summons, a warrant must be issued for the arrest of the defendant.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-106__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A no-knock warrant issued pursuant to
subsection 3 is void if:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-106__subsec_6__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A peace officer deliberately misrepresents a
material fact or deliberately omits material information in an affidavit in
support of an application for the no-knock warrant; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-106__subsec_6__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the misrepresented material fact is
excluded or the omitted material information is included, the affidavit does
not meet the criteria set forth in paragraphs</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-106__subsec_6__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>to</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-106__subsec_6__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>, inclusive, of
subsection 3.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1400; A1971,
830;2021,
192)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-108">
          <num>171.108</num>
          <heading>Contents of warrant of arrest.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-108__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Be signed by the magistrate with the
magistrateï¿½s name of office;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-108__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Contain the name of the defendant or,
if the defendantï¿½s name is unknown, any name or description by which the
defendant can be identified with reasonable certainty;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-108__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>State the date of its issuance, and the
county, city or town where it was issued;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-108__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>State the offense described inNRS 171.106;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-108__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Command that the defendant be arrested
and brought before the nearest available magistrate; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-108__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>State whether the warrant is a no-knock
warrant.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1400; A2021,
193)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-112">
          <num>171.112</num>
          <heading>Contents of summons.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-112__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A summons is an order in writing in the
name of the State of Nevada which must:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-112__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Include the information described in
subsections 1 to 4, inclusive, ofNRS
171.108; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-112__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Summon the defendant to appear before a
magistrate at a stated time and place.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-112__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon a complaint against a corporation,
the magistrate must issue a summons, signed by the magistrate, with the
magistrateï¿½s name of office, requiring the corporation to appear before the
magistrate at a specified time and place to answer the charge, the time to be
not less than 10 days after the issuing of the summons.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1400; A2021,
193)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-114">
          <num>171.114</num>
          <heading>Execution of warrant and service of summons: By whom.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The warrant shall be directed to and executed
by a peace officer. The summons may be served by any person authorized to serve
a summons in a civil action.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1401)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-116">
          <num>171.116</num>
          <heading>When magistrate may depute person to act as constable.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>A magistrate may depute in writing any
suitable and discreet person to act as constable when no constable is at hand
and the nature of the business requires immediate action.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1401)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-118">
          <num>171.118</num>
          <heading>Execution of warrant and service of summons: Territorial limits.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The warrant may be executed or the summons may
be served at any place within the jurisdiction of the State of Nevada.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1401)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-122">
          <num>171.122</num>
          <heading>Manner in which execution of warrant and service of summons are
made; additional requirements for execution of no-knock warrant; issuance of
citation in lieu of execution of warrant of arrest.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-122__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 3, the warrant must be executed by the arrest of the defendant. The
peace officer need not have the warrant in the peace officerï¿½s possession at
the time of the arrest, but upon request the peace officer must show the
warrant to the defendant as soon as possible. If the peace officer does not
have a warrant in the peace officerï¿½s possession at the time of the arrest, the
peace officer shall then inform the defendant of the peace officerï¿½s intention
to arrest the defendant, of the offense charged, the authority to make it and
of the fact that a warrant has or has not been issued. The defendant must not
be subjected to any more restraint than is necessary for the defendantï¿½s arrest
and detention. If the defendant either flees or forcibly resists, the peace
officer may use only the amount of reasonable force necessary to effect the
arrest as provided inNRS 171.1455and193.305.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-122__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In addition to the requirements
described in subsection 1, if the warrant is a no-knock warrant, the peace
officers involved in the execution of the no-knock warrant shall:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-122__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Before executing the no-knock warrant,
determine whether the circumstances necessitate that the arrest of the
defendant be effectuated in the manner prescribed by the no-knock warrant and,
if they do not, the peace officers shall not effectuate the arrest of the
defendant in such a manner; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-122__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In executing the no-knock warrant:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="171-122__subsec_2__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Wear prominent insignia that renders
the peace officers readily identifiable as peace officers;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-122__subsec_2__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Wear a portable event recording device
in accordance with the requirements described inNRS 289.830;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-122__subsec_2__subsec_b__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Use only the amount of force
reasonably necessary to enter the premises; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-122__subsec_2__subsec_b__subsec_4">
                <num>(4)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>As soon as practicable after entering
the premises, identify the presence of the peace officers and state the purpose
of the peace officers for entering the premises.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-122__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In lieu of executing a warrant by
arresting the defendant, a peace officer may issue a citation as provided inNRS 171.1773if:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-122__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The warrant is issued upon an offense
punishable as a misdemeanor;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-122__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The peace officer has no indication that the
defendant has previously failed to appear on the charge reflected in the
warrant;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-122__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The defendant provides satisfactory evidence
of his or her identity to the peace officer;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-122__subsec_3__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The defendant signs a written promise to
appear in court for the misdemeanor offense; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-122__subsec_3__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The peace officer has reasonable grounds to
believe that the defendant will keep a written promise to appear in court.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-122__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A summons must be served upon a
defendant by delivering a copy to the defendant personally, or by leaving it at
the defendantï¿½s dwelling house or usual place of abode with some person then
residing in the house or abode who is at least 16 years of age and is of
suitable discretion, or by mailing it to the defendantï¿½s last known address. In
the case of a corporation, the summons must be served at least 5 days before
the day of appearance fixed in the summons, by delivering a copy to an officer
or to a managing or general agent or to any other agent authorized by
appointment or by law to receive service of process and, if the agent is one
authorized by statute to receive service and the statute so requires, by also
mailing a copy to the corporationï¿½s last known address within the State of
Nevada or at its principal place of business elsewhere in the United States.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1401; A1985,
618;1993,
143,931,932;2020,
32nd Special Session, 69;2021,
194,2636)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1223">
          <num>171.1223</num>
          <heading>Peace officer with limited jurisdiction must notify primary law
enforcement agency of commission of certain felonies; transfer of investigation
to primary law enforcement agency.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1223__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 3, in a county whose population is 100,000 or more, a peace officer
with limited jurisdiction who witnesses a category A felony being committed or
attempted in the officerï¿½s presence, or has reasonable cause for believing a
person has committed or attempted to commit a category A felony in an area that
is within the officerï¿½s jurisdiction, shall immediately notify the primary law
enforcement agency in the city or county, as appropriate, where the offense or
attempted offense was committed.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1223__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon arrival of an officer from the
primary law enforcement agency notified pursuant to subsection 1, a peace
officer with limited jurisdiction shall immediately transfer the investigation
of the offense or attempted offense to the primary law enforcement agency.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1223__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of subsection 1 do not:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1223__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Apply to an offense or attempted offense that
is a misdemeanor, gross misdemeanor or felony other than a category A felony;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1223__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Apply to an officer of the Nevada Highway
Patrol, a member of the police department of the Nevada System of Higher
Education, an agent of the Investigation Division of the Department of Public
Safety or a ranger of the Division of State Parks of the State Department of
Conservation and Natural Resources;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1223__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Apply to a peace officer with limited
jurisdiction if an interlocal agreement between the officerï¿½s employer and the
primary law enforcement agency in the city or county in which a category A
felony was committed or attempted authorizes the peace officer with limited jurisdiction
to respond to and investigate the felony without immediately notifying the
primary law enforcement agency; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1223__subsec_3__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Prohibit a peace officer with limited
jurisdiction from:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1223__subsec_3__subsec_d__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Contacting a primary law enforcement
agency for assistance with an offense that is a misdemeanor, gross misdemeanor
or felony that is not a category A felony; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1223__subsec_3__subsec_d__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Responding to a category A felony
until the appropriate primary law enforcement agency arrives at the location
where the felony was allegedly committed or attempted, including, without
limitation, taking any appropriate action to provide assistance to a victim of
the felony, to apprehend the person suspected of committing or attempting to
commit the felony, to secure the location where the felony was allegedly
committed or attempted and to protect the life and safety of the peace officer
and any other person present at that location.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1223__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1223__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Peace officer with limited jurisdictionï¿½
means:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1223__subsec_4__subsec_a__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A school police officer who is
appointed or employed pursuant to subsection 5 ofNRS 391.281;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1223__subsec_4__subsec_a__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>An airport guard or police officer who
is appointed pursuant toNRS 496.130;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1223__subsec_4__subsec_a__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A person employed to provide police
services for an airport authority created by a special act of the Legislature;
and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1223__subsec_4__subsec_a__subsec_4">
                <num>(4)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A marshal or park ranger who is part
of a unit of specialized law enforcement established pursuant toNRS 280.125.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1223__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Primary law enforcement agencyï¿½ means:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1223__subsec_4__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A police department of an incorporated
city;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1223__subsec_4__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The sheriffï¿½s office of a county; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1223__subsec_4__subsec_b__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If the county is within the
jurisdiction of a metropolitan police department, the metropolitan police
department.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2001,
1868; A2003,
102;2015,
3834;2017,
2061,3158)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1225">
          <num>171.1225</num>
          <heading>Peace officer to provide information to suspected victims of
domestic violence.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1225__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When investigating an act of domestic
violence, a peace officer shall:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1225__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Make a good faith effort to explain the
provisions ofNRS 171.137pertaining to
domestic violence and advise victims of all reasonable means to prevent further
abuse, including advising each person of the availability of a shelter or other
services in the community.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1225__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Provide a person suspected of being the
victim of an act of domestic violence with a written copy of the following
statements:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1225__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>My name is Officer
......................... (naming the investigating officer). Nevada law
requires me to inform you of the following information.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1225__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If I have probable cause to believe
that a battery has been committed against you, your minor child or the minor
child of the person believed to have committed the battery in the last 24 hours
by your spouse, your former spouse, any other person to whom you are related by
blood or marriage, a person with whom you have had or are having a dating
relationship or a person with whom you have a child in common, and if I had a
face-to-face encounter with the person suspected of committing the battery that
was of sufficient duration to determine whether probable cause existed while
responding to the initial incident or call for service, I am required, unless
mitigating circumstances exist, to arrest the person suspected of committing
the battery.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1225__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If I have probable cause to believe
that a battery has been committed against you, your minor child or the minor
child of the person believed to have committed the battery in the last 7 days
by your spouse, your former spouse, any other person to whom you are related by
blood or marriage, a person with whom you have had or are having a dating
relationship or a person with whom you have a child in common, and if I did not
have a face-to-face encounter with the person suspected of committing the
battery that was of sufficient duration to determine whether probable cause
existed while responding to the initial incident or call for service, I am
required, unless mitigating circumstances exist, to arrest the person suspected
of committing the battery.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1225__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_4">
                <num>(4)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If I am unable to arrest the person
suspected of committing the battery, you have the right to request that the
prosecutor file a criminal complaint against the person. I can provide you with
information on this procedure. If convicted, the person who committed the
battery may be placed on probation, ordered to see a counselor, put in jail or
fined.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1225__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_5">
                <num>(5)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The law provides that you may seek a
court order for the protection of you, your minor children or any animal that
is owned or kept by you, by the person who committed or threatened the act of
domestic violence or by the minor child of either such person against further
threats or acts of domestic violence. You do not need to hire a lawyer to
obtain such an order for protection.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1225__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_6">
                <num>(6)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>An order for protection may require
the person who committed or threatened the act of domestic violence against you
to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (I) Stop threatening, harassing or
injuring you or your children;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (II) Move out of your residence;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (III) Stay away from your place of
employment;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (IV) Stay away from the school
attended by your children;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (V) Stay away from any place you or
your children regularly go;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (VI) Avoid or limit all
communication with you or your children;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (VII) Stop physically injuring,
threatening to injure or taking possession of any animal that is owned or kept
by you or your children, either directly or through an agent; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (VIII) Stop physically injuring or
threatening to injure any animal that is owned or kept by the person who
committed or threatened the act or his or her children, either directly or through
an agent.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1225__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_7">
                <num>(7)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A court may make future orders for
protection which award you custody of your children and require the person who
committed or threatened the act of domestic violence against you to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (I) Pay the rent or mortgage due on
the place in which you live;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (II) Pay the amount of money
necessary for the support of your children;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (III) Pay part or all of the costs
incurred by you in obtaining the order for protection; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (IV) Comply with the arrangements
specified for the possession and care of any animal owned or kept by you or
your children or by the person who committed or threatened the act or his or
her children.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1225__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_8">
                <num>(8)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>To get an order for protection, go to
room number ....... (state the room number of the office at the court) at the
court, which is located at ......................... (state the address of the
court). Ask the clerk of the court to provide you with the forms for an order
of protection.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1225__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_9">
                <num>(9)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If the person who committed or
threatened the act of domestic violence against you violates the terms of an
order for protection, the person may be arrested and, if:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (I) The arresting officer determines
that such a violation is accompanied by a direct or indirect threat of harm;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (II) The person has previously
violated a temporary or extended order for protection; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (III) At the time of the violation
or within 2 hours after the violation, the person has a concentration of
alcohol of 0.08 or more in the personï¿½s blood or breath or an amount of a
prohibited substance in the personï¿½s blood or urine, as applicable, that is
equal to or greater than the amount set forth in subsection 3 or 4 ofNRS 484C.110,
ï¿½the person
will not be admitted to bail sooner than 12 hours after arrest.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1225__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_10">
                <num>(10)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>You may obtain emergency assistance
or shelter by contacting your local program against domestic violence at
......................... (state name, address and telephone number of local
program) or you may call, without charge to you, the Statewide Program Against
Domestic Violence at ........................ (state toll-free telephone number
of Statewide Program).
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1225__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The failure of a peace officer to carry
out the requirements set forth in subsection 1 is not a defense in a criminal
prosecution for the commission of an act of domestic violence, nor may such an
omission be considered as negligence or as causation in any civil action
against the peace officer or the officerï¿½s employer.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1225__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1225__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Act of domestic violenceï¿½ means any of the
following acts committed by a person against his or her spouse, former spouse,
any other person to whom he or she is related by blood or marriage, a person
with whom he or she has had or is having a dating relationship, a person with
whom he or she has a child in common, the minor child of any of those persons
or his or her minor child:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1225__subsec_3__subsec_a__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A battery.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1225__subsec_3__subsec_a__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>An assault.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1225__subsec_3__subsec_a__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Compelling the other by force or
threat of force to perform an act from which he or she has the right to refrain
or to refrain from an act which he or she has the right to perform.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1225__subsec_3__subsec_a__subsec_4">
                <num>(4)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A sexual assault.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1225__subsec_3__subsec_a__subsec_5">
                <num>(5)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A knowing, purposeful or reckless
course of conduct intended to harass the other. Such conduct may include, but
is not limited to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (I) Stalking.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (II) Arson.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (III) Trespassing.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (IV) Larceny.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (V) Destruction of private property.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (VI) Carrying a concealed weapon
without a permit.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (VII) Injuring or killing an animal.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1225__subsec_3__subsec_a__subsec_6">
                <num>(6)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>False imprisonment.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1225__subsec_3__subsec_a__subsec_7">
                <num>(7)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Unlawful entry of the otherï¿½s
residence, or forcible entry against the otherï¿½s will if there is a reasonably
foreseeable risk of harm to the other from the entry.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1225__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Dating relationshipï¿½ means frequent,
intimate associations primarily characterized by the expectation of affectional
or sexual involvement. The term does not include a casual relationship or an
ordinary association between persons in a business or social context.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1989,
64; A1993,
2771;1995,
899;1997,
1800;2001,
1221;2007,
1015;2013,
40;2017,
316,3180;2023,
1601)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1227">
          <num>171.1227</num>
          <heading>Peace officer to submit written report concerning suspected acts
of domestic violence; information from reports to be aggregated and forwarded
to Central Repository; content of report.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1227__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a peace officer investigates an act
that constitutes domestic violence pursuant toNRS 33.018, the peace officer shall prepare
and submit a written report of the investigation to the peace officerï¿½s
supervisor or to another person designated by the peace officerï¿½s supervisor,
regardless of whether the peace officer makes an arrest.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1227__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the peace officer investigates a
mutual battery that constitutes domestic violence pursuant toNRS 33.018and finds that one of the
persons involved was the primary physical aggressor, the peace officer shall
include in the report:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1227__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The name of the person who was the primary
physical aggressor; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1227__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A description of the evidence which supports
the peace officerï¿½s finding.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1227__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the peace officer does not make an
arrest, the peace officer shall include in the report the reason the peace
officer did not do so.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1227__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The information contained in a report made
pursuant to subsections 1 and 2 must be:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1227__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Aggregated each month; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1227__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Forwarded by each jurisdiction to the Central
Repository for Nevada Records of Criminal History not later than the 15th day
of the following month.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1227__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Director of the Department of
Public Safety shall prescribe the form on which the information described in
subsection 4 must be reported to the Central Repository. In addition to the
information required pursuant to subsections 1 and 2, the form must also
require the inclusion of the following information from each report:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1227__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The gender, age and race of the persons
involved;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1227__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The relationship of the persons involved;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1227__subsec_5__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The date and time of day of the offense;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1227__subsec_5__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The number of children present, if any, at
the time of the offense;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1227__subsec_5__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Whether or not an order for protection
against domestic violence was in effect at the time of the offense;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1227__subsec_5__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Whether or not any weapons were used during
the commission of the offense;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1227__subsec_5__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Whether or not any person required medical
attention;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1227__subsec_5__subsec_h">
              <num>(h)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Whether or not any person was given a
domestic violence card that contains information about appropriate counseling
or other supportive services available in the community in which that person
resides;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1227__subsec_5__subsec_i">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Whether or not the primary physical
aggressor, if identified, was arrested and, if not, any mitigating
circumstances explaining why an arrest was not made; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1227__subsec_5__subsec_j">
              <num>(j)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Whether or not any other person was arrested.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1997,
1533; A2007,
2482)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1228">
          <num>171.1228</num>
          <heading>Investigation of alleged sexual offense: Alleged victim not
required to submit to polygraphic examination or other similar examination.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1228__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A law enforcement officer, prosecutor
or other employee of a governmental entity shall not, as a condition of
investigating an alleged sexual offense, request or require a victim of the
alleged sexual offense to take or submit to a polygraphic examination or other
similar examination that is used, or the results of which are used, for the
purpose of rendering a diagnostic opinion regarding the honesty or dishonesty
of a person.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1228__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, ï¿½sexual
offenseï¿½ has the meaning ascribed to it inNRS
179D.097.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2007,
95)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1229">
          <num>171.1229</num>
          <heading>Fingerprinting of persons detained and cited for committing
suspected acts of domestic violence; fingerprints to be forwarded to Central
Repository.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1229__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Detains a person for violating a
county, city or town ordinance or state law that:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1229__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Is punishable as a misdemeanor; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1229__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Constitutes domestic violence pursuant toNRS 33.018; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1229__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Issues the person a citation in lieu of
taking the person before a magistrate,
ï¿½the peace
officer shall, in the manner prescribed by the Director of the Department of
Public Safety, obtain a complete set of fingerprints of the person and forward
those fingerprints and the report that the peace officer is required to prepare
pursuant toNRS 171.1227to the Central
Repository for Nevada Records of Criminal History.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1997,
1533; A2017,
258)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-123">
          <num>171.123</num>
          <heading>Temporary detention by peace officer of person suspected of
crime or civil infraction or of violating conditions of parole or probation:
Limitations.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-123__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any peace officer may detain any person
whom the officer encounters under circumstances which reasonably indicate that
the person has committed, is committing or is about to commit a crime or civil
infraction.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-123__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any peace officer may detain any person
the officer encounters under circumstances which reasonably indicate that the
person has violated or is violating the conditions of the personï¿½s parole or
probation.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-123__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The officer may detain the person
pursuant to this section only to ascertain the personï¿½s identity and the
suspicious circumstances surrounding the personï¿½s presence abroad. Any person
so detained shall identify himself or herself, but may not be compelled to
answer any other inquiry of any peace officer.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-123__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person must not be detained longer
than is reasonably necessary to effect the purposes of this section, and in no
event longer than 60 minutes. The detention must not extend beyond the place or
the immediate vicinity of the place where the detention was first effected,
unless the person is arrested.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-123__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, ï¿½civil
infractionï¿½ has the meaning ascribed to it inNRS
481.015.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
535; A1973,
597;1975,
1200;1987,
1172;1995,
2068;2021,
3353)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1231">
          <num>171.1231</num>
          <heading>Arrest if probable cause appears.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>At
any time after the onset of the detention pursuant toNRS 171.123, the person so detained shall
be arrested if probable cause for an arrest appears. If, after inquiry into the
circumstances which prompted the detention, no probable cause for arrest
appears, such person shall be released.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
535)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1232">
          <num>171.1232</num>
          <heading>Search to ascertain presence of dangerous weapon; seizure of
weapon or evidence.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1232__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any peace officer reasonably
believes that any person whom the peace officer has detained or is about to
detain pursuant toNRS 171.123is armed
with a dangerous weapon and is a threat to the safety of the peace officer or
another, the peace officer may search such person to the extent reasonably
necessary to ascertain the presence of such weapon. If the search discloses a
weapon or any evidence of a crime, such weapon or evidence may be seized.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1232__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Nothing seized by a peace officer in
any such search is admissible in any proceeding unless the search which
disclosed the existence of such evidence is authorized by and conducted in
compliance with this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
535)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1233">
          <num>171.1233</num>
          <heading>Recording of law enforcement activity.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1233__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who is not under arrest or in
the custody of a peace officer may record a law enforcement activity and
maintain custody and control of that recording and any property or instruments
used by the person to record a law enforcement activity. A person who is under
arrest or in the custody of a peace officer does not, by that status alone,
forfeit the right to have any such recordings, property or instruments
maintained and returned to him or her. This subsection must not be construed to
authorize a person to engage in actions that interfere with or obstruct a law
enforcement activity or otherwise violate any other law in an effort to record
a law enforcement activity.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1233__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A peace officer shall not act to
interfere with a personï¿½s recording of a law enforcement activity, including,
without limitation, by:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1233__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Intentionally preventing or attempting to
prevent the person from recording a law enforcement activity;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1233__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Threatening the person for recording a law
enforcement activity;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1233__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Commanding that the person cease recording a
law enforcement activity when the person was nevertheless authorized by law to
record the law enforcement activity;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1233__subsec_2__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Stopping, seizing or searching the person
because he or she recorded a law enforcement activity; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1233__subsec_2__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Unlawfully seizing property or instruments
used by the person to record a law enforcement activity, unlawfully destroying
or seizing any recorded image of a law enforcement activity or copying such a
recording of a law enforcement activity without the consent of the person who
recorded it or obtaining approval from an appropriate court.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1233__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1233__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Law enforcement activityï¿½ means any activity
by a peace officer acting under the color of law.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1233__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Peace officerï¿½ means any person upon whom
some or all of the powers of a peace officer are conferred pursuant toNRS 289.150to289.360, inclusive.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1233__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Recordï¿½ means to capture or attempt to
capture any moving or still image, sound or impression through the use of any
recording device, camera or any other device capable of capturing audio or
moving or still images, or by means of written notes or observations. The term
includes, without limitation, the capturing of or the attempt to capture any
moving or still image, sound or impression through the use of any such device
for the purpose of broadcasting an event or occurrence in real time.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2020,
32nd Special Session, 68)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1235">
          <num>171.1235</num>
          <heading>Gaming licensee may detain person suspected of having committed
felony in gaming establishment.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1235__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1235__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Establishmentï¿½ means any premises whereon
any gaming is done or any premises owned or controlled by a licensee for the
purpose of parking motor vehicles owned or operated by patrons of such
licensee.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1235__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Licenseeï¿½ has the meaning ascribed to it inNRS 463.0171.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1235__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any licensee or the licenseeï¿½s
officers, employees or agents may take into custody and detain any person when
such licensee or the licenseeï¿½s officers, employees or agents have reasonable
cause to believe the person detained has committed a felony, whether or not in
the presence of such licensee or the licenseeï¿½s officers, employees or agents.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1235__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Detention pursuant to this section
shall be in the establishment, in a reasonable manner, for a reasonable length
of time and solely for the purpose of notifying a peace officer. Such taking
into custody and detention shall not render the licensee or the licenseeï¿½s
officers, employees or agents criminally or civilly liable for false arrest,
false imprisonment, slander or unlawful detention unless such taking into
custody and detention are unreasonable under all the circumstances.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1235__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>No licensee or the licenseeï¿½s officers,
employees or agents are entitled to the immunity from liability provided for in
this section unless there is displayed in a conspicuous place in the
establishment a notice in boldface type clearly legible and in substantially
this form:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ Any gaming licensee or the
licenseeï¿½s officers, employees or agents who have reasonable cause to believe
that any person has committed a felony may detain such person in the
establishment for the purpose of notifying a peace officer.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1973,
1700; A2003,
20th Special Session, 15)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1237">
          <num>171.1237</num>
          <heading>Identification of suspect by live lineup, photo lineup or
show-up: Law enforcement agencies to adopt policies and procedures governing
use.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1237__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each law enforcement agency shall adopt
policies and procedures governing the use of live lineups, photo lineups and
show-ups.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1237__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1237__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Live lineupï¿½ means an identification
procedure in which a group of persons, including the suspect, is displayed to
an eyewitness to determine whether the eyewitness identifies the suspect as the
perpetrator of a crime.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1237__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Photo lineupï¿½ means an identification
procedure in which an array of photographs, including a photograph of the
suspect, is displayed to an eyewitness in hard copy or by digital image to
determine whether the eyewitness identifies the suspect as the perpetrator of a
crime.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1237__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Show-upï¿½ means an identification procedure
in which the suspect appears individually for possible identification by the
eyewitness as the perpetrator of a crime.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2011,
325)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1239">
          <num>171.1239</num>
          <heading>Electronic recording of custodial interrogations conducted in
place of detention; adoption of policies by law enforcement agency.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1239__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each law enforcement agency in this
State shall adopt detailed, written policies regarding the electronic recording
of custodial interrogations that are conducted in a place of detention.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1239__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any policies adopted by a law
enforcement agency pursuant to this section must be made available:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1239__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>To all law enforcement officers employed by
the law enforcement agency; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1239__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For public inspection during normal business
hours.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1239__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any policies adopted by a law
enforcement agency pursuant to this section must include, without limitation:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1239__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A requirement that, except as otherwise
provided in any policy adopted pursuant to paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1239__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>, an electronic
recording must be made of an entire custodial interrogation which is conducted
in a place of detention if the person being interrogated is suspected of
committing homicide as described inNRS
200.010to200.260, inclusive, or
sexual assault as defined inNRS 200.366.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1239__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A requirement that, except as otherwise
provided in any policy adopted pursuant to paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1239__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>, if a person being
interrogated chooses to make or sign a written statement during the course of a
custodial interrogation concerning a homicide as described inNRS 200.010to200.260, inclusive, or sexual assault as
defined inNRS 200.366, the making and
signing of the statement must be electronically recorded.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1239__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The circumstances in which all or a portion
of a custodial interrogation is not required to be electronically recorded,
including, without limitation, when:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1239__subsec_3__subsec_c__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>An equipment malfunction prevents the
electronic recording of the custodial interrogation in its entirety and
replacement equipment is not immediately available.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1239__subsec_3__subsec_c__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The law enforcement officer conducting
the custodial interrogation fails, in good faith, to record the interrogation
because:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (I) He or she inadvertently fails to
operate the recording equipment properly; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (II) The recording equipment
malfunctions or stops recording without the law enforcement officerï¿½s
knowledge.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1239__subsec_3__subsec_c__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>More than one custodial interrogation
is being conducted simultaneously, thereby exceeding the available electronic
recording capacity of the recording equipment.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1239__subsec_3__subsec_c__subsec_4">
                <num>(4)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The person who is being or will be
interrogated:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (I) Affirmatively asserts his or her
desire to speak with law enforcement officers without being recorded;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (II) Makes a statement spontaneously
and not in response to a question asked during the custodial interrogation;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (III) Makes a statement during
routine questioning during the process of his or her arrest; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (IV) Makes a statement at a time
when the law enforcement officer conducting the interrogation is, in good
faith, unaware of the personï¿½s involvement in a homicide as described inNRS 200.010to200.060, inclusive, a sexual assault as
defined inNRS 200.366or an offense for
which a custodial interrogation is otherwise required to be electronically
recorded in accordance with the policies adopted pursuant to this section.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1239__subsec_3__subsec_c__subsec_5">
                <num>(5)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>At the time of the custodial
interrogation, the law enforcement officer conducting the interrogation is, in
good faith, unaware that the type of offense involved is a homicide as
described inNRS 200.010to200.060, inclusive, a sexual assault as
defined inNRS 200.366or an offense for
which a custodial interrogation is otherwise required to be electronically
recorded in accordance with the policies adopted pursuant to this section.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1239__subsec_3__subsec_c__subsec_6">
                <num>(6)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Exigent circumstances make recording
impractical.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1239__subsec_3__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Requirements pertaining to the retention and
storage of electronic recordings made pursuant to this section.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1239__subsec_3__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The circumstances in which all or a portion
of an electronic recording is not required to be retained, including, without
limitation, when the electronic recording is damaged or destroyed, without bad
faith on the part of any person or entity in control of the electronic
recording.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1239__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each law enforcement agency in this
State shall collaborate with the district attorney of the county in which the
law enforcement agency is located regarding the contents of the policies
required to be adopted pursuant to this section.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1239__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1239__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Custodial interrogationï¿½ means any
interrogation of a person who is required to be advised of his or her rights
pursuant toMiranda v. Arizona, 384 U.S. 436</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1239__subsec_5__subsec_a__subsec_1966">
                <num>(1966)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1239__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Electronic recordingï¿½ means an audio or
audiovisual recording.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1239__subsec_5__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Interrogationï¿½ means questioning which is
initiated by a law enforcement officer or any words or actions on the part of a
law enforcement officer, other than those which are ordinarily attendant to
arrest and custody, that the officer should know are reasonably likely to
elicit an incriminating response from the person who is being questioned.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1239__subsec_5__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Law enforcement agencyï¿½ means:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1239__subsec_5__subsec_d__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The sheriffï¿½s office of a county;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1239__subsec_5__subsec_d__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A metropolitan police department; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1239__subsec_5__subsec_d__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A police department of an incorporated
city.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1239__subsec_5__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Place of detentionï¿½ means a fixed location
under the control of a law enforcement agency of this State where persons are
questioned about alleged crimes.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2019,
794)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-124">
          <num>171.124</num>
          <heading>Arrest by peace officer or officer of Drug Enforcement
Administration.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-124__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 3 andNRS 33.070and33.320, a peace officer or an officer of
the Drug Enforcement Administration designated by the Attorney General of the
United States for that purpose may make an arrest in obedience to a warrant
delivered to him or her, or may, without a warrant, arrest a person:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-124__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For a public offense committed or attempted
in the officerï¿½s presence.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-124__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When a person arrested has committed a felony
or gross misdemeanor, although not in the officerï¿½s presence.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-124__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When a felony or gross misdemeanor has in
fact been committed, and the officer has reasonable cause for believing the
person arrested to have committed it.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-124__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>On a charge made, upon a reasonable cause, of
the commission of a felony or gross misdemeanor by the person arrested.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-124__subsec_1__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When a warrant has in fact been issued in
this State for the arrest of a named or described person for a public offense,
and the officer has reasonable cause to believe that the person arrested is the
person so named or described.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-124__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A peace officer or an officer of the
Drug Enforcement Administration designated by the Attorney General of the
United States for that purpose may also, at night, without a warrant, arrest
any person whom the officer has reasonable cause for believing to have
committed a felony or gross misdemeanor, and is justified in making the arrest,
though it afterward appears that a felony or gross misdemeanor has not been
committed.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-124__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An officer of the Drug Enforcement
Administration may only make an arrest pursuant to subsections 1 and 2 for a
violation ofchapter 453of NRS.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1401; A1975,
755;1979,
834;1983,
1651;1985,
1171,2022,2170;2001,
2850;2003,
888;2013,
2946;2015,
2521)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1245">
          <num>171.1245</num>
          <heading>Arrest by agent of Federal Bureau of Investigation or Secret
Service.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1245__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>For a public offense committed or
attempted in the agentï¿½s presence.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1245__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When a person arrested has committed a
felony or gross misdemeanor, although not in the agentï¿½s presence.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1245__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When a felony or gross misdemeanor has
in fact been committed, and the agent has reasonable cause for believing the
person arrested to have committed it.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1245__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>On a charge made, upon a reasonable
cause, of the commission of a felony or gross misdemeanor by the person
arrested.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1245__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When a warrant has in fact been issued
in this State for the arrest of a named or described person for a public
offense, and the agent has reasonable cause to believe that the person arrested
is the person so named or described.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1985,
451)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1255">
          <num>171.1255</num>
          <heading>Arrest by officer or agent of Bureau of Indian Affairs or police
officer employed by Indian tribe.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1255__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 2, an officer or agent of the Bureau of Indian Affairs or a person
employed as a police officer by an Indian tribe may make an arrest in obedience
to a warrant delivered to him or her, or may, without a warrant, arrest a
person:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1255__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For a public offense committed or attempted
in the officer or agentï¿½s presence.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1255__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When a person arrested has committed a felony
or gross misdemeanor, although not in the officer or agentï¿½s presence.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1255__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When a felony or gross misdemeanor has in
fact been committed, and the officer or agent has reasonable cause for
believing the person arrested to have committed it.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1255__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>On a charge made, upon a reasonable cause, of
the commission of a felony or gross misdemeanor by the person arrested.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1255__subsec_1__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When a warrant has in fact been issued in
this State for the arrest of a named or described person for a public offense,
and the officer or agent has reasonable cause to believe that the person
arrested is the person so named or described.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1255__subsec_1__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the peace officer has probable cause to
believe that the person to be arrested has committed a battery upon that
personï¿½s spouse and the peace officer finds evidence of bodily harm to the
spouse.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1255__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such an officer or agent may make an
arrest pursuant to subsection 1 only:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1255__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Within the boundaries of an Indian
reservation or Indian colony for an offense committed on that reservation or colony;
or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1255__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Outside the boundaries of an Indian
reservation or Indian colony if the officer or agent is:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1255__subsec_2__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Acting under an agreement pursuant to
subsection 3 ofNRS 289.152; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1255__subsec_2__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>In fresh pursuit of a person who is
reasonably believed by the officer or agent to have committed a felony within
the boundaries of the reservation or colony or has committed, or attempted to
commit, any criminal offense within those boundaries in the presence of the
officer or agent.
ï¿½For the
purposes of this subsection, ï¿½fresh pursuitï¿½ has the meaning ascribed to it inNRS 171.156.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1985,
452; A2019,
535)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1257">
          <num>171.1257</num>
          <heading>Arrest by postal inspector of United States Postal Inspection
Service.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1257__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A postal inspector of the United States
Postal Inspection Service may make an arrest in obedience to a warrant
delivered to him or her, or may, without a warrant, arrest a person:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1257__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For a public offense related to postal
matters committed or attempted in the postal inspectorï¿½s presence.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1257__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the person arrested has committed a
felony or gross misdemeanor related to postal matters, although not in the
postal inspectorï¿½s presence.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1257__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When a felony or gross misdemeanor related to
postal matters has in fact been committed, and the postal inspector has
reasonable cause for believing the person arrested to have committed it.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1257__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>On a charge made, upon a reasonable cause, of
the commission of a felony or gross misdemeanor related to postal matters by
the person arrested.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1257__subsec_1__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When a warrant has in fact been issued in
this State for the arrest of a named or described person for a public offense
related to postal matters, and the postal inspector has reasonable cause to
believe that the person arrested is the person so named or described.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1257__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, ï¿½postal
mattersï¿½ means any act related to mail service, including, without limitation,
delivering and collecting mail, mail theft and mail fraud.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2007,
2173)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-126">
          <num>171.126</num>
          <heading>Arrest by private person.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-126__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>For a public offense committed or
attempted in the personï¿½s presence.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-126__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When the person arrested has committed
a felony, although not in the personï¿½s presence.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-126__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When a felony has been in fact
committed, and the private person has reasonable cause for believing the person
arrested to have committed it.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1402)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-128">
          <num>171.128</num>
          <heading>Magistrate may order arrest for committing or attempting to
commit offense in magistrateï¿½s presence.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>A
magistrate may orally order a peace officer or private person to arrest anyone
committing or attempting to commit a public offense in the presence of the
magistrate, and may thereupon proceed as if the offender had been brought
before the magistrate on a warrant of arrest.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1402)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-132">
          <num>171.132</num>
          <heading>Person making arrest may summon assistance.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Any person making an arrest may orally summon
as many persons as the person making the arrest deems necessary to aid him or
her therein.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1402)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-134">
          <num>171.134</num>
          <heading>Escape or rescue of arrested person: Pursuit and retaking at any
time and place in State.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If a
person arrested escapes or is rescued, the person from whose custody he or she
escaped or was rescued may immediately pursue and retake the person at any time
and in any place within the State.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1402)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-136">
          <num>171.136</num>
          <heading>When arrest may be made.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-136__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the offense charged is a felony or
gross misdemeanor, the arrest may be made on any day, and at any time of day or
night.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-136__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If it is a misdemeanor, the arrest
cannot be made between the hours of 7 p.m. and 7 a.m., except:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-136__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Upon the direction of a magistrate, endorsed
upon the warrant;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-136__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the offense is committed in the presence
of the arresting officer;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-136__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the person is found and the arrest is
made in a public place or a place that is open to the public and:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="171-136__subsec_2__subsec_c__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>There is a warrant of arrest against
the person; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-136__subsec_2__subsec_c__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The misdemeanor is discovered because
there was probable cause for the arresting officer to stop, detain or arrest
the person for another alleged violation or offense;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-136__subsec_2__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the offense is committed in the presence
of a private person and the person makes an arrest immediately after the
offense is committed;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-136__subsec_2__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the arrest is made in the manner
provided inNRS 171.137or171.1375;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-136__subsec_2__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the person is already in custody as a
result of another lawful arrest; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-136__subsec_2__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When the person voluntarily surrenders
himself or herself in response to an outstanding warrant of arrest.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1402; A1977,
874;1985,
6,2023;1991,
331;1993,
119;2001,
1431;2017,
3182;2019,
1806,2857)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-137">
          <num>171.137</num>
          <heading>Arrest required for suspected battery constituting domestic
violence; exceptions.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-137__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 2, whether or not a warrant has been issued, a peace officer shall,
unless mitigating circumstances exist, arrest a person when the peace officer
has probable cause to believe that the person to be arrested has committed a
battery upon his or her spouse, former spouse, any other person to whom he or
she is related by blood or marriage, a person with whom he or she has had or is
having a dating relationship, a person with whom he or she has a child in
common, the minor child of any of those persons, his or her minor child or a
person who is the custodian or guardian of his or her minor child:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-137__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the peace officer had a face-to-face
encounter with the person to be arrested that was of sufficient duration to
determine whether probable cause existed while responding to the initial
incident or call for service, within the preceding 24 hours.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-137__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the peace officer did not have a
face-to-face encounter with the person to be arrested that was of sufficient
duration to determine whether probable cause existed while responding to the
initial incident or call for service, within the preceding 7 days.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-137__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the peace officer has probable cause
to believe that a battery described in subsection 1 was a mutual battery, the
peace officer shall attempt to determine which person was the primary physical
aggressor. If the peace officer determines that one of the persons who
allegedly committed a battery was the primary physical aggressor involved in
the incident, the peace officer is not required to arrest any other person
believed to have committed a battery during the incident. In determining
whether a person is a primary physical aggressor for the purposes of this
subsection, the peace officer shall consider:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-137__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Prior domestic violence involving either
person;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-137__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The relative severity of the injuries
inflicted upon the persons involved;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-137__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The potential for future injury;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-137__subsec_2__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Whether one of the alleged batteries was
committed in self-defense; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-137__subsec_2__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any other factor that may help the peace
officer decide which person was the primary physical aggressor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-137__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A peace officer shall not base a
decision regarding whether to arrest a person pursuant to this section on the
peace officerï¿½s perception of the willingness of a victim or a witness to the
incident to testify or otherwise participate in related judicial proceedings.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-137__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Nothing in this section shall be
construed to impose liability upon a peace officer or his or her employer for a
determination made in good faith by the peace officer not to arrest a person
pursuant to this section.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-137__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of this section do not
apply to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-137__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Siblings, except those siblings who are in a
custodial or guardianship relationship with each other; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-137__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Cousins, except those cousins who are in a
custodial or guardianship relationship with each other.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-137__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, ï¿½dating
relationshipï¿½ means frequent, intimate associations primarily characterized by
the expectation of affectional or sexual involvement. The term does not include
a casual relationship or an ordinary association between persons in a business
or social context.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1985,
2170; A1989,
23;1995,
901;1997,
1533,1802;1999,
486;2019,
1806;2023,
1604)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1375">
          <num>171.1375</num>
          <heading>Arrest of person suspected of battery upon certain persons.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1375__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Whether or not a warrant has been
issued, a peace officer may arrest a person if the peace officer:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1375__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Has probable cause to believe that the person
to be arrested has, within the preceding 24 hours, committed a battery upon:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1375__subsec_1__subsec_a__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A person with whom he or she is
actually residing;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1375__subsec_1__subsec_a__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A sibling, if the person is not the
custodian or guardian of the sibling; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1375__subsec_1__subsec_a__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A cousin, if the person is not the
custodian or guardian of the cousin; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1375__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Had a face-to-face encounter with the person
to be arrested that was of sufficient duration to determine whether probable
cause existed while responding to the initial incident or call for service.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1375__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Whether or not a warrant has been
issued, a peace officer may arrest a person if the peace officer:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1375__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Has probable cause to believe that the person
to be arrested has, within the immediately preceding 7 days, committed a
battery upon:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1375__subsec_2__subsec_a__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A person with whom he or she is
actually residing;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1375__subsec_2__subsec_a__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A sibling, if the person is not the
custodian or guardian of the sibling; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1375__subsec_2__subsec_a__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A cousin, if the person is not the
custodian or guardian of the cousin; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1375__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Did not have a face-to-face encounter with
the person to be arrested that was of sufficient duration to determine whether
probable cause existed while responding to the initial incident or call for
service.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1375__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Nothing in this section shall be
construed to impose liability upon a peace officer or his or her employer for a
determination made in good faith by the peace officer not to arrest a person
pursuant to this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2019,
1805; A2023,
1605)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-138">
          <num>171.138</num>
          <heading>Breaking open door or window: Making arrest.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>To make an arrest, a private person, if the
offense is a felony, and in all cases a peace officer, may break open a door or
window of the house, structure or other place of concealment in which the
person to be arrested is, or in which there is reasonable grounds for believing
the person to be, after having demanded admittance and explained the purpose
for which admittance is desired.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1402; A1983,
244)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-142">
          <num>171.142</num>
          <heading>Breaking open door or window: Upon detention after making
arrest.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Any person who has entered
a house, structure or other place of concealment to make an arrest may break
open a door or window if that is necessary to liberate himself or herself. An
officer may do the same to liberate a person who, acting in the officerï¿½s aid,
entered to make an arrest and is detained inside.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1402; A1983,
244)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-144">
          <num>171.144</num>
          <heading>Breaking open door or window: Retaking person arrested.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>To retake a person arrested who has escaped or
been rescued, the person pursuing may break open an outer or inner door or
window of a dwelling house, structure or other place of concealment, if, after
notice of his or her intention, the person pursuing is refused admittance.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1402)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1455">
          <num>171.1455</num>
          <heading>Use of deadly force to effect arrest: Limitations.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1455__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A peace officer shall use de-escalation
techniques and alternatives to the use of force whenever possible or
appropriate and consistent with his or her training, including, without
limitation, advisements, warnings, verbal persuasion and other tactics. If it
is necessary for the peace officer to use force, the peace officer must:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1455__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If it is possible to do so safely, identify
himself or herself as a peace officer through verbal commands, visual
identification, including, without limitation, a clearly marked uniform or
vehicle, or other reasonable means; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1455__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Use only the level of force that is objectively
reasonable under the circumstances to bring an incident or person under control
and safely accomplish a lawful purpose. The level of force used by the officer
must, to the extent feasible:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1455__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Be balanced against the level of force
or resistance exhibited by the person; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1455__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Be carefully controlled.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1455__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A peace officer may, after giving a
warning, if feasible, use deadly force to effect the arrest of a person only if
there is probable cause to believe that the person:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1455__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Has committed a felony which involves the
infliction or threat of serious bodily harm or the use of deadly force; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1455__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Poses an imminent threat of serious bodily
harm or death to the peace officer or to others.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1455__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each law enforcement agency shall adopt
a written policy and provide training to a peace officer regarding the
potential threat of serious bodily harm or death to the peace officer or others
from a person who:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1455__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Is known or reasonably believed not to be
armed with a deadly weapon; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1455__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Is known or reasonably believed by the peace
officer to be:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1455__subsec_3__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Under 13 years of age;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1455__subsec_3__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Over 70 years of age;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1455__subsec_3__subsec_b__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Physically frail;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1455__subsec_3__subsec_b__subsec_4">
                <num>(4)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Mentally or physically disabled;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1455__subsec_3__subsec_b__subsec_5">
                <num>(5)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Pregnant;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1455__subsec_3__subsec_b__subsec_6">
                <num>(6)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Suffering from a mental or behavioral
health issue; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1455__subsec_3__subsec_b__subsec_7">
                <num>(7)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Experiencing a medical emergency.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1455__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The written policy adopted and training
provided pursuant to subsection 3 must reflect the best practices with respect
to the use of force on the persons described in that subsection.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1455__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In addition to any other information
required pursuant to subsection 3, the written policy must include, without
limitation:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1455__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Guidelines for the use of force;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1455__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Guidelines for the use of deadly force;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1455__subsec_5__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A requirement that peace officers utilize
de-escalation techniques, crisis intervention and other alternatives to force
when feasible;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1455__subsec_5__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A requirement that peace officers utilize
de-escalation techniques for responding to persons with mental illness or
experiencing a behavioral health crisis;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1455__subsec_5__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A requirement that the law enforcement
agency, when feasible, send a peace officer who has been trained in crisis
intervention to respond to an incident involving a person who has made suicidal
statements;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1455__subsec_5__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Factors for evaluating and reviewing all
incidents which require the use of force; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1455__subsec_5__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The date on which the written policy was
adopted by the law enforcement agency.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1455__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, unless the
context otherwise requires:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1455__subsec_6__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Law enforcement agencyï¿½ means:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1455__subsec_6__subsec_a__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A police department of an incorporated
city;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1455__subsec_6__subsec_a__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The sheriffï¿½s office of a county;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1455__subsec_6__subsec_a__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A metropolitan police department;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1455__subsec_6__subsec_a__subsec_4">
                <num>(4)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The Department of Corrections;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1455__subsec_6__subsec_a__subsec_5">
                <num>(5)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The police department for the Nevada
System of Higher Education;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1455__subsec_6__subsec_a__subsec_6">
                <num>(6)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Any political subdivision of this
State employing park rangers to enforce laws within its jurisdiction; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1455__subsec_6__subsec_a__subsec_7">
                <num>(7)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Any political subdivision of this
State which has as its primary duty the enforcement of law and which employs
peace officers pursuant toNRS 289.150to289.360, inclusive, to fulfill its
duty.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1455__subsec_6__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Level of forceï¿½ means an escalating series
of actions a peace officer may use to resolve or control a situation or person
depending on the intensity of the situation or resistance of the person that
ranges from the use of no force to the use of deadly force.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1993,
931; A2021,
1456,2637)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-146">
          <num>171.146</num>
          <heading>Weapon may be taken from person arrested.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Any person making an arrest may take from the
person arrested all dangerous and offensive weapons which the person arrested
may have about his or her person.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1402)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-147">
          <num>171.147</num>
          <heading>Duties of arresting officer where person arrested appears to be
intoxicated or not in control of the personï¿½s physical functions.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-147__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every peace officer shall, when
arresting any person who appears to be intoxicated or not in control of the
personï¿½s physical functions, investigate in a reasonable manner to determine
whether or not that person is wearing a bracelet, necklace, other visible
device or other identification identifying a medical condition which might
account for the actions of the person.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-147__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any arresting officer who discovers
identification of a medical condition during an investigation conducted
pursuant to subsection 1 shall take reasonable steps to aid the afflicted
person in receiving medication or other treatment for the medical condition.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1981,
781)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-148">
          <num>171.148</num>
          <heading>Warrant of arrest by telegram authorized.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-148__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A warrant of arrest may be transmitted
by telegram. A copy of a warrant transmitted by telegram may be sent to one or
more peace officers, and the copy is as effectual in the hands of any officer,
and the officer must proceed in the same manner under it, as though the officer
held an original warrant issued by the magistrate before whom the original
complaint in the case was laid.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-148__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every officer causing a warrant to be
transmitted by telegram pursuant to subsection 1 must certify as correct a copy
of the warrant and endorsement thereon, and must return the original with a
statement of the officerï¿½s action thereunder.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-148__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, ï¿½telegramï¿½
includes every method of electric or electronic communication by which a
written as distinct from an oral message is transmitted.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1402; A1973,
598;2003,
984)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-152">
          <num>171.152</num>
          <heading>Return of warrant after execution by arrest or issuance of
citation; return of summons after service; cancellation by district attorney
before execution or service; reissuance.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-152__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The peace officer executing a warrant
by arrest shall make return thereof to the magistrate before whom the defendant
is brought pursuant toNRS 171.178and171.184. At the request of the district
attorney any unexecuted warrant must be returned to the magistrate by whom it
was issued and must be cancelled.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-152__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The peace officer executing a warrant
by issuance of a citation pursuant to subsection 3 ofNRS 171.122shall:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-152__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Record on the warrant the number assigned to
the citation issued thereon;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-152__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Attach the warrant to the citation issued
thereon; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-152__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Return the warrant and citation to the
magistrate before whom the defendant is scheduled to appear.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-152__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>On or before the return day the person
to whom a summons was delivered for service shall make return thereof to the
magistrate before whom the summons is returnable.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-152__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>At the request of the district attorney
made at any time while the complaint is pending, a warrant returned unexecuted
and not cancelled or a summons returned unserved or a duplicate thereof may be
delivered by the magistrate to a peace officer for execution or service.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1403; A1993,
144;2021,
195)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-153">
          <num>171.153</num>
          <heading>Right of person arrested to make telephone calls.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-153__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person arrested has the right to
make a reasonable number of completed telephone calls from the police station
or other place at which the person is booked immediately after the person is
booked and, except where physically impossible, no later than 3 hours after the
arrest. Such telephone calls may be limited to local calls, except that long
distance calls may be made by the arrested person at his or her own expense.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-153__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A reasonable number of calls must
include one completed call to a friend or bail agent and one completed call to
an attorney.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1973,
724; A1997,
3393)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1536">
          <num>171.1536</num>
          <heading>Arrest of person with communications disability: Interpreter to
be made available.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Upon the arrest
of a person with a communications disability as defined inNRS 50.050, and before any interrogation or
the taking of a statement, the peace officer in actual charge of the station,
headquarters or other facility to which the person with a communications
disability has been brought shall make an interpreter available at public
expense to that person in accordance with the provisions ofNRS 50.050to50.053, inclusive.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1975,
309; A1979,
657;2001,
1776;2007,
170)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1537">
          <num>171.1537</num>
          <heading>Arrest of person with disability: Right to communicate by mail
or telephone.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>When a person with a
disability is detained in custody, the detaining authority shall make available
a reasonable means of communication, at least pencil and paper, and at least
two envelopes and first-class postage stamps. If the person with a disability
so requests, the proper officer of the detaining authority shall make on the
personï¿½s behalf the same number and kind of telephone calls which a person
arrested is authorized by law or custom to make and shall mail any letters
written by that person.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1975,
309; A2001,
1776)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1538">
          <num>171.1538</num>
          <heading>Arrest of person with communications disability: Waiver of right
to interpretation or communication.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1538__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The rights to interpretation and
communication provided inNRS 171.1536and171.1537may not be waived except
knowingly and voluntarily by the person with a communications disability by a
written statement indicating a desire not to be so assisted. At any time after
arrest but before the termination of any custody, the person may retract a
waiver by indicating a desire to be so assisted.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1538__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Unless there is a waiver under this
section, there must be no interrogation or taking of the statement of a person
with a communications disability without the assistance of an interpreter in
accordance with the provisions ofNRS 50.050to50.053, inclusive.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1975,
309; A2001,
1776;2007,
170)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1539">
          <num>171.1539</num>
          <heading>Transfer of impounded animal owned or possessed by arrested and
detained person: Recovery for cost of care; lien.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1539__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided inNRS 574.201to574.204, inclusive, if a person is lawfully
arrested and detained and any animal owned or possessed by the person is
impounded by the county, city or other local government in which the person is
arrested at the time of the arrest or after the arrest, the person may provide
the name of any person who is authorized to care for the animal. The county,
city or other local government or animal shelter must transfer the animal to
such a person if the county, city or other local government determines that the
person is able to provide adequate care and shelter to the animal. If within 10
days after the county, city or other local government impounds the animal no
such authorized person is able to provide adequate care and shelter to the
animal, the county, city or other local government or animal shelter:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1539__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>May allow another person who is able to
provide adequate care and shelter to care for the animal temporarily; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1539__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>May take possession of the animal.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1539__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The State shall create and maintain a
written notice which must:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1539__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Inform the person or the public that an
animal, owned or possessed by a person who has been arrested and detained, may
have been impounded;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1539__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Include the current contact information of
each animal shelter in each county, city or other local government responsible
for:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1539__subsec_2__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Impounding an animal; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1539__subsec_2__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Providing care and shelter to an
animal;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1539__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Be available in English, Spanish, Tagalog and
Standard Chinese;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1539__subsec_2__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Be provided to each county or city jail or
detention facility; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1539__subsec_2__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Be posted in a conspicuous place in each
county or city jail or detention facility.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1539__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person lawfully arrested and
detained:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1539__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>May make a reasonable number of completed
telephone calls from a county or city jail or detention facility for the
purpose of locating an animal impounded pursuant to this section; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1539__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Shall not be charged for each completed call
to an animal shelter listed in the written notice posted pursuant to subsection
2.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1539__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a person is convicted of the crime
for which he or she was lawfully arrested, the county, city or other local
government or animal shelter may by appropriate legal action recover the
reasonable cost of any care and shelter furnished to the animal by the county,
city or other local government or animal shelter, including, without limitation,
imposing a lien on the animal for the cost of such care and shelter.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1539__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The board of county commissioners of
each county, if its jurisdiction to enact and enforce ordinances relating to
animals is not limited by an interlocal agreement, may adopt an ordinance which
provides for time of not less than 5 days to a person lawfully arrested or
detained for the purpose of providing the person a reasonable opportunity to
locate another person to take possession of an animal. Such a reasonable opportunity
is provided upon assistance from a county, city or other local government or an
animal shelter.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1539__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The city council or other governing
body of each incorporated city, whether organized under general law or special
charter, if its jurisdiction to enact and enforce ordinances relating to
animals is not limited by an interlocal agreement, may adopt an ordinance which
provides for time of not less than 5 days to a person lawfully arrested or
detained for the purpose of providing the person a reasonable opportunity to
locate another person to take possession of an animal. Such a reasonable
opportunity is provided upon assistance from a county, city or other local
government or an animal shelter.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1539__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1539__subsec_7__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Animalï¿½ means any dog, cat, horse, other
domesticated animal or undomesticated animal which is maintained as a pet. The
term:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1539__subsec_7__subsec_a__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Includes any chicken, pig, rabbit or
other animal which is maintained as a pet whether or not the animal is
domesticated.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1539__subsec_7__subsec_a__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subparagraph 1, does not include any cattle, sheep, goats, swine or poultry.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1539__subsec_7__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Animal shelterï¿½ has the meaning ascribed to
it inNRS 574.240.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2017,
1593; A2019,
1774)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-154">
          <num>171.154</num>
          <heading>Short title.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>NRS 171.154to171.164, inclusive, may be cited as the
Uniform Act on Interstate Fresh Pursuit.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1403)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-156">
          <num>171.156</num>
          <heading>Definitions.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-156__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>ï¿½Fresh pursuitï¿½ includes fresh pursuit
as defined by the common law and also the pursuit of a person who has committed
a felony or who is reasonably suspected of having committed a felony. It shall
also include the pursuit of a person suspected of having committed a supposed
felony, though no felony has actually been committed, if there is reasonable
ground for believing that a felony has been committed. Fresh pursuit as used inNRS 171.154to171.164, inclusive, shall not necessarily
imply instant pursuit, but pursuit without unreasonable delay.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-156__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>ï¿½Stateï¿½ includes the District of
Columbia for the purpose ofNRS 171.154to171.164, inclusive.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1403)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-158">
          <num>171.158</num>
          <heading>Arrests within this State by foreign officers; hearing before
magistrate.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-158__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any member of a duly organized state,
county or municipal peace unit of another state of the United States who enters
this State in fresh pursuit, and continues within this State in fresh pursuit,
of a person in order to arrest the person on the ground that the person is
believed to have committed a felony in the other state, shall have the same
authority to arrest and hold such person in custody, as has any member of any
duly organized state, county or municipal peace unit of this State, to arrest
and hold in custody a person on the ground that the person is believed to have
committed a felony in this State.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-158__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The officer of another state making an
arrest within this State shall take the person arrested before a magistrate of
the county in which the arrest was made, without unnecessary delay. The
magistrate shall conduct a hearing for the purpose of determining the lawfulness
of the arrest. If the magistrate determines that the arrest was lawful, the
magistrate shall commit the person arrested to await for a reasonable time the
issuance of an extradition warrant by the Governor of this State or admit the
person to bail for such purpose. If the magistrate determines the arrest was
unlawful the magistrate shall discharge the person arrested.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-158__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>This section shall not be construed so
as to make unlawful any arrest in this State which would otherwise be lawful.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1403)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-162">
          <num>171.162</num>
          <heading>Duty of Secretary of State.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>On
March 4, 1955, the Secretary of State shall certify a copy ofNRS 171.154to171.164, inclusive, to the executive
department of each of the states of the United States.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1404)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-164">
          <num>171.164</num>
          <heading>Severability.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If
any part ofNRS 171.154to171.164, inclusive, is for any reason
declared void, it is declared to be the intent ofNRS 171.154to171.164, inclusive, that such invalidity
shall not affect the validity of the remaining portions of those sections.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1404)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-166">
          <num>171.166</num>
          <heading>Short title.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>NRS 171.166to171.176, inclusive, may be cited as the
Uniform Act on Intrastate Fresh Pursuit.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1404)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-168">
          <num>171.168</num>
          <heading>Definitions.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Fresh
pursuitï¿½ as used inNRS 171.166to171.176, inclusive, shall include fresh
pursuit as defined by the common law and also the pursuit of a person who has
committed a felony or is reasonably suspected of having committed a felony in
this state, or who has committed or attempted to commit any criminal offense in
this state in the presence of the arresting officer referred to inNRS 171.172or for whom such officer holds
a warrant of arrest for a criminal offense. It shall also include the pursuit
of a person suspected of having committed a supposed felony in this state,
though no felony has actually been committed, if there is reasonable ground for
so believing. Fresh pursuit as used inNRS
171.166to171.176, inclusive, shall
not necessarily imply instant pursuit, but pursuit without unreasonable delay.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1404)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-172">
          <num>171.172</num>
          <heading>When officer may arrest.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Any
peace officer of this state in fresh pursuit of a person who is reasonably
believed by the peace officer to have committed a felony in this state or has
committed, or attempted to commit, any criminal offense in this state in the
presence of such officer, or for whom such officer holds a warrant of arrest,
may hold in custody such person anywhere in this state.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1404)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-174">
          <num>171.174</num>
          <heading>Procedure after arrest.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If
such an arrest is made in obedience to a warrant, the disposition of the
prisoner shall be as in other cases of arrest under a warrant. If the arrest is
without a warrant, the prisoner shall without unnecessary delay be taken before
a municipal court or a justice of the peace or other magistrate of the county
wherein such an arrest was made, and such court shall admit such person to
bail, if the offense is bailable, by taking security by way of recognizance for
the appearance of such prisoner before the court having jurisdiction of such
criminal offense.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1404)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-176">
          <num>171.176</num>
          <heading>Limitation.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>NRS 171.172shall not make unlawful an
arrest which would otherwise be lawful.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1404)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-177">
          <num>171.177</num>
          <heading>When person detained must be taken before magistrate.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-177__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When the person demands an immediate
appearance before a magistrate;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-177__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When the person is detained pursuant to
a warrant for the personï¿½s arrest;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-177__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When the person is arrested by a peace
officer; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-177__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In any other event when the person is
issued a misdemeanor citation by an authorized person and refuses to give a
written promise to appear in court as provided inNRS 171.1773.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1973,
156; A1975,
1200;1993,
144)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1771">
          <num>171.1771</num>
          <heading>Issuance of citation when person detained by peace officer.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1771__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 2, whenever any person is detained by a peace officer for any
violation of a county, city or town ordinance or a state law which is
punishable as a misdemeanor and the person is not required to be taken before a
magistrate, the person must be given a misdemeanor citation unless the
violation constitutes a repeat offense or a prohibited offense, in which case
the person may, in the discretion of the peace officer, either be given a
misdemeanor citation or be taken without unnecessary delay before the proper
magistrate.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1771__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person described in subsection 1 must
be taken before the proper magistrate when:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1771__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The person does not furnish satisfactory
evidence of identity; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1771__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The peace officer has reasonable grounds to
believe that:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1771__subsec_2__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The person will disregard a written
promise to appear in court;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1771__subsec_2__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The violation will continue; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1771__subsec_2__subsec_b__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Another person or property is in
imminent danger.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1973,
156; A2021,
3454)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1772">
          <num>171.1772</num>
          <heading>Issuance of citation after arrest by private person.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1772__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Whenever any person is arrested by a
private person, as provided inNRS 171.126,
for any violation of a county, city or town ordinance or state law which is
punishable as a misdemeanor, such person arrested must be issued a misdemeanor
citation by a peace officer in lieu of being immediately taken before a
magistrate by the peace officer unless the violation constitutes a repeat
offense or a prohibited offense, in which case the person arrested may be
issued the misdemeanor citation or be immediately taken before a magistrate by
the peace officer.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1772__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The citation described in subsection 1
must not be issued unless:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1772__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The person arrested furnishes satisfactory
evidence of identity; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1772__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The peace officer has reasonable grounds to
believe that:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1772__subsec_2__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The person arrested will keep a
written promise to appear in court;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1772__subsec_2__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The violation will cease; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="171-1772__subsec_2__subsec_b__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Another person or property is not in
imminent danger.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1973,
1157; A1975,
1201;2001,
2023;2021,
3454)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1773">
          <num>171.1773</num>
          <heading>Form and contents of citation: When person detained by peace
officer.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1773__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Whenever a person is detained by a
peace officer for any violation of a county, city or town ordinance or a state
law which is punishable as a misdemeanor and the person is not taken before a
magistrate as required or permitted byNRS
171.177,171.1771or171.1772, the peace officer must prepare a
misdemeanor citation manually or electronically in the form of a complaint
issuing in the name of ï¿½The State of Nevadaï¿½ or in the name of the respective
county, city or town, containing a notice to appear in court, the name and
address of the person, the state registration number of the personï¿½s vehicle,
if any, the offense charged, including a brief description of the offense and the
NRS or ordinance citation, the time when and place where the person is required
to appear in court, and such other pertinent information as may be necessary.
The citation must be signed by the peace officer. If the citation is prepared
electronically, the officer shall sign the copy of the citation that is
delivered to the person charged with the violation.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1773__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The time specified in the notice to
appear must be at least 5 days after the alleged violation unless the person
charged with the violation demands an earlier hearing.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1773__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The place specified in the notice must
be before a magistrate, as designated inNRS
171.178and171.184.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1773__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The person charged with the violation
may give a written promise to appear in court by signing at least one copy of
the misdemeanor citation prepared by the peace officer, in which event the
peace officer shall deliver a copy of the citation to the person, and thereupon
the peace officer shall not take the person into physical custody for the
violation. If the citation is prepared electronically, the officer shall
deliver the signed copy of the citation to the person and shall indicate on the
electronic record of the citation whether the person charged gave a written
promise to appear. A copy of the citation that is signed by the person charged
or the electronic record of the citation which indicates that the person
charged gave a written promise to appear suffices as proof of service.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1973,
156; A1991,
16;1999,
1141;2021,
3455)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1774">
          <num>171.1774</num>
          <heading>Form and contents of citation: When issued after arrest by
private person.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1774__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In those instances described inNRS 171.1772, the peace officer summoned
after the arrest shall prepare a misdemeanor citation manually or
electronically in the form of a complaint issuing in the name of ï¿½The State of
Nevadaï¿½ or in the name of the respective county, city or town, and containing:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1774__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A notice to appear in court;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1774__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The name and address of the person;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1774__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The state registration number of the personï¿½s
vehicle, if any;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1774__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The offense charged, including a brief
description of the offense and the NRS or ordinance citation;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1774__subsec_1__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The time when and place where the person is
required to appear in court;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1774__subsec_1__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Such other pertinent information as may be
necessary; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1774__subsec_1__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The signatures of the private person making
the arrest and the peace officer preparing the citation.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1774__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The time specified in the notice to
appear must be at least 5 days after the alleged violation unless the person
charged with the violation demands an earlier hearing.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1774__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The place specified in the notice must
be before a magistrate, as designated inNRS
171.178and171.184.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1774__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The person charged with the violation
may give a written promise to appear in court by signing at least one copy of
the misdemeanor citation prepared by the peace officer, in which event the
peace officer shall deliver a copy of the citation to the person, and thereupon
the peace officer shall not take the person into physical custody for the
violation. If the citation is prepared electronically, the officer shall
deliver the signed copy of the citation to the person and shall indicate on the
electronic record of the citation whether the person charged gave a written
promise to appear. A copy of the citation that is signed by the person charged
or the electronic record of the citation which indicates that the person
charged gave a written promise to appear suffices as proof of service.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1973,
1157; A1991,
16;1999,
1142)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1775">
          <num>171.1775</num>
          <heading>Preparation of citations: Use of citation book or electronic
device; maintenance of records relating to citation book or electronic device.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1775__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every county, city or town law
enforcement agency in this state shall provide in appropriate form misdemeanor
citations containing notices to appear which must meet the requirements ofNRS 171.177to171.1779, inclusive, and be:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1775__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Issued in books; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1775__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Available through an electronic device used
to prepare the citations.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1775__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The chief administrative officer of
each law enforcement agency is responsible for the issuance of such books and
electronic devices and shall maintain a record of each book, each electronic device
and each citation contained therein issued to individual members of the law
enforcement agency. The chief administrative officer shall require and retain a
receipt for every book and electronic device that is issued.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1973,
157,1158;
A1991,
17;1999,
1143)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-17751">
          <num>171.17751</num>
          <heading>Designation of certain state, county and city officers to
prepare, sign and serve citations.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-17751__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any board of county commissioners or
governing body of a city may designate the chief officer of the organized fire
department or any employees designated by the chief officer, and certain of its
inspectors of solid waste management, building, housing and licensing
inspectors, zoning enforcement officers, parking enforcement officers, animal control
officers, traffic engineers, marshals and park rangers of units of specialized
law enforcement established pursuant toNRS
280.125, and other persons charged with the enforcement of county or city
ordinances, to prepare, sign and serve written citations on persons accused of
violating a county or city ordinance.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-17751__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Chief Medical Officer and the
health officer of each county, district and city may designate certain
employees to prepare, sign and serve written citations on persons accused of
violating any law, ordinance or regulation of a board of health that relates to
public health.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-17751__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Administrator of the Housing
Division of the Department of Business and Industry may designate certain
employees to prepare, sign and serve written citations on persons accused of
violating any law or regulation of the Division relating to the provisions ofchapters 118B,461,461Aand489of NRS.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-17751__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The State Contractorsï¿½ Board may
designate certain of its employees to prepare, sign and serve written citations
on persons pursuant to subsection 2 ofNRS
624.115.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-17751__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An employee designated pursuant to this
section:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-17751__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>May exercise the authority to prepare, sign
and serve citations only within the field of enforcement in which the employee
works;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-17751__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>May, if employed by a city or county,
prepare, sign and serve a citation only to enforce an ordinance of the city or
county by which the employee is employed; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-17751__subsec_5__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Shall comply with the provisions ofNRS 171.1773.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1979,
871; A1981,
564,858;1987,
377;1989,
279;1993,
81,1330,1511,2515;1995,
583;1999,
2966;2005,
1382;2017,
3613)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1776">
          <num>171.1776</num>
          <heading>Issued citations: Filing with court; disposition of charges by
court; unlawful acts; maintenance of records.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1776__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every peace officer upon issuing a
misdemeanor citation, pursuant toNRS 171.177to171.1779, inclusive, to an alleged
violator of any provision of a county, city or town ordinance or of a state law
which is punishable as a misdemeanor shall file manually or, if the provisions
of subsection 2 are satisfied, file electronically the original or a copy of
such misdemeanor citation with a court having jurisdiction over the alleged
offense.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1776__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A copy of a misdemeanor citation that
is prepared electronically may be filed electronically with a court having
jurisdiction over the alleged offense if the court:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1776__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Authorizes such electronic filing;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1776__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Has the ability to receive and store the
citation electronically; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1776__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Has the ability to physically reproduce the
citation upon request.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1776__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon the filing of the original or a
copy of such misdemeanor citation with a court having jurisdiction over the
alleged offense, such original or copy of such misdemeanor citation may be
disposed of only by trial in such court or other official action by a judge of
such court.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1776__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is unlawful and official misconduct
for any peace officer or other officer or public employee to dispose of a
misdemeanor citation or copies thereof or of the record of the issuance of a
misdemeanor citation in a manner other than as required in this section.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1776__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The chief administrative officer of
every county, city or town law enforcement agency shall require the return of a
physical copy or electronic record of every misdemeanor citation issued by an
officer under the chief administrative officerï¿½s supervision to an alleged
misdemeanant and of all physical copies or electronic records of every
misdemeanor citation which has been spoiled or upon which any entry has been
made and not issued to an alleged misdemeanant.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1776__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such chief administrative officer shall
also maintain or cause to be maintained in connection with every misdemeanor
citation issued by an officer under the chief administrative officerï¿½s
supervision a record of the disposition of the charge by the court in which the
original or copy of the misdemeanor citation was filed.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1973,
157,1158;
A1999,
1143)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1777">
          <num>171.1777</num>
          <heading>Issued citations: Audit of records.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Every
record of misdemeanor citations required byNRS
171.177to171.1779, inclusive,
shall be audited at least semiannually by the appropriate fiscal officer of the
governmental agency to which the law enforcement agency is responsible.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1973,
158,1159)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1778">
          <num>171.1778</num>
          <heading>Citation filed with court deemed complaint for purpose of
prosecution.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1778__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Includes information whose truthfulness
is attested as required for a complaint charging commission of the offense
alleged in the citation to have been committed; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1778__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Is prepared electronically,
ï¿½then the
citation when filed with a court of competent jurisdiction shall be deemed to
be a lawful complaint for the purpose of prosecution.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1973,
158,1159;
A1983,
446;1999,
1144)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-17785">
          <num>171.17785</num>
          <heading>Effect of violation of written promise to appear; appearance by
counsel in lieu of personal appearance authorized.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-17785__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is unlawful for a person to violate
a written promise to appear given to a peace officer upon the issuance of a
misdemeanor citation prepared manually or electronically, regardless of the
disposition of the charge for which the citation was originally issued.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-17785__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person may comply with a written
promise to appear in court by an appearance by counsel.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-17785__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A warrant may issue upon a violation of
a written promise to appear.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1999,
1141)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1779">
          <num>171.1779</num>
          <heading>NRS 171.177to171.1779, inclusive, not applicable to
violations of traffic laws.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The
provisions ofNRS 171.177to171.1779, inclusive, do not apply to those
situations in which a person is detained by a peace officer for any violation ofchapters 484Ato484E, inclusive, of NRS.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1973,
158,1159)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-178">
          <num>171.178</num>
          <heading>Appearance before magistrate; release from custody by arresting
officer.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-178__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsections 5 and 6, a peace officer making an arrest under a warrant issued
upon a complaint or without a warrant shall take the arrested person without
unnecessary delay before the magistrate who issued the warrant or the nearest
available magistrate empowered to commit persons charged with offenses against
the laws of the State of Nevada.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-178__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A private person making an arrest
without a warrant shall deliver the arrested person without unnecessary delay
to a peace officer. Except as otherwise provided in subsections 5 and 6 andNRS 171.1772, the peace officer shall take
the arrested person without unnecessary delay before the nearest available
magistrate empowered to commit persons charged with offenses against the laws
of the State of Nevada.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-178__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If an arrested person is not brought
before a magistrate within 72 hours after arrest, excluding nonjudicial days,
the magistrate:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-178__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Shall give the prosecuting attorney an
opportunity to explain the circumstances leading to the delay; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-178__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>May release the arrested person if the
magistrate determines that the person was not brought before a magistrate
without unnecessary delay.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-178__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When a person arrested without a
warrant is brought before a magistrate, a complaint must be filed forthwith.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-178__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided inNRS 178.484and178.487, where the defendant can be
admitted to bail without appearing personally before a magistrate, the
defendant must be so admitted with the least possible delay, and required to
appear before a magistrate at the earliest convenient time thereafter.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-178__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A peace officer may immediately release
from custody without any further proceedings any person the peace officer
arrests without a warrant if the peace officer is satisfied that there are
insufficient grounds for issuing a criminal complaint against the person
arrested. Any record of the arrest of a person released pursuant to this
subsection must also include a record of the release. A person so released shall
be deemed not to have been arrested but only detained.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1404; A1971,
574;1975,
1201;1979,
323,1190;1997,
3356;2001,
2023)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-182">
          <num>171.182</num>
          <heading>Proceedings before another magistrate.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If
the defendant is brought before a magistrate in the same county, other than the
one who issued the warrant, the affidavits and depositions on which the warrant
was granted, if the defendant insists upon an examination, must be sent to that
magistrate, or, if they cannot be procured, the prosecutor and the prosecutorï¿½s
witnesses must be summoned to give their testimony anew.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1405)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-184">
          <num>171.184</num>
          <heading>Proceedings upon complaint for offenses triable in another
county.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-184__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When a complaint is laid before a
magistrate of the commission of a public offense triable in another county of
the State, but showing that the defendant is in the county where the complaint
is laid, the same proceedings must be had as prescribed in this chapter except
that the warrant must require the defendant to be taken before the nearest or
most accessible magistrate of the county in which the offense is triable, and
the depositions of the complainant or prosecutor, and of the witnesses who may
have been produced, must be delivered by the magistrate to the officer to whom
the warrant is delivered.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-184__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The officer who executed the warrant
must take the defendant before the nearest or most accessible magistrate of the
county in which the offense is triable, and must deliver the depositions and
the warrant, with the officerï¿½s return endorsed thereon, and the magistrate
must then proceed in the same manner as upon a warrant issued by the
magistrate.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-184__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the offense charged in the warrant
issued pursuant to subsection 1 is a misdemeanor, the officer must, upon being
required by the defendant, take the defendant before a magistrate of the county
in which the warrant was issued, who must admit the defendant to bail, and
immediately transmit the warrant, depositions and undertaking to the justice of
the peace or clerk of the court in which the defendant is required to appear.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1405)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1845">
          <num>171.1845</num>
          <heading>Proceedings upon discovery of another arrest warrant outstanding
in another county.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1845__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a person is brought before a
magistrate under the provisions ofNRS
171.178or171.184, and it is
discovered that there is a warrant for the personï¿½s arrest outstanding in
another county of this State, the magistrate may release the person in accordance
with the provisions ofNRS 178.4851if:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1845__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The warrant arises out of a public offense
which constitutes a misdemeanor; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1845__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The person provides a suitable address where
the magistrate who issued the warrant in the other county can notify the person
of a time and place to appear.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1845__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a person is released under the
provisions of this section, the magistrate who releases the person shall
transmit the cash, bond, notes or agreement submitted under the provisions ofNRS 178.502or178.4851, together with the personï¿½s
address, to the magistrate who issued the warrant. Upon receipt of the cash,
bonds, notes or agreement and address, the magistrate who issued the warrant
shall notify the person of a time and place to appear.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1845__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any bail set under the provisions of
this section must be in addition to and apart from any bail set for any public
offense with which a person is charged in the county in which a magistrate is
setting bail. In setting bail under the provisions of this section, a
magistrate shall set the bail in an amount which is sufficient to induce a
reasonable person to travel to the county in which the warrant for the arrest
is outstanding.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1845__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who fails to appear in the
other county as ordered is guilty of failing to appear and shall be punished as
provided inNRS 199.335. A sentence of
imprisonment imposed for failing to appear in violation of this section must be
imposed consecutively to a sentence of imprisonment for the offense out of
which the warrant arises.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1973,
612; A1981,
1583;1999,
1844;2021,
3575)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-186">
          <num>171.186</num>
          <heading>Rights of defendant before preliminary examination.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The magistrate or master shall inform the
defendant of the complaint and of any affidavit filed therewith, of the right
to retain counsel, of the right to request the assignment of counsel if the
defendant is unable to obtain counsel, and of the right to have a preliminary
examination. The magistrate or master shall also inform the defendant that the
defendant is not required to make a statement and that any statement made may
be used against him or her. The magistrate shall allow the defendant reasonable
time and opportunity to consult counsel, and shall admit the defendant to bail
as provided in this title.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1405; A1977,
1571)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-188">
          <num>171.188</num>
          <heading>Procedure for appointment of attorney for indigent defendant.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-188__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any defendant charged with a public
offense who is an indigent may, by oral statement to the district judge, justice
of the peace, municipal judge or master, request the appointment of an attorney
to represent the defendant. The record in each such case must indicate that the
defendant was provided an opportunity to make an oral statement and whether the
defendant made such a statement or declined to request the appointment of an
attorney. If the defendant declined to request the appointment of an attorney,
the record must also indicate that the decision to decline was made knowingly
and voluntarily and with an understanding of the consequences.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-188__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The request must be accompanied by the
defendantï¿½s affidavit, which must state:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-188__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>That the defendant is without means of
employing an attorney; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-188__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Facts with some particularity, definiteness
and certainty concerning the defendantï¿½s financial disability.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-188__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The district judge, justice of the
peace, municipal judge or master shall forthwith consider the application and
shall make such further inquiry as he or she considers necessary. If the
district judge, justice of the peace, municipal judge or master:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-188__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Finds that the defendant is without means of
employing an attorney; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-188__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Otherwise determines that representation is
required,
ï¿½the judge,
justice or master shall designate the public defender of the county or the
State Public Defender, as appropriate, to represent the defendant.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-188__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the appropriate public defender is
unable to represent the defendant, or other good cause appears, the judge,
justice or master shall order the appointment of another attorney and refer the
selection of the attorney:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-188__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In a county whose population is less than
100,000, to the Department of Indigent Defense Services or its designee in
compliance with the plan of the county for the provision of indigent defense
services; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-188__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In a county whose population is 100,000 or
more, in compliance with the plan of the county for the provision of indigent
defense services.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-188__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The county or State Public Defender
must be reimbursed by the city for costs incurred in appearing in municipal
court. The county shall reimburse the State Public Defender for costs incurred
in appearing in Justice Court, unless the county has transferred the
responsibility to provide all indigent defense services for the county to the
State Public Defender pursuant toNRS
180.450. If a private attorney is appointed as provided in this section,
the private attorney must be reimbursed by the county for appearance in Justice
Court or the city for appearance in municipal court.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1405; A1969,
478;1971,
1412;1973,
357;1977,
1571;1983,
901;2019,
2879;2021,
2266)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-192">
          <num>171.192</num>
          <heading>Certification of bail; discharge of defendant.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>On admitting the defendant to bail, the
magistrate shall certify on the warrant the fact of having done so, and deliver
the warrant and recognizance to the officer having charge of the defendant. The
officer shall forthwith discharge the defendant from arrest, and shall, without
delay, deliver the warrant and recognizance to the justice of the peace,
magistrate or clerk of the court at which the defendant is required to appear.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1406)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-194">
          <num>171.194</num>
          <heading>Procedure when arrest for capital offense.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The defendant, when arrested under a warrant
for a capital offense, must be held in custody by the sheriff of the county in
which the complaint is filed, unless admitted to bail after an examination or
upon a writ of habeas corpus.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1406)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-196">
          <num>171.196</num>
          <heading>Preliminary examination: Waiver; time for conducting;
postponement; introduction of evidence and cross-examination of witnesses by
defendant; admissibility of hearsay evidence.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-196__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If an offense is not triable in the
Justice Court, the defendant must not be called upon to plead. If the defendant
waives preliminary examination, the magistrate shall immediately hold the
defendant to answer in the district court.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-196__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the defendant does not waive
examination, the magistrate shall hear the evidence within 15 days, unless for
good cause shown the magistrate extends such time. Unless the defendant waives
counsel, reasonable time must be allowed for counsel to appear.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-196__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in this
subsection, if the magistrate postpones the examination at the request of a
party, the magistrate may order that party to pay all or part of the costs and
fees expended to have a witness attend the examination. The magistrate shall
not require a party who requested the postponement of the examination to pay
for the costs and fees of a witness if:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-196__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>It was not reasonably necessary for the
witness to attend the examination; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-196__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The magistrate ordered the extension pursuant
to subsection 4.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-196__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If application is made for the
appointment of counsel for an indigent defendant, the magistrate shall postpone
the examination until:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-196__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The application has been granted or denied;
and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-196__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the application is granted, the attorney
appointed or the public defender has had reasonable time to appear.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-196__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The defendant may cross-examine
witnesses against him or her and may introduce evidence in his or her own
behalf.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-196__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Hearsay evidence consisting of a
statement made by the alleged victim of the offense is admissible at a
preliminary examination conducted pursuant to this section only if the
defendant is charged with one or more of the following offenses:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-196__subsec_6__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A sexual offense committed against a child
who is under the age of 16 years if the offense is punishable as a felony. As
used in this paragraph, ï¿½sexual offenseï¿½ has the meaning ascribed to it inNRS 179D.097.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-196__subsec_6__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Abuse of a child pursuant toNRS 200.508if the offense is committed
against a child who is under the age of 16 years and the offense is punishable
as a felony.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-196__subsec_6__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An act which constitutes domestic violence
pursuant toNRS 33.018, which is
punishable as a felony and which resulted in substantial bodily harm to the
alleged victim.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1406; A1971,
159;1997,
116;2015,
576)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1965">
          <num>171.1965</num>
          <heading>Discovery by defendant before preliminary examination; material
subject to discovery; effect of failure to permit discovery.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1965__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>At the time a person is brought before
a magistrate pursuant toNRS 171.178, or
as soon as practicable thereafter, but not less than 5 judicial days before a
preliminary examination, the prosecuting attorney shall provide a defendant
charged with a felony or a gross misdemeanor with copies of any:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1965__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Written or recorded statements or confessions
made by the defendant, or any written or recorded statements made by a witness
or witnesses, or any reports of statements or confessions, or copies thereof,
within the possession or custody of the prosecuting attorney;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1965__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Results or reports of physical or mental
examinations, scientific tests or scientific experiments made in connection
with the particular case, or copies thereof, within the possession or custody
of the prosecuting attorney; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1965__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Books, papers, documents or tangible objects
that the prosecuting attorney intends to introduce in evidence during the case
in chief of the State, or copies thereof, within the possession or custody of
the prosecuting attorney.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1965__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The defendant is not entitled, pursuant
to the provisions of this section, to the discovery or inspection of:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1965__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An internal report, document or memorandum
that is prepared by or on behalf of the prosecuting attorney in connection with
the investigation or prosecution of the case.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1965__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A statement, report, book, paper, document,
tangible object or any other type of item or information that is privileged or
protected from disclosure or inspection pursuant to the Constitution or laws of
this State or the Constitution of the United States.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1965__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of this section are not
intended to affect any obligation placed upon the prosecuting attorney by the
Constitution of this State or the Constitution of the United States to disclose
exculpatory evidence to the defendant.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1965__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The magistrate shall not postpone a preliminary
examination at the request of a party based solely on the failure of the
prosecuting attorney to permit the defendant to inspect, copy or photograph
material as required in this section, unless the court finds that the defendant
has been prejudiced by such failure.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1997,
2364; A2009,
486)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-197">
          <num>171.197</num>
          <heading>Use of affidavit at preliminary examination: When permitted;
notice by district attorney; circumstances under which district attorney must
produce person who signed affidavit; continuances.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-197__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a witness resides outside this State
or more than 100 miles from the place of a preliminary examination, the
witnessï¿½s affidavit may be used at the preliminary examination if it is
necessary for the district attorney to establish as an element of any offense
that:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-197__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The witness was the owner, possessor or
occupant of real or personal property; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-197__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The defendant did not have the permission of
the witness to enter, occupy, possess or control the real or personal property
of the witness.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-197__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a financial institution does not
maintain any principal or branch office within this State or if a financial
institution that maintains a principal or branch office within this State does
not maintain any such office within 100 miles of the place of a preliminary
examination, the affidavit of a custodian of the records of the financial
institution or the affidavit of any other qualified person of the financial
institution may be used at the preliminary examination if it is necessary for
the district attorney to establish as an element of any offense that:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-197__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When a check or draft naming the financial
institution as drawee was drawn or passed, the account or purported account
upon which the check or draft was drawn did not exist, was closed or held
insufficient money, property or credit to pay the check or draft in full upon
its presentation; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-197__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>When a check or draft naming the financial
institution as drawee was presented for payment to the financial institution,
the account or purported account upon which the check or draft was drawn did
not exist, was closed or held insufficient money, property or credit to pay the
check or draft in full.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-197__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The district attorney shall provide
either written or oral notice to the defendant, not less than 10 days before
the scheduled preliminary examination, that the district attorney intends to
use an affidavit described in this section at the preliminary examination.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-197__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If, at or before the time of the
preliminary examination, the defendant establishes that:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-197__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>There is a substantial and bona fide dispute
as to the facts in an affidavit described in this section; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-197__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>It is in the best interests of justice that
the person who signed the affidavit be cross-examined,
ï¿½the
magistrate may order the district attorney to produce the person who signed the
affidavit and may continue the examination for any time it deems reasonably
necessary in order to receive such testimony.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1993,
548; A1999,
163)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-1975">
          <num>171.1975</num>
          <heading>Use of audiovisual technology to present live testimony at
preliminary examination: Requirements.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-1975__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a witness resides more than 100
miles from the place of a preliminary examination or is unable to attend the
preliminary examination because of a medical condition, or if good cause
otherwise exists, the magistrate must allow the witness to testify at the
preliminary examination through the use of audiovisual technology.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1975__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a witness testifies at the
preliminary examination through the use of audiovisual technology:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1975__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The testimony of the witness must be
transcribed by a certified court reporter; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1975__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Before giving testimony, the witness must be
sworn and must sign a written declaration, on a form provided by the
magistrate, which acknowledges that the witness understands that he or she is
subject to the jurisdiction of the courts of this state and may be subject to
criminal prosecution for the commission of any crime in connection with his or
her testimony, including, without limitation, perjury, and that the witness
consents to such jurisdiction.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1975__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Audiovisual technology used pursuant to
this section must ensure that the witness may be:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-1975__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Clearly heard and seen; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-1975__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Examined and cross-examined.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-1975__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, ï¿½audiovisual
technologyï¿½ includes, without limitation, closed-circuit video and
videoconferencing.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2001,
543; A2015,
577)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-198">
          <num>171.198</num>
          <heading>Reporting testimony of witnesses.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-198__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 2, a magistrate shall employ a certified court reporter to take down
all the testimony and the proceedings on the hearing or examination and, within
such time as the court may designate, have such testimony and proceedings
transcribed into typewritten transcript.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-198__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A magistrate who presides over a
preliminary hearing in a justice court, in any case other than in a case in
which the death penalty is sought, may employ a certified court reporter to
take down all the testimony and the proceedings on the hearing or appoint a
person to use sound recording equipment to record all the testimony and the
proceedings on the hearing. If the magistrate appoints a person to use sound
recording equipment to record the testimony and proceedings on the hearing, the
testimony and proceedings must be recorded and transcribed in the same manner
as set forth inNRS 4.390to4.420, inclusive. Any transcript of the
testimony and proceedings produced from a recording conducted pursuant to this
subsection is subject to the provisions of this section in the same manner as a
transcript produced by a certified court reporter.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-198__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When the testimony of each witness is
all taken and transcribed by the reporter, the reporter shall certify to the
transcript in the same manner as for a transcript of testimony in the district
court, which certificate authenticates the transcript for all purposes of this
title.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-198__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Before the date set for trial, either
party may move the court before which the case is pending to add to, delete
from or otherwise correct the transcript to conform with the testimony as given
and to settle the transcript so altered.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-198__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The compensation for the services of a
reporter employed as provided in this section are the same as provided inNRS 3.370, to be paid out of the county
treasury as other claims against the county are allowed and paid.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-198__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Testimony reduced to writing and
authenticated according to the provisions of this section must be filed by the
examining magistrate with the clerk of the district court of the magistrateï¿½s
county, and if the prisoner is subsequently examined upon a writ of habeas
corpus, such testimony must be considered as given before such judge or court.
A copy of the transcript must be furnished to the defendant and to the district
attorney.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-198__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The testimony so taken may be used:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-198__subsec_7__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>By the defendant; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-198__subsec_7__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>By the State if the defendant was represented
by counsel or affirmatively waived his or her right to counsel,
ï¿½upon the
trial of the cause, and in all proceedings therein, when the witness is sick,
out of the State, dead, or persistent in refusing to testify despite an order
of the judge to do so, or when the witnessï¿½s personal attendance cannot be had
in court.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1406; A1973,
1322;1987,
911;1989,
1272;1993,
75,1411,2024;1995,
570;2009,
633)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-202">
          <num>171.202</num>
          <heading>District attorney to prosecute at preliminary examination where
felony or gross misdemeanor charged.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The
district attorney of the proper county shall be present at and conduct the
prosecution in all preliminary examinations where a felony or gross misdemeanor
is charged.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1407)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-204">
          <num>171.204</num>
          <heading>Exclusion of persons; exceptions.</heading>
          <subsection eId="171-204__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 2, the magistrate may, if good cause is shown and upon the request
of any party or on the magistrateï¿½s own motion, exclude from the examination
every person except:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="171-204__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The magistrateï¿½s clerk;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-204__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Attorney General;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-204__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The prosecuting attorney;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-204__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An investigating officer, after the
investigating officer has testified as a prosecuting witness and the
investigating officerï¿½s cross-examination has been completed;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-204__subsec_1__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any counsel for the victim;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-204__subsec_1__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The victim, after the victim has testified as
a prosecuting witness and the victimï¿½s cross-examination has been completed;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-204__subsec_1__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The defendant and the defendantï¿½s counsel;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-204__subsec_1__subsec_h">
              <num>(h)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The witness who is testifying;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-204__subsec_1__subsec_i">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The officer having the defendant or a witness
in the officerï¿½s custody;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-204__subsec_1__subsec_j">
              <num>(j)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An attendant to a witness designated pursuant
toNRS 178.571; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="171-204__subsec_1__subsec_k">
              <num>(k)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any other person whose presence is found by
the magistrate to be necessary for the proper conduct of the examination.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-204__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who is called as a witness
primarily for the purpose of identifying the victim may not be excluded from
the examination except in the discretion of the magistrate.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="171-204__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, ï¿½victimï¿½
includes any person described inNRS 178.569.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1407; A1969,
628;1983,
891;1995,
72,996;1997,
72,513)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-206">
          <num>171.206</num>
          <heading>Procedure following preliminary examination.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If from the evidence it appears to the
magistrate that there is probable cause to believe that an offense has been
committed and that the defendant has committed it, the magistrate shall
forthwith hold the defendant to answer in the district court; otherwise the
magistrate shall discharge the defendant. The magistrate shall admit the
defendant to bail as provided in this title. After concluding the proceeding
the magistrate shall transmit forthwith to the clerk of the district court all
papers in the proceeding and any bail.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1407)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_171-208">
          <num>171.208</num>
          <heading>Remand for preliminary examination.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If
a preliminary examination has not been had and the defendant has not
unconditionally waived the examination, the district court may for good cause
shown at any time before a plea has been entered or an indictment found remand
the defendant for preliminary examination to the appropriate justice of the
peace or other magistrate, and the justice or other magistrate shall then
proceed with the preliminary examination as provided in this chapter.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1407; A1987,
1188)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>