<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="NRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-123"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-123"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#nevada-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-nv"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="123"/>
          <FRBRname value="NRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-123/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-123/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-123/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-123/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="nevada-legislature" href="https://www.leg.state.nv.us" showAs="Nevada State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_123">
        <num>123</num>
        <heading>RIGHTS OF MARRIED COUPLES</heading>
        <section eId="sec_123-010">
          <num>123.010</num>
          <heading>Property rights of a married couple governed by chapter;
exceptions; rights vested before March 10, 1873, not affected.</heading>
          <subsection eId="123-010__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The property rights of a married couple
are governed by this chapter, unless there is:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="123-010__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A premarital agreement which is enforceable
pursuant tochapter 123Aof NRS; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="123-010__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A marriage contract or settlement,
ï¿½containing
stipulations contrary thereto.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-010__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Chapter 76, Statutes of Nevada 1865, is
repealed, but no rights vested or proceedings taken before March 10, 1873,
shall be affected by anything contained in this chapter of NRS.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [26:119:1873; B ï¿½ 176; BH ï¿½ 524; C ï¿½ 535; RL ï¿½ 2180;
NCL ï¿½ 3380] + [35:119:1873; B ï¿½ 185; BH ï¿½ 533; C ï¿½ 544; RL ï¿½ 2189; NCL ï¿½
3389]—(NRS A1989,
1004;2017,
760)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-020">
          <num>123.020</num>
          <heading>Curtesy and dower not allowed.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>No
estate is allowed one spouse as tenant by curtesy upon the death of his or her
spouse, nor is any estate in dower allotted to the other spouse upon the death
of his or her spouse.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [7:119:1873; B ï¿½ 157; BH ï¿½ 505; C ï¿½ 516; RL ï¿½ 2161;
NCL ï¿½ 3361]—(NRS A2017,
761)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-030">
          <num>123.030</num>
          <heading>How a married couple may hold property.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>A
married couple may hold real or personal property as joint tenants, tenants in
common, or as community property.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [8:119:1873; B ï¿½ 158; BH ï¿½ 506; C ï¿½ 517; RL ï¿½ 2162;
NCL ï¿½ 3362]—(NRS A1959,
408;2017,
761)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-050">
          <num>123.050</num>
          <heading>Spouse not liable for debts of other incurred before marriage.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Neither the separate property of a spouse nor
the spouseï¿½s share of the community property is liable for the debts of the
other spouse contracted before the marriage.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [17 1/2:119:1873; added1933,
118; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 3371.01]—(NRS A1975,
558)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-060">
          <num>123.060</num>
          <heading>No interests in property of other.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Except
as mentioned inNRS 123.070, neither
spouse has any interest in the property of the other spouse.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [18:119:1873; B ï¿½ 168; BH ï¿½ 516; C ï¿½ 527; RL ï¿½ 2172;
NCL ï¿½ 3372]—(NRS A2017,
761)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-070">
          <num>123.070</num>
          <heading>Spouses may make contracts.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Either
spouse may enter into any contract, engagement or transaction with the other
spouse, or with any other person respecting property, which either might enter
into if unmarried, subject in any contract, engagement or transaction between
themselves, to the general rules which control the actions of persons occupying
relations of confidence and trust toward each other.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [19:119:1873; B ï¿½ 169; BH ï¿½ 517; C ï¿½ 528; RL ï¿½ 2173;
NCL ï¿½ 3373]—(NRS A2017,
761)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-080">
          <num>123.080</num>
          <heading>Contract altering legal relations: Separation agreement;
consideration; introduction in evidence in divorce action.</heading>
          <subsection eId="123-080__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A married couple cannot by any contract
with each other alter their legal relations except as to property, and except
that they may agree to an immediate separation and may make provision for the
support of either of them and of their children during such separation.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-080__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The mutual consent of the parties is a
sufficient consideration for such an agreement as is mentioned in subsection 1.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-080__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In the event that a suit for divorce is
pending or immediately contemplated by one of the spouses against the other,
the validity of such agreement shall not be affected by a provision therein
that the agreement is made for the purpose of removing the subject matter
thereof from the field of litigation, and that in the event of a divorce being
granted to either party, the agreement shall become effective and not
otherwise.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-080__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a contract executed by a married
couple, or a copy thereof, be introduced in evidence as an exhibit in any
divorce action, and the court shall by decree or judgment ratify or adopt or
approve the contract by reference thereto, the decree or judgment shall have
the same force and effect and legal consequences as though the contract were
copied into the decree, or attached thereto.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [20:119:1873; A1935,
194;1953,
235] + [21:119:1873; B ï¿½ 171; BH ï¿½ 519; C ï¿½ 530; RL ï¿½ 2175; NCL ï¿½
3375]—(NRS A2017,
761)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-090">
          <num>123.090</num>
          <heading>Necessaries provided to neglected spouse when neglecting spouse
neglects to provide; recovery of value.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If
a spouse neglects to make adequate provision for the support of his or her
spouse, any other person may in good faith supply the neglected spouse with
articles necessary for his or her support, and recover the reasonable value
thereof from the neglecting spouse. The separate property of the neglecting
spouse is liable for the cost of such necessities if the community property of
the spouses is not sufficient to satisfy such debt.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [22:119:1873; B ï¿½ 172; BH ï¿½ 520; C ï¿½ 531; RL ï¿½ 2176;
NCL ï¿½ 3376]—(NRS A1975,
558;2017,
761)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-100">
          <num>123.100</num>
          <heading>Abandoned spouse not liable for support of abandoning spouse.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>A spouse abandoned by his or her spouse is not
liable for the support of the abandoning spouse until such spouse offers to
return unless the misconduct of the abandoned spouse justified the abandonment.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [23:119:1873; B ï¿½ 173; BH ï¿½ 521; C ï¿½ 532; RL ï¿½ 2177;
NCL ï¿½ 3377]—(NRS A1975,
558;2017,
761)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-110">
          <num>123.110</num>
          <heading>When spouse must support other spouse.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>A
spouse must support his or her spouse out of his or her separate property when
the spouse has no separate property and they have no community property and the
spouse, from infirmity, is not able or competent to support himself or herself.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [24:119:1873; B ï¿½ 174; BH ï¿½ 522; C ï¿½ 533; RL ï¿½ 2178;
NCL ï¿½ 3378]—(NRS A2017,
762)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-121">
          <num>123.121</num>
          <heading>Segregation of damage awards when spouses sue jointly.</heading>
          <subsection eId="123-121__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the action is for personal injuries,
damages assessed for:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="123-121__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Personal injuries and pain and suffering, to
the injured spouse as his or her separate property.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="123-121__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Loss of comfort and society, to the spouse
who suffers such loss.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="123-121__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Loss of services and hospital and medical
expenses, to the spouses as community property.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-121__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the action is for injury to
property, damages shall be awarded according to the character of the injured
property. Damages to separate property shall be awarded to the spouse owning
such property, and damages to community property shall be awarded to the
spouses as community property.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1975,
558; A2017,
762)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-125">
          <num>123.125</num>
          <heading>Character of property transferred into trust.</heading>
          <subsection eId="123-125__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A trust instrument may provide that
community property or separate property transferred into an irrevocable trust
of which both spouses are distribution beneficiaries, as defined inNRS 163.415, remains community property or
separate property, as applicable, during the marriage. Any community property
or separate property, including, without limitation, any income, appreciation
and proceeds thereof, that is distributed or withdrawn from a trust instrument
containing such a provision remains community property or separate property, as
applicable.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-125__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A spouse or other party in a case must
establish by clear and convincing evidence the transmutation of community
property or separate property that is transferred into a trust from, as
applicable:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="123-125__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Community property to separate property; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="123-125__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Separate property to community property.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-125__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of this section do not
affect the character of community property or separate property that is
transferred into a trust in any manner other than as described in this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2017,
1669; A2019,
1852)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-130">
          <num>123.130</num>
          <heading>Separate property of each spouse.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>All
property of a spouse owned by him or her before marriage, and that was acquired
by him or her afterwards by gift, bequest, devise, descent or by an award for
personal injury damages, with the rents, issues and profits thereof, is his or
her separate property.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1:119:1873; B ï¿½ 151; BH ï¿½ 499; C ï¿½ 510; RL ï¿½ 2155;
NCL ï¿½ 3355]—(NRS A1975,
558;2017,
762)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-140">
          <num>123.140</num>
          <heading>Inventory of separate property: Execution; recording;
supplemental inventory.</heading>
          <subsection eId="123-140__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A full and complete inventory of the
separate property of a married person, exclusive of money, may be made out and
signed by such person, acknowledged or proved in the manner required for the
acknowledgment or proof of a conveyance of real property, and may be recorded,
if such person is a resident of this State, in the office of the recorder of
the county in which such person resides. If any real property lying in another
county is included in a recorded inventory, then the inventory shall be also
recorded in the office of the recorder of such other county.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-140__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the married person is not a resident
of this state, a recorded inventory shall be recorded in the office of the
recorder of each county where any portion of the property, real or personal, is
situated, located or used.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-140__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>From time to time thereafter, a further
and supplemental inventory may be made out, signed, acknowledged or proved, and
recorded in like manner, of all other separate property afterward acquired by
such married person, excepting money, and the rents, issues and profits of such
personï¿½s separate property, included in the original or any subsequent
inventory, if the same be in money.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [3:119:1873; B ï¿½ 153; BH ï¿½ 501; C ï¿½ 512; RL ï¿½ 2157;
NCL ï¿½ 3357]—(NRS A1959,
9;1975,
559)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-150">
          <num>123.150</num>
          <heading>Recording of inventory is notice and evidence of title.</heading>
          <subsection eId="123-150__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a married person is a resident of
this state, the recording of the inventory of the personï¿½s separate property in
the office of the recorder of the county in which the person resides is notice
of the personï¿½s title to the separate property, except as to any real property
situate in another county, and as to that real property, the recording of the
inventory thereof in the office of the recorder of the county where the same is
situate, is notice of the personï¿½s title thereto.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-150__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a married person is not a resident
of this state, the recording of the inventory of the personï¿½s separate property
in the office of the recorder of the county where any portion of the property,
real or personal, included in the inventory is situate, located or used, is
notice of the personï¿½s title as to all that property situate, located or used
in that county.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [4:119:1873; B ï¿½ 154; BH ï¿½ 502; C ï¿½ 513; RL ï¿½ 2158;
NCL ï¿½ 3358]—(NRS A1975,
559;2001,
1755;2003,
75)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-160">
          <num>123.160</num>
          <heading>Effect of failure to record inventory.</heading>
          <subsection eId="123-160__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When a married person is a resident of
this state, the failure to file for record an inventory of such personï¿½s
separate property in the office of the recorder of the county of residence, or
the omission from the inventory, filed for record in such office, of any part
of such property, except as to real property situate in another county, is
prima facie evidence, as between such married person and purchasers in good
faith and for a valuable consideration from the other spouse, that the property
of which no inventory has been so filed, or which has been omitted from the
inventory, is not the separate property of such person. As to any real property
situate in another county, the failure to file for record an inventory thereof
in the office of the recorder of the county where the same is situate, or the
omission from the inventory, filed for record in such office, of any part of
such real property, is prima facie evidence, as between the married person and
such purchasers as aforesaid, that such real property of which no inventory has
been so filed, or which has been omitted from the inventory, is not such
personï¿½s separate property.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-160__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When a married person is not a resident
of this state, the failure to file for record an inventory of such personï¿½s
separate property in the office of the recorder of the county where any portion
of such property is situate, located or used, or the omission from the
inventory, filed in such office, of any part of such property, is, as to all
such property situate, located or used in that county, of which no inventory
has been so filed, or which has been omitted from the inventory, prima facie
evidence, as between the married person and such purchasers as aforesaid, that
the same is not such personï¿½s separate property.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-160__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions ofNRS 123.140,123.150and this section do not preclude
the introduction of other evidence to show the separate or community character
of the property of the spouses.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [5:119:1873; B ï¿½ 155; BH ï¿½ 503; C ï¿½ 514; RL ï¿½ 2159;
NCL ï¿½ 3359]—(NRS A1975,
559)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-170">
          <num>123.170</num>
          <heading>Each spouse controls own separate property.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Either spouse may, without the consent of the
other spouse, convey, charge, encumber or otherwise in any manner dispose of
his or her separate property.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [9:119:1873; B ï¿½ 159; BH ï¿½ 507; C ï¿½ 518; RL ï¿½ 2163;
NCL ï¿½ 3363]—(NRS A1975,
560)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-180">
          <num>123.180</num>
          <heading>Property and earnings of minor children.</heading>
          <subsection eId="123-180__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any property acquired by a child by
gift, bequest, devise or descent, with the rents, issues and profits thereof,
is the childï¿½s own property, and neither parent is entitled to any interest
therein.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-180__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The earnings and accumulations of
earnings of a minor child are the community property of his or her parents
unless relinquished to the child. Such relinquishment may be shown by written
instrument, proof of a specific oral gift, or proof of a course of conduct.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-180__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When a married couple is living
separate and apart the earnings and accumulations of earnings of their minor
children, unless relinquished, are the separate property of the spouse who has
their custody or, if no custody award has been made, then the separate property
of the spouse with whom such children are living.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [14:119:1873; B ï¿½ 164; BH ï¿½ 512; C ï¿½ 523; RL ï¿½ 2168;
NCL ï¿½ 3368]—(NRS A1975,
560;2017,
762)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-190">
          <num>123.190</num>
          <heading>Earnings of either spouse appropriated to own use pursuant to
written authorization of other spouse deemed gift.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>When
a spouse has given written authority to his or her spouse to appropriate to his
or her own use the spouseï¿½s earnings, the same, with the issues and profits
thereof, is deemed a gift from one spouse to the other, and is, with such
issues and profits, the latter spouseï¿½s separate property.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [15:119:1873; B ï¿½ 165; BH ï¿½ 513; C ï¿½ 524; RL ï¿½ 2169;
NCL ï¿½ 3369]—(NRS A1973,
1036;2017,
762)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-220">
          <num>123.220</num>
          <heading>Community property defined.</heading>
          <subsection eId="123-220__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An agreement in writing between the
spouses.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-220__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A decree of separate maintenance issued
by a court of competent jurisdiction.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ 3.NRS
123.190.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-220__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A decree issued or agreement in writing
entered pursuant toNRS 123.259.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [2:119:1873; B ï¿½ 152; BH ï¿½ 500; C ï¿½ 511; RL ï¿½ 2156;
NCL ï¿½ 3356]—(NRS A1975,
560;1987,
1016;1989,
380;2009,
1636;2017,
763)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-225">
          <num>123.225</num>
          <heading>Interests of each spouse in community property are present,
existing and equal interests.</heading>
          <subsection eId="123-225__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The respective interests of each spouse
in community property during continuance of the marriage relation are present,
existing and equal interests, subject to the provisions ofNRS 123.230.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-225__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of this section apply to
all community property, whether the community property was acquired before, on
or after March 26, 1959.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1959,
408; A1997,
1596;2017,
763)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-230">
          <num>123.230</num>
          <heading>Control of community property.</heading>
          <subsection eId="123-230__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Neither spouse may devise or bequeath
more than one-half of the community property.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-230__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Neither spouse may make a gift of
community property without the express or implied consent of the other.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-230__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Neither spouse may sell, convey or
encumber the community real property unless both join in the execution of the
deed or other instrument by which the real property is sold, conveyed or
encumbered, and the deed or other instrument must be acknowledged by both.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-230__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Neither spouse may purchase or contract
to purchase community real property unless both join in the transaction of
purchase or in the execution of the contract to purchase.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-230__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Neither spouse may create a security
interest, other than a purchase-money security interest as defined inNRS 104.9103, in, or sell, community
household goods, furnishings or appliances unless both join in executing the
security agreement or contract of sale, if any.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-230__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Neither spouse may acquire, purchase,
sell, convey or encumber the assets, including real property and goodwill, of a
business where both spouses participate in its management without the consent
of the other. If only one spouse participates in management, he or she may, in
the ordinary course of business, acquire, purchase, sell, convey or encumber
the assets, including real property and goodwill, of the business without the
consent of the nonparticipating spouse.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [6:119:1873; A1897,
24;1917,
121; 1919 RL ï¿½ 2160; NCL ï¿½ 3360]—(NRS A1973,
1037;1975,
560;1977,
271;1997,
1596;1999,
391)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-240">
          <num>123.240</num>
          <heading>Payments or refunds under benefit or savings plans to employees,
beneficiaries or estates: Discharge of employer, trustee or insurance company
from adverse claims; notice.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding
the provisions ofNRS 123.220and123.230, whenever payment or refund is made
to an employee, former employee, or his or her beneficiary or estate pursuant
to a written retirement, death or other employee benefit plan or savings plan,
such payment or refund shall fully discharge the employer and any trustee or
insurance company making such payment or refund from all adverse claims
thereto, unless, before such payment or refund is made, the employer or former
employer, where the payment is made by the employer or former employer, has
received at its principal place of business within this state written notice by
or on behalf of some other person that such other person claims to be entitled
to such payment or refund or some part thereof or where a trustee or insurance
company is making the payment, such notice has been received by the trustee or
insurance company at its home office, but nothing contained in this section
shall affect any claim or right to any such payment or refund or part thereof
as between all persons other than the employee and the trustee or insurance
company making such payment or refund.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [6.5:119:1873; added1953,
337]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-250">
          <num>123.250</num>
          <heading>Ownership of survivor upon death of spouse; disposal by will of
decedent.</heading>
          <subsection eId="123-250__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 2, upon the death of either spouse:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="123-250__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An undivided one-half interest in the
community property is the property of the surviving spouse and his or her sole
separate property.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="123-250__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The remaining interest:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="123-250__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Is subject to the testamentary
disposition of the decedent or, in the absence of such a testamentary
disposition, goes to the surviving spouse; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="123-250__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Is the only portion subject to
administration under the provisions of title 12 of NRS.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-250__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of this section:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="123-250__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Do not apply to the extent that they are
inconsistent with the provisions ofchapter 41Bof NRS.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="123-250__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Do not apply to community property with right
of survivorship.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="123-250__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Apply to all other community property,
whether the community property was acquired before, on or after July 1, 1975.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-250__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, ï¿½community
property with right of survivorshipï¿½ means community property in which a right
of survivorship exists pursuant toNRS
111.064or115.060or any other
provision of law.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1:198:1937; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 3395.01]—(NRS A1957,
359;1959,
408;1975,
561;1981,
779;1997,
1597;1999,
1355;2017,
763)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-259">
          <num>123.259</num>
          <heading>Division of income and resources of married couple: Manner;
conditions; restrictions.</heading>
          <subsection eId="123-259__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 2, a court of competent jurisdiction may, upon a proper petition
filed by a spouse or the guardian of a spouse, enter a decree dividing the
income and resources of a married couple pursuant to this section if one spouse
is an institutionalized spouse and the other spouse is a community spouse.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-259__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court shall not enter such a decree
if the division is contrary to a premarital agreement between the spouses which
is enforceable pursuant tochapter 123Aof
NRS.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-259__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Unless modified pursuant to subsection
4 or 5, the court may divide the income and resources:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="123-259__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Equally between the spouses; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="123-259__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>By protecting income for the community spouse
through application of the maximum federal minimum monthly maintenance needs
allowance set forth in 42 U.S.C. ï¿½ 1396r-5</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="123-259__subsec_3__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="123-259__subsec_3__subsec_d__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>(C) and by permitting a
transfer of resources to the community spouse an amount which does not exceed
the amount set forth in 42 U.S.C. ï¿½ 1396r-5</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="123-259__subsec_3__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="123-259__subsec_3__subsec_f__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>(A)(ii).
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-259__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If either spouse establishes that the
community spouse needs income greater than that otherwise provided under
paragraph</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="123-259__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 3, upon finding exceptional circumstances resulting
in significant financial duress and setting forth in writing the reasons for
that finding, the court may enter an order for support against the
institutionalized spouse for the support of the community spouse in an amount
adequate to provide such additional income as is necessary.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-259__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If either spouse establishes that a
transfer of resources to the community spouse pursuant to paragraph</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="123-259__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of
subsection 3, in relation to the amount of income generated by such a transfer,
is inadequate to raise the income of the community spouse to the amount allowed
under paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="123-259__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 3 or an order for support issued pursuant to
subsection 4, the court may substitute an amount of resources adequate to
provide income to fund the amount so allowed or to fund the order for support.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-259__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A copy of a petition for relief under
subsection 4 or 5 and any court order issued pursuant to such a petition must
be served on the Administrator of the Division of Welfare and Supportive
Services of the Department of Health and Human Services when any application
for medical assistance is made by or on behalf of an institutionalized spouse.
The Administrator may intervene no later than 45 days after receipt by the
Division of Welfare and Supportive Services of the Department of Health and
Human Services of an application for medical assistance and a copy of the
petition and any order entered pursuant to subsection 4 or 5, and may move to
modify the order.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-259__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person may enter into a written
agreement with his or her spouse dividing their community income, assets and
obligations into equal shares of separate income, assets and obligations of the
spouses. Such an agreement is effective only if one spouse is an
institutionalized spouse and the other spouse is a community spouse or a
division of the income or resources would allow one spouse to qualify for
services underNRS 427A.250to427A.280, inclusive.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-259__subsec_8">
            <num>8.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An agreement entered into or decree
entered pursuant to this section may not be binding on the Division of Welfare
and Supportive Services of the Department of Health and Human Services in
making determinations under the State Plan for Medicaid.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="123-259__subsec_9">
            <num>9.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, ï¿½community
spouseï¿½ and ï¿½institutionalized spouseï¿½ have the meanings respectively ascribed
to them in 42 U.S.C. ï¿½ 1396r-5</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="123-259__subsec_9__subsec_h">
              <num>(h)</num>
              <content>
                <p>.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1987,
1016; A1989,
380,1005;1993,
2412;1997,
1248;2009,
1257;2017,
763)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-270">
          <num>123.270</num>
          <heading>Contracts or settlements to be written and acknowledged.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>All marriage contracts or settlements must be
in writing, and executed and acknowledged or proved in like manner as a
conveyance of land is required to be executed and acknowledged or proved.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [27:119:1873; B ï¿½ 177; BH ï¿½ 525; C ï¿½ 536; RL ï¿½ 2181;
NCL ï¿½ 3381]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-280">
          <num>123.280</num>
          <heading>Recording in counties where real property situated.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>When such marriage contract or settlement is
acknowledged or proved, it must be recorded in the office of the recorder of
every county in which any real property may be situated which is conveyed or
affected by such contract.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [28:119:1873; B ï¿½ 178; BH ï¿½ 526; C ï¿½ 537; RL ï¿½ 2182;
NCL ï¿½ 3382]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-290">
          <num>123.290</num>
          <heading>Record of contract to impart notice.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>When
such marriage contract or settlement is deposited in the recorderï¿½s office for
record, it shall, as to all property affected thereby in the county where the
same is deposited, impart full notice to all persons of the contents thereof.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [29:119:1873; B ï¿½ 179; BH ï¿½ 527; C ï¿½ 538; RL ï¿½ 2183;
NCL ï¿½ 3383]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-300">
          <num>123.300</num>
          <heading>Effect of not recording contract or settlement.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>No such marriage contract or settlement shall
be valid as to any real property, or affect the same, except as between the
parties thereto, until it shall be deposited for record with the recorder of
the county in which such real property is situate.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [30:119:1873; B ï¿½ 180; BH ï¿½ 528; C ï¿½ 539; RL ï¿½ 2184;
NCL ï¿½ 3384]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_123-310">
          <num>123.310</num>
          <heading>Minors may make marriage contracts or settlements.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>A minor capable of contracting marriage may
make a valid marriage contract or settlement.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [31:119:1873; B ï¿½ 181; BH ï¿½ 529; C ï¿½ 540; RL ï¿½ 2185;
NCL ï¿½ 3385]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>