<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="NRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-160"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-160"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#nevada-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-nv"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="160"/>
          <FRBRname value="NRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-160/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-160/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-160/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-160/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="nevada-legislature" href="https://www.leg.state.nv.us" showAs="Nevada State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_160">
        <num>160</num>
        <heading>VETERANSï¿½ GUARDIANSHIP</heading>
        <section eId="sec_160-010">
          <num>160.010</num>
          <heading>Short title.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>This
chapter may be cited as the Uniform Veteransï¿½ Guardianship Act.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [18:28:1929; NCL ï¿½ 9565]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_160-020">
          <num>160.020</num>
          <heading>Definitions.</heading>
          <subsection eId="160-020__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>ï¿½Benefitsï¿½ means all money payable by
the United States through the Department of Veterans Affairs.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="160-020__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>ï¿½Department of Veterans Affairsï¿½ means
the Department of Veterans Affairs, its predecessors or successors.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="160-020__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>ï¿½Estateï¿½ and ï¿½incomeï¿½ include only
money received by the guardian from the Department of Veterans Affairs and all
earnings, interest and profits derived therefrom.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="160-020__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>ï¿½Guardianï¿½ means any person acting as a
fiduciary for a ward.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="160-020__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>ï¿½Secretaryï¿½ means the Secretary of
Veterans Affairs of the United States or the Secretaryï¿½s successor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="160-020__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>ï¿½Wardï¿½ means a beneficiary of the
Department of Veterans Affairs.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1:28:1929; NCL ï¿½ 9548]—(NRS A1985,
508;1995,
1078)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_160-030">
          <num>160.030</num>
          <heading>Applicability.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever,
pursuant to any law of the United States or regulation of the Department of
Veterans Affairs, the Secretary requires the appointment of a guardian for a
ward before the payment of benefits, the appointment must be made in the manner
provided in this chapter.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [2:28:1929; NCL ï¿½ 9549]—(NRS A1995,
1078)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_160-040">
          <num>160.040</num>
          <heading>Limitation on number of wards; exceptions.</heading>
          <subsection eId="160-040__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in this
section, it is unlawful for any person to accept appointment as guardian of any
ward if the proposed guardian is at that time acting as guardian for five
wards. In any case, upon presentation of a petition by an attorney of the
Department of Veterans Affairs pursuant to this section alleging that a
guardian is acting in a fiduciary capacity for more than five wards and
requesting his or her discharge for that reason, the court, upon proof substantiating
the petition, shall require a final accounting from the guardian and shall
discharge the guardian in the case.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="160-040__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The limitations of this section do not
apply where the guardian is a bank or trust company acting for the wardsï¿½
estates only.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="160-040__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An individual may be guardian of more
than five wards if they are all members of the same family.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="160-040__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The limitations of this section do not
apply to a public guardian.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [3:28:1929; NCL ï¿½ 9550]—(NRS A1961,
32;1977,
488;1995,
1078;1999,
2477;2017,
383)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_160-050">
          <num>160.050</num>
          <heading>Appointment of guardian.</heading>
          <subsection eId="160-050__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A petition for the appointment of a
guardian may be filed in any court of competent jurisdiction by or on behalf of
any person who under existing law is entitled to priority of appointment. If
there is no person so entitled or if the person so entitled neglects or refuses
to file such a petition within 30 days after the mailing of notice by the
Department of Veterans Affairs to the last known address of such person
indicating the necessity for the same, a petition for such appointment may be
filed in any court of competent jurisdiction by or on behalf of any responsible
person residing in this State.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="160-050__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The petition for appointment must set
forth the name, age and place of residence of the ward, the names and places of
residence of the nearest relatives, if known, and the fact that the ward is
entitled to receive money payable by or through the Department of Veterans
Affairs, and must set forth the amount of money then due and the amount of
probable future payments.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="160-050__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The petition must also set forth the
name and address of the person or institution, if any, having actual custody of
the ward.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="160-050__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In case of a mentally incompetent ward
the petition must show that such ward has been rated incompetent on examination
by the Department of Veterans Affairs in accordance with the laws and
regulations governing the Department of Veterans Affairs.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [4:28:1929; NCL ï¿½ 9551]—(NRS A1995,
1079)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_160-060">
          <num>160.060</num>
          <heading>Evidence of necessity for guardian for minor.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If a petition is filed for the appointment of
a guardian of a minor ward, a certificate of the Secretary or a representative
of the Secretary, setting forth the age of such minor as shown by the records
of the Department of Veterans Affairs and the fact that the appointment of a
guardian is a condition precedent to the payment of any money due the minor by
the Department of Veterans Affairs, constitutes prima facie evidence of the
necessity for such appointment.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [5:28:1929; NCL ï¿½ 9552]—(NRS A1995,
1079)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_160-070">
          <num>160.070</num>
          <heading>Evidence of necessity for guardian for incompetent.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If a petition is filed for the appointment of
a guardian of a mentally incompetent ward, a certificate of the Secretary or a
representative of the Secretary, setting forth the fact that such person has
been rated incompetent by the Department of Veterans Affairs on examination in
accordance with the laws and regulations governing the Department of Veterans
Affairs and that the appointment of a guardian is a condition precedent to the
payment of any money due such person by the Department of Veterans Affairs,
constitutes prima facie evidence of the necessity for such appointment.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [6:28:1929; NCL ï¿½ 9553]—(NRS A1995,
1079)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_160-080">
          <num>160.080</num>
          <heading>Notice.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Upon the
filing of a petition for the appointment of a guardian under the provisions of
this chapter, the court shall cause such notice to be given as provided by law.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [7:28:1929; NCL ï¿½ 9554]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_160-090">
          <num>160.090</num>
          <heading>Bond.</heading>
          <subsection eId="160-090__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Before making an appointment under the
provisions of this chapter, the court shall establish to its satisfaction that
the person whose appointment as guardian is sought is a fit and proper person
to be appointed.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="160-090__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon the appointment being made, the
guardian shall, except as otherwise provided in this section, execute and file
a bond to be approved by the court in an amount not less than the value of the
personal property of the estate plus the anticipated annual income. Thereafter,
the amount of the bond must be equal to the total value of the personal estate
plus the annual income. The bond must be in the form and be conditioned as
required of guardians appointed pursuant to the provisions ofchapter 159or159Aof NRS. The premiums on all such bonds must be paid from the estate.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="160-090__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a banking corporation as defined inNRS 657.016, or a trust company, as defined
byNRS 669.070, doing business in this state
is appointed guardian of the estate of a ward, no bond is required of the
guardian unless the court by specific order requires a bond.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="160-090__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the court orders that the estate and
income, or a part thereof, be deposited in a banking corporation, as defined inNRS 657.016, or trust company, as
defined byNRS 669.070, doing business
in this state and that such estate and income, or any part thereof, must not be
withdrawn without authorization of the court, then the amount of the guardianï¿½s
bond must be reduced in an amount equal to the amount of the estate and income
on deposit with the banking corporation, and the surety on the bonds must be
exonerated from any loss to the estate in connection with the deposit.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="160-090__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Where a bond is tendered by a guardian
with personal sureties, the sureties shall file with the court a certificate
under oath which describes the property owned, both real and personal, and
contains a statement that they are each worth the sum named in the bond as the
penalty thereof over and above all their debts and liabilities and exclusive of
property exempt from execution.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [8:28:1929; NCL ï¿½ 9555]—(NRS A1959,
65;1969,
1190;1971,
1010;1977,
640;1999,
2478;2017,
383,887)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_160-100">
          <num>160.100</num>
          <heading>Accounts.</heading>
          <subsection eId="160-100__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every guardian who receives on account
of a ward of the guardian any money from the Department of Veterans Affairs
shall file with the court annually, on the anniversary date of the appointment,
in addition to such other accounts as may be required by the court, a full,
true and accurate account under oath of all money so received by the guardian
and of all disbursements thereof, and showing the balance thereof in the hands
of the guardian at the date of such account and how invested.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="160-100__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A certified copy of each of such
accounts filed with the court must be sent by the guardian to the office of the
Department of Veterans Affairs having jurisdiction over the area in which the
court is located. The court shall fix a time and place for the hearing on such
account not less than 15 days or more than 30 days after the date of filing the
account, and notice thereof must be given by the court to the concerned office
of the Department of Veterans Affairs not less than 15 days before the date
fixed for the hearing.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="160-100__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notice of such hearing must in like
manner be given to the guardian.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [9:28:1929; NCL ï¿½ 9556]—(NRS A1995,
1080)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_160-110">
          <num>160.110</num>
          <heading>Penalty for failure to account.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If
any guardian fails to file any account of the money received by the guardian
from the Department of Veterans Affairs on account of a ward of the guardian
within 30 days after such account is required by either the court or the
Department of Veterans Affairs, or fails to furnish the Department of Veterans
Affairs with a copy of the accounts of the guardian as required by this
chapter, such failure constitutes grounds for removal.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [10:28:1929; NCL ï¿½ 9557]—(NRS A1995,
1080)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_160-120">
          <num>160.120</num>
          <heading>Compensation of guardian.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Compensation
payable to a guardian must not exceed 5 percent of the income of the ward
during any year. In the event of extraordinary services rendered by any
guardian, the court may, upon petition and after hearing thereon, authorize
additional compensation therefor payable from the estate of the ward. Notice of
such petition and hearing must be given to the proper office of the Department
of Veterans Affairs in the manner provided inNRS
160.100. No compensation may be allowed on the corpus of an estate received
from a preceding guardian. The guardian may be allowed from the estate of the
ward of the guardian reasonable premiums paid by him or her to any corporate
surety upon his or her bond.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [11:28:1929; NCL ï¿½ 9558]—(NRS A1995,
1080)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_160-130">
          <num>160.130</num>
          <heading>Investments.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Every
guardian shall invest the funds of the estate in such manner or in such
securities, in which the guardian has no interest, as allowed by law or
approved by the court.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [12:28:1929; NCL ï¿½ 9559]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_160-140">
          <num>160.140</num>
          <heading>Maintenance and support.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>A
guardian shall not apply any portion of the estate of a ward of the guardian
for the support and maintenance of any person other than the ward, except upon
order of the court after a hearing, notice of which has been given to the
proper office of the Department of Veterans Affairs in the manner provided inNRS 160.100.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [13:28:1929; NCL ï¿½ 9560]—(NRS A1995,
1080)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_160-150">
          <num>160.150</num>
          <heading>Copies of public records to be furnished.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>When a copy of any public record is required
by the Department of Veterans Affairs to be used in determining the eligibility
of any person to participate in benefits made available by the Department of
Veterans Affairs, the official charged with the custody of such public record
shall without charge provide the applicant for such benefits or any person
acting on behalf of the applicant or the representative of the Department of
Veterans Affairs with a certified copy of such record.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [14:28:1929; NCL ï¿½ 9561]—(NRS A1995,
1081)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_160-160">
          <num>160.160</num>
          <heading>Commitment to Department of Veterans Affairs or other federal
agency.</heading>
          <subsection eId="160-160__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In any proceeding under the laws of
this State for involuntary court-ordered admission of a person alleged to be
mentally ill or otherwise in need of confinement in a hospital or other
institution for his or her care, the court may order the admission of that
person to the Department of Veterans Affairs or another agency of the Federal
Government, whenever:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="160-160__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>It is determined, after such adjudication of
the status of that person as may be required bychapter
433Aof NRS, that involuntary court-ordered admission to a hospital for
mental disease or another institution is necessary for safekeeping or
treatment; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="160-160__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>It appears that the person is eligible for
care or treatment by the Department of Veterans Affairs or any other agency
that has facilities available and that the person is eligible for care or
treatment therein.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="160-160__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The person whose involuntary
court-ordered admission is sought must be personally served with notice of the
pending proceeding in the manner provided bychapter
433Aof NRS. This chapter does not affect that personï¿½s right to appear and
be heard in the proceedings.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [15:28:1929; NCL ï¿½ 9562]—(NRS A1957,
660;1975,
1632;1985,
2274;1995,
1081)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_160-161">
          <num>160.161</num>
          <heading>Regulations of Department of Veterans Affairs or other federal
agency; powers of officer; jurisdiction of court.</heading>
          <subsection eId="160-161__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon commitment, a person is subject to
the rules and regulations of the Department of Veterans Affairs or other agency
when admitted to any facility operated by any such agency within or without
this state.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="160-161__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The chief officer of any facility of
the Department of Veterans Affairs or institution operated by any other agency
of the United States to which the person is so committed is, with respect to
that person, vested with the same powers as the Director and the Medical
Director of Northern Nevada Adult Mental Health Services with respect to
retention of custody, transfer, parole or discharge.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="160-161__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The committing court shall retain
jurisdiction:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="160-161__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>To inquire, at any time, into the mental
condition of persons so committed.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="160-161__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>To determine the necessity for the
continuance of the personï¿½s restraint.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1957,
660; A1973,
92,1218;1995,
1081;2001,
1116)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_160-162">
          <num>160.162</num>
          <heading>Transfer of person from Northern Nevada Adult Mental Health
Services to Department of Veterans Affairs or other federal agency.</heading>
          <subsection eId="160-162__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon receipt of a certificate of the
Department of Veterans Affairs or another agency of the United States that
facilities are available for the care or treatment of any person previously
committed to the custody of Northern Nevada Adult Mental Health Services and
that the person is eligible for care or treatment, the Director of Northern
Nevada Adult Mental Health Services may cause the transfer of the person to the
Department of Veterans Affairs or other agency of the United States for care or
treatment.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="160-162__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The committing court must be notified
by the Director of Northern Nevada Adult Mental Health Services upon effecting
such a transfer.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="160-162__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>No person may be transferred to the
Department of Veterans Affairs or such other agency of the United States if the
person is confined pursuant to a conviction of a felony or misdemeanor or if
the person has been acquitted of the charge solely on the ground of insanity,
unless before the transfer the court originally committing the person enters an
order for the transfer after appropriate motion and hearing.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="160-162__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person transferred as provided in
this section shall be deemed to be committed to the Department of Veterans
Affairs or other agency of the United States pursuant to the original
commitment.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1957,
661; A1973,
92,1219;1995,
1081;2001,
1116)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_160-170">
          <num>160.170</num>
          <heading>Discharge of guardian.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>When
a minor ward for whom a guardian has been appointed under the provisions of
this chapter or other laws of this state attains his or her majority, and if
incompetent is declared competent by the Department of Veterans Affairs and the
court, and when any incompetent ward, not a minor, is declared competent by the
Department of Veterans Affairs and the court, the guardian must, upon making a
satisfactory accounting, be discharged upon a petition filed for that purpose.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [16:28:1929; NCL ï¿½ 9563]—(NRS A1995,
1082)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_160-180">
          <num>160.180</num>
          <heading>Liberal construction.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>This
chapter must be construed liberally to secure the beneficial intents and
purposes thereof and applies only to beneficiaries of the Department of
Veterans Affairs.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [17:28:1929; NCL ï¿½ 9564]—(NRS A1995,
1082)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_160-190">
          <num>160.190</num>
          <heading>Uniformity of interpretation.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>This
chapter shall be so interpreted and construed as to effectuate its general
purpose to make uniform the law of those states which enact it.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [19:28:1929; NCL ï¿½ 9566]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>