<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="NRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-484E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-484E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#nevada-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-nv"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="484E"/>
          <FRBRname value="NRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-484E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-484E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-484E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-484E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="nevada-legislature" href="https://www.leg.state.nv.us" showAs="Nevada State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_484E">
        <num>484E</num>
        <heading>CRASHES AND REPORTS OF</heading>
        <section eId="sec_484E-010">
          <num>484E.010</num>
          <heading>Duty to stop at scene of crash involving death or personal
injury; penalty.</heading>
          <subsection eId="484E-010__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The driver of any vehicle involved in a
crash on a highway or on premises to which the public has access resulting in
bodily injury to or the death of a person shall immediately stop his or her
vehicle at the scene of the crash or as close thereto as possible, and shall
forthwith return to and in every event shall remain at the scene of the crash
until the driver has fulfilled the requirements ofNRS 484E.030.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-010__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every such stop must be made without
obstructing traffic more than is necessary.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-010__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person failing to comply with the
provisions of subsection 1 is guilty of a category B felony and shall be
punished by imprisonment in the state prison for a minimum term of not less
than 2 years and a maximum term of not more than 20 years and by a fine of not
less than $2,000 nor more than $5,000. A person failing to comply with the
provisions of subsection 1 commits a separate offense under this section for
the bodily injury to or the death of each person that results from a crash with
regard to which the person failed to comply with the provisions of subsection
1.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-010__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A sentence imposed pursuant to
subsection 3 may not be suspended nor may probation be granted.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
1482; A1979,
1484;1983,
1066;1993,
2135;1995,
1297;2015,
1365,1641)—(Substituted
in revision for NRS 484.219)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_484E-020">
          <num>484E.020</num>
          <heading>Duty to stop at scene of crash involving damage to vehicle or
property; duty to move vehicle under certain circumstances; penalty.</heading>
          <subsection eId="484E-020__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The driver of any vehicle involved in a
crash resulting only in damage to a vehicle or other property which is driven
or attended by any person shall:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="484E-020__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Immediately stop his or her vehicle at the
scene of the crash; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="484E-020__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the driverï¿½s vehicle is creating a hazard
or obstructing traffic and can be moved safely, move the vehicle or cause the
vehicle to be moved out of the traffic lanes of the roadway to a safe location
that does not create a hazard or obstruct traffic and, if applicable, safely
fulfill the requirements ofNRS 484E.030.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-020__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who violates this section is
guilty of a misdemeanor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
1483; A1997,
2798;2007,
77;2015,
1642;2017,
1296;2021,
3343)—(Substituted in revision for NRS 484.221)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_484E-030">
          <num>484E.030</num>
          <heading>Duty to give information and render aid; report if no police
officer present; penalty.</heading>
          <subsection eId="484E-030__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The driver of any vehicle involved in a
crash resulting in injury to or death of any person or damage to any vehicle or
other property which is driven or attended by any person shall:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="484E-030__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Give his or her name, address and the
registration number of the vehicle the driver is driving, and shall upon
request and if available exhibit his or her license to operate a motor vehicle
to any person injured in such crash or to the driver or occupant of or person
attending any vehicle or other property damaged in such crash;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="484E-030__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Give such information and upon request
manually surrender such license to any police officer at the scene of the crash
or who is investigating the crash; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="484E-030__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Render to any person injured in such crash
reasonable assistance, including the carrying, or the making of arrangements
for the carrying, of such person to a physician, surgeon or hospital for
medical or surgical treatment if it is apparent that such treatment is
necessary, or if such carrying is requested by the injured person.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-030__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If no police officer is present, the
driver of any vehicle involved in such crash after fulfilling all other
requirements of subsection 1 andNRS
484E.010, insofar as possible on his or her part to be performed, shall
forthwith report such crash to the nearest office of a police authority or of
the Nevada Highway Patrol and submit thereto the information specified in
subsection 1.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-030__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who violates this section is
guilty of a misdemeanor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
1483; A2015,
1642;2021,
3343)—(Substituted in revision for NRS 484.223)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_484E-040">
          <num>484E.040</num>
          <heading>Duty upon damaging unattended vehicle or other property;
penalty.</heading>
          <subsection eId="484E-040__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 2, the driver of any vehicle which is involved in a crash with any
vehicle or other property which is unattended, resulting in any damage to such
other vehicle or property, shall immediately stop and shall then and there
locate and notify the operator or owner of such vehicle or other property of
the name and address of the driver and owner of the vehicle striking the
unattended vehicle or other property or shall attach securely in a conspicuous
place in or on such vehicle or property a written notice giving the name and
address of the driver and of the owner of the vehicle doing the striking.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-040__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the vehicle of a driver involved in
a crash pursuant to subsection 1 is creating a hazard or obstructing traffic
and can be moved safely, the driver shall, before meeting the requirements of
subsection 1, move the vehicle or cause the vehicle to be moved out of the
traffic lanes of the roadway to a safe location that does not create a hazard
or obstruct traffic and minimizes interference with the free movement of
traffic.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-040__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who violates this section is
guilty of a misdemeanor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
1483; A2015,
1642;2017,
1297;2021,
3343)—(Substituted in revision for NRS 484.225)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_484E-050">
          <num>484E.050</num>
          <heading>Immediate notice to police officer of crash involving unattended
vehicle or other property; penalty.</heading>
          <subsection eId="484E-050__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The driver of a vehicle which is
involved in a crash with any vehicle or other property which is unattended,
resulting in any damage to such other vehicle or property, shall immediately by
the quickest means of communication give notice of such crash to the nearest
office of a police authority or of the Nevada Highway Patrol.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-050__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Whenever the driver of a vehicle is
physically incapable of giving an immediate notice of a crash as required in
subsection 1 and there was another occupant in the vehicle at the time of the
crash capable of doing so, such occupant shall make or cause to be given the
notice not given by the driver.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-050__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who violates this section is
guilty of a misdemeanor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
1483; A2015,
1643;2021,
3344)—(Substituted in revision for NRS 484.227)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_484E-060">
          <num>484E.060</num>
          <heading>Seizure and impoundment of vehicle for failure to surrender
license plates and certificate of registration upon suspension of registration.</heading>
          <subsection eId="484E-060__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A peace officer at the scene of a crash
involving a motor vehicle shall, by radio, request that the information on file
with the Department be checked regarding the validity of the registration for
each motor vehicle involved in the crash. If the peace officer is informed that
the registration of a motor vehicle involved in the crash has been suspended pursuant
to any provision ofchapter 485of NRS, the
peace officer shall determine whether the license plates and certificate of
registration for the motor vehicle have been surrendered as required byNRS 485.320. If the license plates and
certificate have not been surrendered, the peace officer shall:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="484E-060__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Issue a traffic citation in the manner
provided inNRS 484A.630charging the
registered owner with a violation ofNRS
485.320and485.330; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="484E-060__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Without a warrant, seize and take possession
of the motor vehicle and cause it to be towed and impounded until the owner
claims it by:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="484E-060__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Presenting proof that the vehicleï¿½s
registration has been reinstated by the Department; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="484E-060__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Paying the cost of the towing and
impoundment.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-060__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Neither the peace officer nor the
governmental entity which employs the peace officer is civilly liable for any
damage to the vehicle that occurs after the vehicle is seized, but before the
towing process begins.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1987,
319; A2015,
1643)—(Substituted in revision for NRS 484.228)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_484E-070">
          <num>484E.070</num>
          <heading>Written or electronic report of crash to Department by driver or
owner; exceptions; confidentiality; use as evidence at trial.</heading>
          <subsection eId="484E-070__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department shall:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="484E-070__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Approve the format of the forms for crash
reports made pursuant to this section; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="484E-070__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Make those forms available to persons who are
required to forward the reports to the Department pursuant to this section.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-070__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsections 3, 4 and 5, the driver of a vehicle which is in any manner involved
in a crash on a highway or on premises to which the public has access, if the
crash results in bodily injury to or the death of any person or total damage to
any vehicle or item of property to an apparent extent of $750 or more, shall,
within 10 days after the crash, forward a written or electronic report of the
crash to the Department. Whenever damage occurs to a motor vehicle, the
operator shall attach to the crash report an estimate of repairs or a statement
of the total loss from an established repair garage, an insurance adjuster
employed by an insurer licensed to do business in this State, an adjuster
licensed pursuant tochapter 684Aof NRS or
an appraiser licensed pursuant tochapter 684Bof NRS. The Department may require the driver or owner of the vehicle to file
supplemental written or electronic reports whenever the original report is
insufficient in the opinion of the Department.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-070__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A report is not required from any
person if the crash was investigated by a police officer pursuant toNRS 484E.110and the report of the
investigating officer contains:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="484E-070__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The name and address of the insurance company
providing coverage to each person involved in the crash;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="484E-070__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The number of each policy; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="484E-070__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The dates on which the coverage begins and
ends.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-070__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The driver of a vehicle subject to the
jurisdiction of the Surface Transportation Board or the Nevada Transportation
Authority need not submit in his or her report the information requested
pursuant to subsection 3 ofNRS 484E.120until the 10th day of the month following the month in which the crash
occurred.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-070__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A written or electronic crash report is
not required pursuant to this chapter from any person who is physically
incapable of making a report, during the period of the personï¿½s incapacity.
Whenever the driver is physically incapable of making a written or electronic
report of a crash as required in this section and the driver is not the owner
of the vehicle, the owner shall within 10 days after knowledge of the crash
make the report not made by the driver.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-070__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>All written or electronic reports
required in this section to be forwarded to the Department by drivers or owners
of vehicles involved in crashes are without prejudice to the person so
reporting and are for the confidential use of the Department or other state
agencies having use of the records for crash prevention, except as otherwise
provided inNRS 239.0115and except
that the Department may disclose to a person involved in a crash or to his or
her insurer the identity of another person involved in the crash when the
personï¿½s identity is not otherwise known or when the person denies having been
present at the crash. The Department may also disclose the name of the personï¿½s
insurer and the number of the personï¿½s policy.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-070__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A written or electronic report
forwarded pursuant to the provisions of this section may not be used as
evidence in any trial, civil or criminal, arising out of a crash except that
the Department shall furnish upon demand of any party to such a trial, or upon
demand of any court, a certificate showing that a specified crash report has or
has not been made to the Department in compliance with law, and, if the report
has been made, the date, time and location of the crash, the names and
addresses of the drivers, the owners of the vehicles involved and the
investigating officers. The report may be used as evidence when necessary to
prosecute charges filed in connection with a violation ofNRS 484E.080.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
1484; A1981,
1126,1865;1983,
1067;1985,
1174,1943;1995,
2732;1997,
1620,2008;2007,
2117;2013,
542;2015,
1643)—(Substituted in revision for NRS 484.229)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_484E-080">
          <num>484E.080</num>
          <heading>Failure to report; false report; penalties.</heading>
          <subsection eId="484E-080__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a person willfully fails, refuses or
neglects to make a report of a crash in accordance with the provisions of this
chapter, the personï¿½s driving privilege may be suspended. Suspension action
taken under this section remains in effect for 1 year unless terminated by
receipt of the report of the crash or upon receipt of evidence that failure to
report was not willful.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-080__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person who gives information in
electronic, oral or written reports as required in this chapter, knowing or
having reason to believe that such information is false, is guilty of a gross
misdemeanor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
1484; A1981,
1127;2013,
543;2015,
1644)—(Substituted in revision for NRS 484.236)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_484E-090">
          <num>484E.090</num>
          <heading>State Registrar of Vital Statistics to report death to
Department.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The State Registrar of
Vital Statistics shall on or before the 10th day of each month report in
writing to the Department the death of any person resulting from a vehicle
crash, giving the time and place of the crash and the circumstances relating
thereto.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
1484; A1985,
1944;2015,
1645)—(Substituted in revision for NRS 484.238)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_484E-100">
          <num>484E.100</num>
          <heading>Garage or repair shop to maintain record of repairs made to
vehicle involved in crash.</heading>
          <subsection eId="484E-100__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Registration number of the vehicle;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-100__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Vehicle identification number;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-100__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Color of the vehicle before the
repairs;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-100__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Location on the vehicle of the damage
repaired;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-100__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Total amount of the damage; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-100__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Name and address of the person who
requested the repairs.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
1484; A1975,
142;1987,
685;2015,
1645)—(Substituted in revision for NRS 484.241)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_484E-110">
          <num>484E.110</num>
          <heading>Police to report to Department of Public Safety; report not
confidential; requirements for preparation of report; submission of copy of
report to Department of Motor Vehicles.</heading>
          <subsection eId="484E-110__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every police officer who investigates a
vehicle crash of which a report must be made as required in this chapter, or
who otherwise prepares a written or electronic report as a result of an investigation
either at the time of and at the scene of the crash or thereafter by
interviewing the participants or witnesses, shall forward a written or
electronic report of the crash to the Department of Public Safety within 10
days after the investigation of the crash. The data collected by the Department
of Public Safety pursuant to this subsection must be recorded in a central
repository created by the Department of Public Safety to track data
electronically concerning vehicle crashes on a statewide basis.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-110__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The written or electronic reports
required to be forwarded by police officers and the information contained
therein are not privileged or confidential.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-110__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every sheriff, chief of police or
office of the Nevada Highway Patrol receiving any report required underNRS 484E.030to484E.090, inclusive, shall immediately
prepare a copy thereof and file the copy with the Department of Public Safety.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-110__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a police officer investigates a
vehicle crash resulting in bodily injury to or the death of any person or total
damage to any vehicle or item of property to an apparent extent of $750 or
more, the police officer shall prepare a written or electronic report of the
investigation.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-110__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As soon as practicable after receiving
a report pursuant to this section, the Department of Public Safety shall submit
a copy of the report to the Department of Motor Vehicles.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
1485; A1985,
1945;1987,
685;2013,
544;2015,
1645)—(Substituted in revision for NRS 484.243)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_484E-120">
          <num>484E.120</num>
          <heading>Forms for report of crash; duties of Department of Public
Safety.</heading>
          <subsection eId="484E-120__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department of Public Safety shall
prepare forms for crash reports required pursuant toNRS 484E.110, suitable with respect to
the persons required to make the reports and the purposes to be served. The
forms must be designed to call for sufficiently detailed information to
disclose with reference to a crash the cause, conditions then existing, the
persons and vehicles involved, the name and address of the insurance company,
the number of the policy providing coverage and the dates on which the coverage
begins and ends. The Department of Public Safety shall, upon request, supply to
a police department, sheriff or other appropriate agency or person, the forms
for crash reports prepared by a police officer pursuant toNRS 484E.110.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-120__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In addition to submitting a copy of a
report pursuant toNRS 484E.110, the
Department of Public Safety shall provide any information required by this
section which is not included in the report to the Department of Motor Vehicles
to enable the Department of Motor Vehicles to determine whether the
requirements for the deposit of security underchapter
485of NRS are inapplicable. The Department of Motor Vehicles may rely upon
the accuracy of information supplied to a police officer by a driver or owner
on the form unless it has reason to believe that the information is erroneous.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-120__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every crash report required pursuant toNRS 484E.070must be made on the
appropriate form approved by the Department of Motor Vehicles pursuant to that
section and must contain all the information required in the form.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="484E-120__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every crash report required pursuant toNRS 484E.110must be made on the
appropriate form approved by the Department of Public Safety and must contain
all the information required therein unless it is not available.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
1485; A1981,
1127;1985,
1175,1945;1999,
3578;2013,
544;2015,
1645)—(Substituted in revision for NRS 484.247)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_484E-130">
          <num>484E.130</num>
          <heading>Department to tabulate and analyze reports.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The Department shall tabulate and analyze all
crash reports received in compliance with this chapter and shall publish
annually, or at more frequent intervals, statistical information based thereon
as to the number and circumstances of vehicle crashes.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
1485; A1985,
1945;2015,
1646)—(Substituted in revision for NRS 484.249)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>