<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="NRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-154"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-154"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#nevada-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-nv"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="154"/>
          <FRBRname value="NRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-154/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-154/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-154/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-154/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="nevada-legislature" href="https://www.leg.state.nv.us" showAs="Nevada State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_154">
        <num>154</num>
        <heading>ESCHEATS</heading>
        <section eId="sec_154-010">
          <num>154.010</num>
          <heading>When estates escheat; escheated estates must be used for
educational purposes.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>An estate
escheats to and is vested in the State of Nevada for educational purposes if
any person dies or has died, within this State, seised of any real or personal
estate, and leaving no heirs, representatives or devisees capable of inheriting
or holding the estate, and in all cases where there is no owner of the estate
capable of holding it. Any balance remaining in a retired employeeï¿½s or
beneficiaryï¿½s individual account under the Public Employeesï¿½ Retirement System
or the Judicial Retirement System established pursuant tochapter 1Aof NRS is not an estate within the
meaning of this chapter.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [311:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.311]—(NRS A1977,
1598;1999,
2354;2001
Special Session, 93)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_154-015">
          <num>154.015</num>
          <heading>Payments or deliveries by personal representative to State
Treasurer: Filing of receipt or certificate; release of liability of personal
representative.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If a personal
representative, on order of the court, pays over or delivers to the State
Treasurer property which has become escheatable to the State, the receipt or
certificate of the State Treasurer evidencing the payment or delivery must be
filed with the clerk of the district court in the county in which the estate is
being administered or is located. Upon filing of the receipt or certificate,
the personal representative is released from all further liability relating to
the property.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1999,
2353)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_154-020">
          <num>154.020</num>
          <heading>Information filed by Attorney General: Contents.</heading>
          <subsection eId="154-020__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the Attorney General is informed, or
has reason to believe, that any real or personal property has become
escheatable to this State for the reasons specified inNRS 154.010, or that any such property has,
for any other reason, become escheatable, the Attorney General shall file an
information on behalf of the State in the district court of the county where
the property, or any part thereof, is located.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-020__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The information must set forth:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="154-020__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A description of the property.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="154-020__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The name of the person last lawfully seised.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="154-020__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The name of the persons holding, possessing
or claiming the property, if known.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="154-020__subsec_2__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The facts and circumstances giving rise to
the claim for escheatment.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-020__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The information must allege that the
State of Nevada has by law the right to the property.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 312:107:1941; A1951,
19]—(NRS A1999,
2354)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_154-030">
          <num>154.030</num>
          <heading>Citation: Issuance; publication.</heading>
          <subsection eId="154-030__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon the filing of the information, the
court shall order that a citation be issued to the person or persons alleged in
the information to hold, possess or claim the property, requiring them to
appear and show cause why the property should not vest in the State of Nevada.
Unless the court otherwise orders, the citation must be made returnable at
least 20 days after its service.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-030__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court may also, if deemed
advisable, order the citation to be published in a newspaper published in the
county where the administration is pending, if any, and, if none, then in some
newspaper in this State.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 312:107:1941; A1951,
19]—(NRS A1999,
2354)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_154-040">
          <num>154.040</num>
          <heading>Receiver: Appointment on petition of Attorney General after
filing of information; bond.</heading>
          <subsection eId="154-040__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>After the filing of an information as
provided inNRS 154.020, and upon
petition of the Attorney General, either before or after answer, upon notice to
the person or persons holding, possessing or claiming the property, if known,
the court may, on sufficient cause therefor being shown, appoint a receiver to
take charge of the real estate or personal property, other than money,
mentioned in the information, and receive the rents and profits of the property
until the title of the property is finally settled.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-040__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The receiver shall, before entering
upon his or her duties, execute a bond to the State of Nevada in a sum to be
fixed by the court, with sureties to be approved by the court, conditioned to
perform faithfully the duties of the trust and to account fully to the person
finally determined to be entitled to the property. That person may maintain an
action on the bond for any default or damage.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [316:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.316]—(NRS A1999,
2354)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_154-060">
          <num>154.060</num>
          <heading>Claimants may appear and plead to information.</heading>
          <subsection eId="154-060__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>All persons named in the information
may appear and plead to the proceedings, and may traverse or deny the facts
stated in the information and the title of the State to the estate at any time
on or before the return day of the citation.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-060__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any other person claiming an interest
in the property may appear and be made a defendant, and plead as stated in
subsection 1 by petition for that purpose filed within the time allowed for
pleading.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-060__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any person appears and pleads as
stated in subsections 1 and 2, denying the title claimed by the State, or
traverses any material fact set forth in the information, or issue or issues of
fact to be made up, the matter must proceed as other civil actions on issues of
fact.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-060__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A survey may be ordered, as in other
civil actions, if the boundary is called into question.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 313:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.313]—(NRS A1999,
2355)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_154-070">
          <num>154.070</num>
          <heading>Judgment and costs.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>After
the issues are tried, if it shall appear from the facts that the State has a
good title to the estate mentioned in the information, or any part thereof, or
if no defense be made by anyone, judgment shall be rendered that the State be
seised thereof, and recover costs of suit against the defendants, if any
appear.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 313:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.313]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_154-080">
          <num>154.080</num>
          <heading>Sale of real property after judgment: Procedure.</heading>
          <subsection eId="154-080__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon any judgment entered by a court of
competent jurisdiction, escheating real property to the State, on petition of
the Attorney General, or on petition of a personal representative of the
estate, the court shall, or the court may upon its own motion, enter an order
that the real property be sold by the sheriff of the county where the property
is situated, at public sale, after giving notice of the time and place of sale
as is provided in cases of sale of property under execution.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-080__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The sheriff shall, within 10 days after
the sale, submit a report thereof to the court. Upon the hearing of the report,
the court may examine the report and any witnesses, and if the proceedings were
unfair, or the sum bid is disproportionate to the value of the property sold,
or if it appears that a sum exceeding the bid by at least 5 percent may be
obtained, the court may vacate the sale and direct another sale to be conducted
in all respects as if no previous sale had taken place.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-080__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If an offer of 5 percent more in amount
than that named in the report is made to the court in writing by a responsible
person, the court may accept that offer and confirm the sale, or order a new
sale.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-080__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If it appears to the court that the
sale was legally made and fairly conducted, and that the sum bid is not
disproportionate to the value of the property sold, and that a sum in excess of
5 percent more than the bid cannot be obtained, or if an increased bid was
accepted by the court, the court shall enter an order confirming the sale and
directing the sheriff, in the name of the State, to execute to the purchaser a
conveyance of the property sold. The conveyance vests in the purchaser all the
right and title of the State therein.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-080__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The sheriff shall, out of the proceeds
of the sale, pay the costs of the proceedings incurred on behalf of the State,
including the expenses of making the sale, and also an attorneyï¿½s fee, if
additional counsel was employed in the proceedings, to be fixed by the court.
The sheriff shall deposit the remaining proceeds in the State Treasury for
credit to the Fund for Escheated Estates.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 313:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.313]—(NRS A1983,
1091;1999,
2355)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_154-100">
          <num>154.100</num>
          <heading>Appeal from judgment.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>As
in civil cases, the Attorney General, in behalf of the State, and any party who
has appeared in any proceedings mentioned inNRS
154.060, has the right to appeal from any judgment rendered in the
proceedings.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [314:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.314]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_154-105">
          <num>154.105</num>
          <heading>Sale of escheated property; deposit of proceeds.</heading>
          <subsection eId="154-105__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The State Treasurer may sell at a
public sale property in the custody of the State Treasurer which has escheated
to the State. The State Treasurer shall cause public notice of the sale to be
given. Any money received from the sale must be deposited in the State Treasury
for credit to the Fund for Escheated Estates.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-105__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The personal representative of an
estate shall sell any property and transmit the proceeds of the sale to the
State Treasurer for credit to the Fund for Escheated Estates unless the State
Treasurer authorizes transmittal of the property.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1091; A1999,
2356)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_154-110">
          <num>154.110</num>
          <heading>Duties of Director of State Department of Conservation and
Natural Resources.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The Director of
the State Department of Conservation and Natural Resources shall keep a true
record or description of all real property vested in the State by escheat. All
real property must be described by legal subdivision, by metes and bounds
sufficiently accurate to identify the ground on an approved township plat from
the Bureau of Land Management or, if within an approved townsite, by reference
to the lot, block, and tract or subdivision.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1:55:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 7530.01] + [Part 315:107:1941;
A1951,
27]—(NRS A1957,
654;1983,
1092;1991,
206)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_154-115">
          <num>154.115</num>
          <heading>Duties of State Controller.</heading>
          <subsection eId="154-115__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Keep a true account of all money paid
into the State Treasury for credit to the Fund for Escheated Estates and of all
real and personal property vested in the State by escheat.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-115__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Account separately for the
proportionate share of interest earned on the money in the Fund for Escheated
Estates and credit an amount equal to that interest to the Fund.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-115__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Transfer:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="154-115__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>All of the interest earned on the money in
the Fund for Escheated Estates;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="154-115__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>All income of any kind which is earned on any
real or personal property vested in the State by escheat; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="154-115__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>All estates which are not claimed within the
period fixed byNRS 154.120, to the
State Permanent School Fund at least annually.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1091)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_154-120">
          <num>154.120</num>
          <heading>Proceedings for recovery of property.</heading>
          <subsection eId="154-120__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If, within 6 years after any judgment
escheating property to the State, any person claims any money or property
vested in the State by the judgment, the person may file a petition in the
district court of Carson City, stating the nature of the claim, with an
appropriate request for the relief demanded.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-120__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A copy of the petition must be served
upon the Attorney General before or at the time of filing. Within 20 days after
service, the Attorney General shall appear in the proceeding and plead or
answer the petition. If, after examining all the facts, the Attorney General is
convinced that the State has no legal defense against the petition, the
Attorney General may, with the consent of the court, confess judgment on behalf
of the State.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-120__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If judgment is not confessed, the
petition is at issue on the 20th day after its filing, and may be heard by the
court on that day, or at such future day as the court may order.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-120__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon the hearing, the court shall
examine the claim and hear the allegations and evidence. If the court finds
that the person is entitled to any money, it shall, by judgment, order the
State Controller to draw a warrant in favor of the claimant upon the State
Treasurer for the sum specified in the order, but without interest, income or
cost of any kind to the state. A certified copy of the judgment and order
directing the State Controller to draw the warrant for money is a sufficient
voucher to do so.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-120__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any property is the subject of the
trial, and the court finds the claimant entitled to it, the court shall enter
an order accordingly. The order divests the interests of the State in or to the
property, but no interest, income or other cost of any kind may be taxed
against the State.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-120__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any property has been sold as
provided in this chapter after the judgment of escheat, the petitioner is
entitled to the proceeds of the sale less the cost of the sale without any
interest, income or other cost to the State of any kind, in lieu of the
property, and the court shall enter an order accordingly.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-120__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>All persons, except minors and
incapacitated persons, who fail to appear and file their petitions within the
time limited in subsection 1 are barred forever. Minors and incapacitated
persons may appear and file their petitions at any time within 5 years after
their respective disabilities are removed.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 6:55:1941; A1951,
26] + [Part 315:107:1941; A1951,
27]—(NRS A1969,
315;1983,
1092;1999,
2356)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_154-130">
          <num>154.130</num>
          <heading>Person furnishing information entitled to percentage of value of
recovered property.</heading>
          <subsection eId="154-130__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>That the amount so received by the
person furnishing the information shall not in the aggregate exceed the sum of
$20,000 in any one case; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-130__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>That one person only shall be entitled
to compensation for such service.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [317:107:1941; A1951,
19]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_154-140">
          <num>154.140</num>
          <heading>Deposit of money from escheated estates.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>All money received by the State from escheated
estates must be deposited in the State Treasury for credit to the Fund for
Escheated Estates which is hereby created as a trust fund.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [318:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.318]—(NRS A1959,
23;1983,
1093)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_154-150">
          <num>154.150</num>
          <heading>Petition to acquire title to escheated property.</heading>
          <subsection eId="154-150__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person desiring to acquire title to
any individual item or real property which has escheated to the State must
proceed by petition to the Director of the State Department of Conservation and
Natural Resources on forms obtainable at the office of the Director and in the
manner described inNRS 154.150to154.180, inclusive.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-150__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A petition for unimproved real property
outside of approved townsites may not be accepted for a parcel of land less
than the smallest legal subdivision (40 acres) unless the area in its entirety
is less than 40 acres. In such a case, that portion of the subdivision must be
described and disposed of on one petition unless, in the discretion of the
Director of the State Department of Conservation and Natural Resources, it is
found that the remaining portion could be disposed of within a reasonable
length of time, and would not become an isolated tract. The Director may then
accept an application for a portion of the tract, if a survey is made and a
plat submitted on tracing cloth, 24 inches by 32 inches, on which is set forth
an accurate description of the property by metes and bounds, with at least one
corner of the property tied to a point on the United States public land
surveys.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [2:55:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 7530.02]—(NRS A1957,
654;1999,
2357)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_154-160">
          <num>154.160</num>
          <heading>Petition to be accompanied by purchase price and fees.</heading>
          <subsection eId="154-160__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The purchase price in the amount of the
petitionerï¿½s offer for the real property desired.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-160__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A sufficient sum to cover the cost of advertising.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-160__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A fee of $5.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [3:55:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 7530.03]—(NRS A1999,
2357)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_154-170">
          <num>154.170</num>
          <heading>Notice of sale: Posting, publication and contents; rejection of
bids.</heading>
          <subsection eId="154-170__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Director of the State Department of
Conservation and Natural Resources shall issue a receipt to the petitioner for
the amount deposited in his or her trust and shall without any unnecessary
delay cause notice of the petition to be given in the following manner:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="154-170__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>By posting one of the notices in a
conspicuous place in the office of the Director of the State Department of
Conservation and Natural Resources.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="154-170__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>By posting one of the notices at a conspicuous
place at the property.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="154-170__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>By publishing a notice in a newspaper in the
county in which the real property is located at least once each week for 4
consecutive weeks prior to the date of sale.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-170__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The notice must contain:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="154-170__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The name of the deceased owner in which was
vested the title before death, if known.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="154-170__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A description of the property as contained in
the petition.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="154-170__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The amount of the offer contained in the
petition.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="154-170__subsec_2__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A statement that the property will be sold to
the highest bidder, specifying the time and place of the sale and that the
transaction must be handled in legal tender of the United States or a certified
check.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="154-170__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Director of the State Department of
Conservation and Natural Resources may reject any or all bids.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [4:55:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 7530.04]—(NRS A1999,
2357)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_154-180">
          <num>154.180</num>
          <heading>Costs borne by purchaser.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The
person to whom the title passes must pay the cost of advertising and the
petition fee. When the title passes to a person other than the person who made
the petition, the original petitioner must be reimbursed all moneys deposited
by him or her.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [5:55:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 7530.05]—(NRS A1999,
2358)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>