<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="NRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-274"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-274"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#nevada-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-nv"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="274"/>
          <FRBRname value="NRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-274/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-274/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-274/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-274/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="nevada-legislature" href="https://www.leg.state.nv.us" showAs="Nevada State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_274">
        <num>274</num>
        <heading>ZONES FOR ECONOMIC</heading>
        <section eId="sec_274-010">
          <num>274.010</num>
          <heading>Definitions.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>As
used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires, the words and
terms defined inNRS 274.020to274.080, inclusive, have the meanings
ascribed to them in those sections.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1971; A2013,
27th Special Session, 21)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-020">
          <num>274.020</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Administratorï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Administratorï¿½
means the Executive Director of the Office of Economic Development.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1971; A2011,
3452)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-030">
          <num>274.030</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Depressed areaï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Depressed
areaï¿½ means an area in which pervasive poverty, unemployment and economic
distress exist.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1971)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-040">
          <num>274.040</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Designating municipalityï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Designating
municipalityï¿½ means a city, or, with respect to the unincorporated areas of the
county, a county which designates a specially benefited zone pursuant to this
chapter.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1971)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-050">
          <num>274.050</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Governing bodyï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Governing
bodyï¿½ means the board of county commissioners, the board of supervisors, the
city council or the board of commissioners, as the case may be.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1971)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-060">
          <num>274.060</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Municipalityï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Municipalityï¿½
means any county, with respect to the unincorporated areas of the county, or
any city in this State, including Carson City.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1971)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-070">
          <num>274.070</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Qualified businessï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Qualified
businessï¿½ means any business organization qualified to receive benefits under
this chapter and which has made an agreement concerning those benefits as
provided byNRS 274.270.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1971)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-080">
          <num>274.080</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Zoneï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Zoneï¿½
means a specially benefited zone designated and approved pursuant to this
chapter.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1971)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-090">
          <num>274.090</num>
          <heading>Administrator: Administration of chapter; regulations.</heading>
          <subsection eId="274-090__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Executive Director of the Office of
Economic Development shall serve as Administrator.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-090__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Administrator shall:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-090__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Administer this chapter.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-090__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Adopt all necessary regulations to carry out
the provisions of this chapter.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1976; A2011,
3452;2015,
2768)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-100">
          <num>274.100</num>
          <heading>Administrator: Duties.</heading>
          <subsection eId="274-100__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When any federal legislation concerning
specially benefited zones is enacted and becomes effective, assist
municipalities in preparing and submitting all information and forms necessary
to permit the zone to be considered as an eligible area under the federal
program.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-100__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Provide information and appropriate
assistance to persons desiring to locate and engage in business in a specially
benefited zone, to persons already engaged in business in a zone and to
designated neighborhood organizations operating there.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-100__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In cooperation with appropriate state
and local governmental agencies, coordinate existing state and local programs
to assist businesses and assist in simplifying procedures by which businesses
within a specially benefited zone must apply for licenses and permits.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-100__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Publicize existing financial incentives
and programs for economic development within a zone and upon request, offer
technical assistance in the development of financial incentives and alternative
sources of revenue to local governments which have specially benefited zones
within their jurisdiction.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-100__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Work together with the responsible
state and federal agencies to promote the coordination of other relevant
programs, including but not limited to programs concerning housing, community
and economic development, small business, banking, financial assistance, and
training for employment which are carried on in a specially benefited zone.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1976)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-110">
          <num>274.110</num>
          <heading>Administrator: Procedure for review of state regulations.</heading>
          <subsection eId="274-110__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Administrator shall conduct a
review of state administrative regulations and shall identify those regulations
which preliminarily appear to the Administrator to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-110__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Affect the conduct of business, industry and
commerce;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-110__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Impose excessive cost on either the creation
or conduct of businesses; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-110__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Inhibit the development and expansion of
business within specially benefited zones.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-110__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Administrator shall conduct hearings
to solicit public comment on the regulations as part of the review.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-110__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>No later than August 1, 1984, the
Administrator shall publish a list of regulations identified pursuant to
subsection 1. The Administrator shall transmit a copy of the list to each agency
which has adopted regulations on the list.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-110__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Within 90 days after the publication of
the list by the Administrator, each agency which adopted any regulation
identified therein shall file a written report with the Administrator detailing
for each identified regulation:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-110__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Its need or justification;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-110__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Whether the regulation is required by state
or federal law, or is discretionary, and to what extent;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-110__subsec_4__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A synopsis of the history of the regulation,
including any internal review of it by the agency after its original adoption;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-110__subsec_4__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any appropriate explanation of its
relationship to other regulatory requirements; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-110__subsec_4__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any available data, analysis and studies
concerning the estimated economic effect of the regulations on the business
which it is to regulate and on the public. The informational statement prepared
as required byNRS 233B.066may be
submitted to satisfy the requirements of this paragraph if it contains a
current estimate of that economic effect.
ï¿½The agencyï¿½s
report is a public record and must be open to public inspection during regular
business hours.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1979)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-120">
          <num>274.120</num>
          <heading>Administrator: Adoption of regulations exempting certain
businesses from state regulations.</heading>
          <subsection eId="274-120__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>No later than January 1, 1985, and from
time to time as necessary, the Administrator shall, except as provided inNRS 274.140, adopt regulations exempting
businesses within specially benefited zones from those state regulations
contained in the list published pursuant toNRS
274.110, for which the Administrator finds that incentives for the creation
of jobs or for business development within specially benefited zones engendered
by the exemption outweigh the need and justification for the regulation. In
making such findings, the Administrator shall consider all information, data
and opinions submitted by the public and the state agencies, and any other
information otherwise available. These regulations must be in the form of
amendments to the existing state regulations to be affected, and are subject to
the provisions ofchapter 233Bof NRS.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-120__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon its effective date, any regulation
of the Administrator adopted under subsection 1 supersedes the exempted state
regulation in accordance with the terms of the exemption. An exemption applies
only to businesses within specially benefited zones during the effective term
of the respective zones. State agencies may not adopt emergency regulations to
circumvent an exemption granted by the Administrator. Any such emergency
regulation is not effective within the specially benefited zones to the extent
it is inconsistent with the terms of the exemption.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1979)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-130">
          <num>274.130</num>
          <heading>Exemption of businesses by agency from its regulations;
regulations of Administrator supersede; modification of local ordinances and
regulations of municipality.</heading>
          <subsection eId="274-130__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as provided inNRS 274.140, a state agency may provide in
its regulations for the exemption of businesses within specially benefited
zones or for modifications or alternatives specifically applicable to
businesses within those zones, which impose less stringent standards or
alternative standards for compliance, including standards based on performance
as a substitute for specific requirements concerning methods, procedures or
equipment. The agency adopting those exemptions, modifications or alternatives
shall file with its proposed regulation its findings that the proposed
regulation provides economic incentives within specially benefited zones which
promote the purposes of this chapter and which, to the extent they include any
exemptions or reductions in regulatory standards or requirements, outweigh the
need or justification for the existing regulation.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-130__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any agency adopts a regulation
pursuant to subsection 1 affecting a regulation contained on the list published
by the Administrator pursuant toNRS 274.110before the Administrator adopts a regulation affecting the regulation on the
list, the agency shall immediately transmit a copy of its proposed regulation
to the Administrator, together with a statement of the reasons why the
Administrator should defer to the agencyï¿½s proposed regulation. Regulations
adopted under subsection 1 are subject to any superseding regulations of the
Administrator adopted underNRS 274.120.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-130__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as provided inNRS 274.140, a designating municipality may
modify, with respect to specially benefited zones, all local ordinances and
regulations regarding zoning, licensing or building codes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1980)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-140">
          <num>274.140</num>
          <heading>Exceptions to exemptions from regulations or ordinances.</heading>
          <subsection eId="274-140__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions ofNRS 274.110,274.120and subsection 1 ofNRS 274.130do not apply to regulations
adopted pursuant to any statute whose purpose is the protection of the
environment, the preservation of historic places and landmarks, or the
protection of persons against discrimination on the basis of race, color, religion,
sex, sexual orientation, gender identity or expression, marital status,
national origin or handicap.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-140__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>No exemption, modification or
alternative to any regulation adopted underNRS
274.110,274.120or274.130is effective which:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-140__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Presents a significant risk to the health or
safety of persons resident in or employed within a specially benefited zone;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-140__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Conflicts with federal law or regulations
such that the State, or any local government or any area of the State other
than specially benefited zones, or any business located outside of a specially benefited
zone would be disqualified from a federal program or from federal tax benefits
or other benefits;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-140__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Suspends or modifies a regulation
specifically required by law; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-140__subsec_2__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Eliminates or reduces benefits to persons who
are residents of or employed within a zone.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1981; A2017,
1067)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-150">
          <num>274.150</num>
          <heading>Qualifications for zone.</heading>
          <subsection eId="274-150__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Is a contiguous area, but the area of a
zone may exclude wholly surrounded territory within its boundaries;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-150__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Is a depressed area;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-150__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Satisfies any additional criteria
established by regulation of the Administrator consistent with the purposes of
this chapter; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-150__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Is entirely within a city or entirely
within the unincorporated areas of a county, except where reasonable need is
established for the zone to cover portions of more than one city or county.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1971)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-160">
          <num>274.160</num>
          <heading>Designation of area as zone; contents of ordinance.</heading>
          <subsection eId="274-160__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A city, within its jurisdiction, or a
county within the unincorporated areas of the county, or municipalities
jointly, may by ordinance designate an area as a specially benefited zone,
subject to the approval of the Governor, if:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-160__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The area is qualified underNRS 274.150; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-160__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The municipality has conducted at least one
public hearing within the proposed zone on:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="274-160__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The question of whether to create the
zone;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="274-160__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>What local plans, financial incentives
and other programs should be established in connection with the zone; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="274-160__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>What the boundaries of the zone should
be.
ï¿½Public
notice of the hearing must be published in at least one newspaper of general
circulation within the proposed zone, not more than 20 days nor less than 5
days before the hearing.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-160__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An ordinance designating an area as a
specially benefited zone must set forth:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-160__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A precise description of the area comprising
the zone, either in the form of a legal description or by reference to
roadways, lakes and waterways, and township, county or city boundaries;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-160__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A finding that the zone meets the
qualifications ofNRS 274.150;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-160__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Provisions for any financial incentives which
pursuant to state or federal law apply to qualified businesses within the zone
at the election of the designating municipality, and which are not applicable
throughout the municipality;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-160__subsec_2__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A designation of the area as a specially
benefited zone, subject to the approval of the Governor; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-160__subsec_2__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The duration or term of the specially
benefited zone.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-160__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>This section does not prohibit a
municipality from extending additional financial incentives in specially
benefited zones or throughout its territory by separate ordinance, if the
provision of those incentives is otherwise authorized by law.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1971)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-170">
          <num>274.170</num>
          <heading>Contents of application to Governor for designation of area as
zone.</heading>
          <subsection eId="274-170__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A certified copy of the ordinance
designating the proposed zone;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-170__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A map of the proposed zone, showing
existing streets and highways;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-170__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An analysis, and any appropriate
supporting documents and statistics, demonstrating that the proposed zone is
qualified underNRS 274.150;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-170__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A statement detailing any reduction,
deferral or elimination of any license or franchise tax, fee, service charge or
other financial incentives or benefits, and any programs, to be provided by the
municipality to qualified businesses within the zone, other than those provided
in the designating ordinance, which are not to be provided throughout the
municipality;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-170__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A statement setting forth the
objectives concerning economic development and planning for the zone;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-170__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A statement describing the functions,
programs and services to be performed by designated neighborhood organizations
within the zone;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-170__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An estimate of the economic effect of
the zone, considering all of the financial incentives or benefits and the
programs contemplated, upon the revenues of the municipality;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-170__subsec_8">
            <num>8.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A recording or the minutes of all
public hearings on the zone;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-170__subsec_9">
            <num>9.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In the case of a joint application, a
statement detailing the need for a zone covering portions of more than one city
or county and a description of the agreement between the joint applicants; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-170__subsec_10">
            <num>10.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such additional information as the
Administrator by regulation may require.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1972)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-180">
          <num>274.180</num>
          <heading>Review of application by Administrator and Governor.</heading>
          <subsection eId="274-180__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>All applications which are to be
considered and acted upon by the Administrator and the Governor during a
calendar year must be received by the Administrator no later than December 31
of the preceding calendar year. Any application received on or after January 1
of any calendar year must be held by the Administrator for consideration and
action during the following calendar year.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-180__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon receipt of an application from a
municipality, the Administrator shall review the application to determine
whether the designated area qualifies as a specially benefited zone underNRS 274.150and whether to recommend
approval or denial of the application by the Governor. No later than May 1, the
Administrator shall notify all applicant municipalities of the Administratorï¿½s
determination of the qualification of their respective designated specially
benefited zones. If any such designated area is found to be qualified to be a
specially benefited zone, the Administrator shall, no later than May 15,
publish a notice in at least one newspaper of general circulation within the
proposed zone to notify the general public of the application and their
opportunity to comment. The notice must include a description of the area and a
brief summary of the application and must indicate locations where the
applicant has provided copies of the application for public inspection. The
notice must also indicate appropriate procedures for the filing of written
comments from residents, businesses, civic and other organizations and property
owners within the zone to the Administrator.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-180__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>By July 1 the Governor shall either
approve or deny all applications filed by December 31 of the preceding year. If
approval of an application filed by December 31 of any year is not received by
July 1 of the following year, the application shall be considered denied. If an
application is denied, the Administrator shall inform the municipality of the
specific reasons for the denial.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1973)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-190">
          <num>274.190</num>
          <heading>Criteria for designation of zone by Governor.</heading>
          <subsection eId="274-190__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In determining which designated areas
will be approved as specially benefited zones, the Governor shall give
preference to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-190__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Areas with high levels of poverty,
unemployment, loss of jobs and population, and general distress;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-190__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Areas which have evidenced the widest support
from the designating municipality, local residents and business, labor and
neighborhood organizations;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-190__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Areas for which a specific plan has been
submitted to effect economic growth and expansion and neighborhood
revitalization for the benefit of residents and existing businesses within the
zone through efforts which may include but need not be limited to a reduction
or elimination of license or franchise taxes, fees or service charges, an
increase in the level and efficiency of local services, and a simplification of
governmental requirements applicable to employers or employees, taking into
account the resources available to the municipality to make those efforts;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-190__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Areas for which there is evidence of prior
consultation between the municipality and business, labor and neighborhood
organizations within the proposed zone;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-190__subsec_1__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Areas for which a specific plan has been
submitted which will or may be expected to benefit residents and employees
within the zone by increasing their opportunities for ownership of and
participation in developments within the specially benefited zone; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-190__subsec_1__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Areas in which specific governmental
functions are to be performed by designated neighborhood organizations in
partnership with the municipality seeking certification of an area as a
specially benefited zone.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-190__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Governorï¿½s determination of whether
to approve a specially benefited zone must be based on the purposes of this
chapter, the criteria set forth inNRS
274.150and subsection 1 of this section and any additional criteria
adopted by regulation of the Administrator.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1974)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-200">
          <num>274.200</num>
          <heading>Certification of zone by Governor; terms and number of zones.</heading>
          <subsection eId="274-200__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Approval of designated specially
benefited zones must be made by the Governor by certification of the
designating ordinance. The Governor shall promptly issue a certificate for each
specially benefited zone upon his or her approval. The certificate must be
signed by the Governor, must make specific reference to the designating
ordinance, which must be attached thereto, and must be filed in the Office of
the Secretary of State. A certified copy of the certificate must be recorded
with the county recorder of the county in which the specially benefited zone
lies.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-200__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A specially benefited zone is effective
upon its certification. The Administrator shall transmit a copy of the
certification to the Department of Taxation, the Employment Security Division
of the Department of Employment, Training and Rehabilitation and to the
designating municipality. The terms and provisions of the designating ordinance
become effective upon certification of the specially benefited zone, and may
not be amended or repealed except as otherwise provided inNRS 274.280.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-200__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided inNRS 274.280, the designating ordinance and
the certification remain in effect for 20 years, or for a lesser number of
years specified in the ordinance, and terminate at midnight of December 31 of
the final year of the certified term.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-200__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>No more than eight specially benefited
zones may be approved by the Governor in any year. In any year, the Governor
may not approve more than three zones located within the same county, whether
within its cities or within the unincorporated areas, nor more than three zones
in the same city. The Governor may approve specially benefited zones in each of
the 6 years commencing with 1984. Thereafter, the Governor may not approve any
additional specially benefited zones, but may amend or rescind certifications
of existing zones as provided inNRS 274.280.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1974; A1993,
1547;2001,
1758)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-210">
          <num>274.210</num>
          <heading>Program for training and employment of residents in zone; report
to municipality and Legislative Commission.</heading>
          <subsection eId="274-210__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In order to stimulate opportunities for
employment for residents of a specially benefited zone, the Administrator shall
initiate a test of a program for the reimbursement of vouchers for the cost of
training residents of the zone eligible under the provisions of the Internal
Revenue Code concerning tax credits for the employment of members of targeted
groups in private industry. This program must not be designed to subsidize
businesses, but is intended to make available opportunities for jobs and
training not otherwise available. Nothing in this subsection requires
businesses within a zone to utilize this program.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-210__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The program described in subsection 1
must be designed:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-210__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For those persons whose opportunities for
obtaining employment are minimal without participation in the program;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-210__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>To minimize the period during which those
persons collect benefits under programs for public assistance; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-210__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>To accelerate the transition of those persons
to unsubsidized employment.
ï¿½The
Administrator shall seek agreement with business, organized labor and the
appropriate state and local agencies on the design, operation and evaluation of
the test program.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-210__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A report with recommendations,
including representative comments of governmental agencies and business and
labor organizations, must be submitted by the Administrator to the designating
municipality and the Legislative Commission not later than 12 months after the
test program commences, or not later than 3 months following the termination of
the test program, whichever first occurs.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1977)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-220">
          <num>274.220</num>
          <heading>Manager of zone: Appointment; qualifications; duties.</heading>
          <subsection eId="274-220__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The management of a specially benefited
zone must be under the jurisdiction of the designating municipality.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-220__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each designating municipality shall, by
ordinance, appoint a zone manager for the certified zones within its
jurisdiction. A zone manager must be an officer or employee of the
municipality.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-220__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The zone manager shall coordinate
activities between the designating municipality, the Administrator and any
designated neighborhood organizations within zones under his or her
jurisdiction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1977)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-230">
          <num>274.230</num>
          <heading>Powers of designating municipality: Cooperation with federal,
state and local governments; improving police protection; federal assistance
for urban development or training for employment; qualifications for benefits.</heading>
          <subsection eId="274-230__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Apply with the United States Department
of Commerce to have the specially benefited zone declared to be a free trade
zone.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-230__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When any federal legislation concerning
specially benefited zones is enacted or becomes effective, prepare and submit,
with the assistance of the Administrator and in a timely fashion, all
information and forms necessary to permit the specially benefited zone
designated and approved under this chapter to be considered as an eligible area
under the federal program.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-230__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Apply for all available assistance from
the federal, state, and in the case of a city, the county government, including
the suspension or modification of their regulations within the specially
benefited zone that have the characteristics described in subsection 1 ofNRS 274.110.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-230__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Develop and carry out a program to
improve police protection within the zone.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-230__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Give priority to the use in the zone of
any federal assistance for urban development or job training.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-230__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>By ordinance adopt regulations for
qualifying employers for the benefits authorized specifically for qualified
businesses under this chapter andNRS
374.643.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1979)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-240">
          <num>274.240</num>
          <heading>Powers of designating municipality: Issuing securities; reducing
certain taxes, fees or service charges; improving governmental services;
providing financing; cooperating with other governmental agencies.</heading>
          <subsection eId="274-240__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Issue bonds or other securities
authorized by other law for the purposes of economic development and use the
proceeds for loans to any new or expanding qualified businesses in the
specially benefited zone.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-240__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Reduce or eliminate any license or
franchise tax, fee or service charge which would otherwise be imposed against
qualified businesses within the specially benefited zone.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-240__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Develop and carry out, alone or where
feasible with the participation of one or more designated neighborhood
organizations as provided inNRS 274.250,
programs to improve needed governmental services within the specially benefited
zone.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-240__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Develop and carry out a plan to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-240__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Ensure the availability of resources to assist
residents of the specially benefited zone in their own efforts to improve the
condition of property and the availability and quality of public services
within the zone.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-240__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Provide or seek assistance for persons or
businesses displaced as a result of undertakings or other activities conducted
pursuant to this chapter.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-240__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Provide financing by tax increment
pursuant tochapter 278Cof NRS.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-240__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Cooperate with any other governmental
agency to provide any other incentive likely to encourage private investment
within the specially benefited zone.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1981; A1997,
2561;2005,
1767)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-250">
          <num>274.250</num>
          <heading>Powers of designating municipality: Delegation of services to
private organizations.</heading>
          <subsection eId="274-250__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A designating municipality may, by
ordinance, delegate one or more of the services or functions described in
subsection 2 to one or more qualified private organizations. For the purposes
of this section, an organization is qualified if:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-250__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Its constituency is composed substantially of
residents of the specially benefited zone;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-250__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>It has a governing body elected by its
constituents;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-250__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>It meets the requirements of paragraph</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="274-250__subsec_1__subsec_c__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>of
subsection</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-250__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of section 501 of the Internal Revenue Code; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-250__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>It exists primarily to perform services
within the zone for the benefit of its residents and businesses.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-250__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A designated neighborhood organization
may be authorized to provide the following services or perform the following
functions in coordination with the municipality:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-250__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Provide or contract for the provision of
public services including, but not limited to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="274-250__subsec_2__subsec_a__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The establishment of patrols to watch
for crime in neighborhoods within the specially benefited zone.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="274-250__subsec_2__subsec_a__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The establishment of volunteer day
care centers.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="274-250__subsec_2__subsec_a__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The organization of recreational
activities for children living within the zone.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="274-250__subsec_2__subsec_a__subsec_4">
                <num>(4)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Garbage collection.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="274-250__subsec_2__subsec_a__subsec_5">
                <num>(5)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Street maintenance and improvement.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="274-250__subsec_2__subsec_a__subsec_6">
                <num>(6)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The maintenance and improvement of
parks, bridges and water and sewer lines.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="274-250__subsec_2__subsec_a__subsec_7">
                <num>(7)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Projects for the conservation of
energy.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="274-250__subsec_2__subsec_a__subsec_8">
                <num>(8)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Health and clinical services.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="274-250__subsec_2__subsec_a__subsec_9">
                <num>(9)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Programs to combat substance use
disorders.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="274-250__subsec_2__subsec_a__subsec_10">
                <num>(10)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Programs to assist older residents of
the zone.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="274-250__subsec_2__subsec_a__subsec_11">
                <num>(11)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The rehabilitation, renovation,
operation and maintenance of housing for persons of low and moderate income.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="274-250__subsec_2__subsec_a__subsec_12">
                <num>(12)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Other types of public services as
provided by ordinance.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-250__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Exercise authority for the enforcement of any
code, permit or procedure for licensing within a specially benefited zone.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-250__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Provide a forum for action by business, labor
and government on innovations for the zone.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-250__subsec_2__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Apply for regulatory relief underNRS 274.110,274.120and274.130.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-250__subsec_2__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Perform such other functions as the
responsible governmental entity may deem appropriate, including offerings and
contracts for insurance with businesses within the zone.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-250__subsec_2__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Agree with local governments to provide these
public services within the zone by contracting with private firms and
organizations, where feasible and prudent.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-250__subsec_2__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Solicit and receive contributions to improve
the quality of life in the specially benefited zone.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1977)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-260">
          <num>274.260</num>
          <heading>Proposal by business to participate in benefits of zone;
contents of proposal.</heading>
          <subsection eId="274-260__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An estimate of the number of new
employees whom the business intends to hire for its place of business within
the specially benefited zone and an estimate of the amount of payroll these
hirings will add to the business.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-260__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An estimate of the amount to be
invested by the business to establish, expand, renovate or occupy a place of
business within the specially benefited zone, including investment in new
buildings, additions, or improvements to existing buildings, machinery,
equipment, furniture, fixtures and inventory.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-260__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A listing of the businessï¿½ current
investment, if any, in a place of business within the specially benefited zone
as of the date of the submission of the proposal. The business shall review and
keep current the estimates and listings required under this subsection to
reflect material changes, and any agreement entered into pursuant toNRS 274.270must set forth final estimates
and listings as of the time the agreement is entered.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1982)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-270">
          <num>274.270</num>
          <heading>Investigation by governing body of proposal by business to
participate in benefits of zone; requirements for hiring certain employees;
review of compliance with agreement; filing of information.</heading>
          <subsection eId="274-270__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The governing body shall investigate
the proposal made by a business pursuant toNRS
274.260, and if it finds that the business is qualified by financial
responsibility and business experience to create and preserve employment
opportunities in the specially benefited zone and improve the economic climate
of the municipality and finds further that the business did not relocate from a
depressed area in this State or reduce employment elsewhere in Nevada in order
to expand in the specially benefited zone, the governing body may, on behalf of
the municipality, enter into an agreement with the business, for a period of
not more than 20 years, under which the business agrees in return for one or
more of the benefits authorized in this chapter andNRS 374.643for qualified businesses, as
specified in the agreement, to establish, expand, renovate or occupy a place of
business within the specially benefited zone and hire new employees at least 35
percent of whom at the time they are employed are at least one of the
following:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-270__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Unemployed persons who have resided at least
6 months in the municipality.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-270__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Persons eligible for employment or job
training under any federal program for employment and training who have resided
at least 6 months in the municipality.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-270__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Recipients of benefits under any state or
county program of public assistance, including, without limitation, temporary
assistance for needy families, Medicaid and unemployment compensation who have
resided at least 6 months in the municipality.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-270__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Persons with a physical or intellectual
disability who have resided at least 6 months in the State.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-270__subsec_1__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Residents for at least 1 year of the area
comprising the specially benefited zone.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-270__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>To determine whether a business is in
compliance with an agreement, the governing body:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-270__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Shall each year require the business to file
proof satisfactory to the governing body of its compliance with the agreement.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-270__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>May conduct any necessary investigation into
the affairs of the business and may inspect at any reasonable hour its place of
business within the specially benefited zone.
ï¿½If the
governing body determines that the business is in compliance with the
agreement, it shall issue a certificate to that effect to the business. The
certificate expires 1 year after the date of its issuance.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-270__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The governing body shall file with the
Administrator, the Department of Taxation and the Employment Security Division
of the Department of Employment, Training and Rehabilitation a copy of each
agreement, the information submitted under paragraph</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-270__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 2 and
the current certificate issued to the business under that subsection. The
governing body shall immediately notify the Administrator, the Department of
Taxation and the Employment Security Division of the Department of Employment,
Training and Rehabilitation whenever the business is no longer certified.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1982; A1993,
1548;1997,
2336;1999,
2237;2013,
693)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-280">
          <num>274.280</num>
          <heading>Procedure to amend ordinance designating zone.</heading>
          <subsection eId="274-280__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The terms of a certified ordinance
designating a specially benefited zone may be amended to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-280__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Alter the boundaries of the zone;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-280__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Limit or repeal financial incentives or
benefits provided in the ordinance; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-280__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Alter the date for terminating the zone.
ï¿½The
amendment does not become effective unless the Governor issues an amended
certificate for the zone. Upon the adoption of the amendment, the municipality
shall promptly file with the Administrator an application for approval thereof,
containing substantially the same information as required for an application
underNRS 274.170insofar as material to
the proposed changes. The municipality must hold a public hearing on the
proposed changes as specified inNRS 274.160.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-280__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Governor shall approve or
disapprove a proposed amendment to a certified specially benefited zone within
90 days after receiving the application from the municipality. The Governor may
not approve changes in a zone which are not in conformity with this chapter or
with other applicable laws. If the Governor issues an amended certificate for a
specially benefited zone, the amended certificate, together with the amended
designating ordinance, must be filed, recorded and transmitted as provided inNRS 274.200.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1975)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-290">
          <num>274.290</num>
          <heading>Termination of zone.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>A
specially benefited zone may be terminated by joint action of the Governor and
the designating municipality. The designating municipality shall conduct at
least one public hearing within the zone before adopting its ordinance of
termination. The mayor of the designating city or the chair of the governing
body of the designating county shall execute with the Administrator a joint
agreement for termination of the zone. The termination of a specially benefited
zone does not become effective until at least 6 months after the execution of
the terminating agreement, which must be filed in the Office of the Secretary
of State.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1975)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-300">
          <num>274.300</num>
          <heading>Effect upon benefits if zone terminated or modified or benefits
reduced or eliminated.</heading>
          <subsection eId="274-300__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>All benefits previously extended within
the zone pursuant to this chapter, or pursuant to any other law of this State
providing benefits specifically to qualified businesses within specially
benefited zones, remain in effect for the original stated term of the zone with
respect to those qualified businesses operating within the zone on the effective
date of the termination or amendment, except as provided in subsection 2.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-300__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A qualified business which is proposed
or which has proposed an expansion is entitled to the benefits previously
applicable within the zone for the original stated term of the zone, if the
business establishes that:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-300__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The proposed business or expansion has been
committed to be located within the zone;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-300__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Substantial and binding financial obligations
have been made towards the development of the business or the expansion; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-300__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Those commitments have been made in
reasonable reliance on the benefits and programs which were to have been
applicable to the business by reason of the zone, including in the case of a
reduction in the term of a zone, the original length of the term.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
1976)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-310">
          <num>274.310</num>
          <heading>Abatement for locating business in certain areas of economic
development: Endorsement required; application; requirements for approval;
certificate of eligibility; duration and amount of abatement; repayment
required under certain circumstances; regulations; judicial review. [Effective
through June 30, 2032.]</heading>
          <subsection eId="274-310__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who intends to locate a
business in this State within:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-310__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A historically underutilized business zone,
as defined in 15 U.S.C. ï¿½ 632;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-310__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A redevelopment area created pursuant tochapter 279of NRS;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-310__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An area eligible for a community development
block grant pursuant to 24 C.F.R. Part 570; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-310__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An enterprise community established pursuant
to 24 C.F.R. Part 597,
ï¿½may submit a
request to the governing body of the county, city or town in which the business
would operate for an endorsement of an application by the person to the Office
of Economic Development for a partial abatement of one or more of the taxes
imposed pursuant tochapter 361of NRS or the
local sales and use taxes. The governing body of the county, city or town shall
provide notice of the request to the board of trustees of the school district
in which the business would operate. The notice must set forth the date, time
and location of the hearing at which the governing body will consider whether
to endorse the application. As used in this subsection, ï¿½local sales and use
taxesï¿½ means the taxes imposed on the gross receipts of any retailer from the
sale of tangible personal property sold at retail, or stored, used or otherwise
consumed, in the political subdivision in which the business is located, except
the taxes imposed by the Sales and Use Tax Act and the Local School Support Tax
Law.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-310__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The governing body of a county, city or
town shall develop procedures for:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-310__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Evaluating whether such an abatement would be
beneficial for the economic development of the county, city or town.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-310__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Issuing a certificate of endorsement for an
application for such an abatement that is found to be beneficial for the
economic development of the county, city or town.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-310__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person whose application has been
endorsed by the governing body of the county, city or town, as applicable,
pursuant to this section may submit the application to the Office of Economic
Development. The Office shall approve the application if the Office makes the
following determinations:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-310__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The business is consistent with:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="274-310__subsec_3__subsec_a__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The State Plan for Economic
Development developed by the Administrator pursuant to subsection 2 ofNRS 231.053; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="274-310__subsec_3__subsec_a__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Any guidelines adopted by the
Administrator to implement the State Plan for Economic Development.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-310__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Not later than 1 year after the date on which
the application was received by the Office, the applicant has executed an
agreement with the Office which states:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="274-310__subsec_3__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The date on which the abatement
becomes effective, as agreed to by the applicant and the Office, which must not
be earlier than the date on which the Office received the application and not
later than 1 year after the date on which the Office approves the application;
and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="274-310__subsec_3__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>That the business will, after the date
on which the abatement becomes effective:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (I) Commence operation and continue
in operation in the historically underutilized business zone, as defined in 15
U.S.C. ï¿½ 632, redevelopment area created pursuant tochapter 279of NRS, area eligible for a community
development block grant pursuant to 24 C.F.R. Part 570 or enterprise community
established pursuant to 24 C.F.R. Part 597 for a period specified by the
Office, which must be at least 5 years; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (II) Continue to meet the
eligibility requirements set forth in this subsection.
ï¿½The
agreement must bind successors in interest of the business for the specified
period.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-310__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The business is registered pursuant to the
laws of this State or the applicant commits to obtain a valid business license
and all other permits required by the county, city or town in which the
business will operate.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-310__subsec_3__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The applicant invested or commits to invest a
minimum of $500,000 in capital assets that will be retained at the location of
the business in the historically underutilized business zone, as defined in 15
U.S.C. ï¿½ 632, redevelopment area created pursuant tochapter 279of NRS, area eligible for a community
development block grant pursuant to 24 C.F.R. Part 570 or enterprise community
established pursuant to 24 C.F.R. Part 597 until at least the date which is 5
years after the date on which the abatement becomes effective.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-310__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the Office of Economic Development
approves an application for a partial abatement, the Office shall immediately
forward a certificate of eligibility for the abatement to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-310__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Department of Taxation;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-310__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Nevada Tax Commission; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-310__subsec_4__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the partial abatement is from the property
tax imposed pursuant tochapter 361of NRS,
the county treasurer of the county in which the business will be located.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-310__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the Office of Economic Development
approves an application for a partial abatement pursuant to this section:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-310__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The partial abatement must be for a duration
of not less than 1 year but not more than 5 years.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-310__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the abatement is from the property tax
imposed pursuant tochapter 361of NRS, the
partial abatement must not exceed 75 percent of the taxes on personal property
payable by a business each year pursuant to that chapter.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-310__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If an applicant for a partial abatement
pursuant to this section fails to execute the agreement described in paragraph</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-310__subsec_6__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 3 within 1 year after the date on which the application was
received by the Office, the applicant shall not be approved for a partial
abatement pursuant to this section unless the applicant submits a new request
pursuant to subsection 1.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-310__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a business whose partial abatement
has been approved pursuant to this section and is in effect ceases:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-310__subsec_7__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>To meet the eligibility requirements for the
partial abatement; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-310__subsec_7__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Operation before the time specified in the
agreement described in paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-310__subsec_7__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 3,
ï¿½the business
shall repay to the Department of Taxation or, if the partial abatement was from
the property tax imposed pursuant tochapter 361of NRS, to the county treasurer, the amount of the partial abatement that was
allowed pursuant to this section before the failure of the business to comply
unless the Nevada Tax Commission determines that the business has substantially
complied with the requirements of this section. Except as otherwise provided inNRS 360.232and360.320, the business shall, in addition to
the amount of the partial abatement required to be paid pursuant to this
subsection, pay interest on the amount due at the rate most recently
established pursuant toNRS 99.040for
each month, or portion thereof, from the last day of the month following the
period for which the payment would have been made had the partial abatement not
been approved until the date of payment of the tax.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-310__subsec_8">
            <num>8.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Office of Economic Development may
adopt such regulations as the Office determines to be necessary or advisable to
carry out the provisions of this section.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-310__subsec_9">
            <num>9.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An applicant for an abatement who is
aggrieved by a final decision of the Office of Economic Development may
petition for judicial review in the manner provided inchapter 233Bof NRS.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2005,
639; A2011,
3452;2013,
27th Special Session, 21;2015,
1074,3052;2019,
2225;2021,
2310)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-320">
          <num>274.320</num>
          <heading>Abatement for expanding business in certain areas of economic
development: Endorsement required; application; requirements for approval;
certificate of eligibility; duration and amount of abatement; repayment
required under certain circumstances; regulations; judicial review. [Effective
through June 30, 2032.]</heading>
          <subsection eId="274-320__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who intends to expand a
business in this State within:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-320__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A historically underutilized business zone,
as defined in 15 U.S.C. ï¿½ 632;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-320__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A redevelopment area created pursuant tochapter 279of NRS;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-320__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An area eligible for a community development
block grant pursuant to 24 C.F.R. Part 570; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-320__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An enterprise community established pursuant
to 24 C.F.R. Part 597,
ï¿½may submit a
request to the governing body of the county, city or town in which the business
operates for an endorsement of an application by the person to the Office of
Economic Development for a partial abatement of the local sales and use taxes
imposed on capital equipment. The governing body of the county, city or town
shall provide notice of the request to the board of trustees of the school
district in which the business operates. The notice must set forth the date,
time and location of the hearing at which the governing body will consider
whether to endorse the application. As used in this subsection, ï¿½local sales
and use taxesï¿½ means the taxes imposed on the gross receipts of any retailer
from the sale of tangible personal property sold at retail, or stored, used or
otherwise consumed, in the political subdivision in which the business is
located, except the taxes imposed by the Sales and Use Tax Act and the Local
School Support Tax Law.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-320__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The governing body of a county, city or
town shall develop procedures for:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-320__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Evaluating whether such an abatement would be
beneficial for the economic development of the county, city or town.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-320__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Issuing a certificate of endorsement for an
application for such an abatement that is found to be beneficial for the
economic development of the county, city or town.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-320__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person whose application has been
endorsed by the governing body of the county, city or town, as applicable,
pursuant to this section may submit the application to the Office of Economic
Development. The Office shall approve the application if the Office makes the
following determinations:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-320__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The business is consistent with:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="274-320__subsec_3__subsec_a__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The State Plan for Economic
Development developed by the Administrator pursuant to subsection 2 ofNRS 231.053; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="274-320__subsec_3__subsec_a__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Any guidelines adopted by the
Administrator to implement the State Plan for Economic Development.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-320__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Not later than 1 year after the date on which
the application was received by the Office, the applicant has executed an
agreement with the Office which states:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="274-320__subsec_3__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The date on which the abatement
becomes effective, as agreed to by the applicant and the Office, which must not
be earlier than the date on which the Office received the application and not
later than 1 year after the date on which the Office approves the application;
and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="274-320__subsec_3__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>That the business will, after the date
on which the abatement becomes effective:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (I) Continue in operation in the
historically underutilized business zone, as defined in 15 U.S.C. ï¿½ 632,
redevelopment area created pursuant tochapter 279of NRS, area eligible for a community development block grant pursuant to 24
C.F.R. Part 570 or enterprise community established pursuant to 24 C.F.R. Part
597 for a period specified by the Office, which must be at least 5 years; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (II) Continue to meet the
eligibility requirements set forth in this subsection.
ï¿½The
agreement must bind successors in interest of the business for the specified
period.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-320__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The business is registered pursuant to the
laws of this State or the applicant commits to obtain a valid business license
and all other permits required by the county, city or town in which the
business operates.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-320__subsec_3__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The applicant invested or commits to invest a
minimum of $250,000 in capital equipment that will be retained at the location
of the business in the historically underutilized business zone, as defined in
15 U.S.C. ï¿½ 632, redevelopment area created pursuant tochapter 279of NRS, area eligible for a community
development block grant pursuant to 24 C.F.R. Part 570 or enterprise community
established pursuant to 24 C.F.R. Part 597 until at least the date which is 5
years after the date on which the abatement becomes effective.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-320__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the Office of Economic Development
approves an application for a partial abatement, the Office shall immediately
forward a certificate of eligibility for the abatement to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-320__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Department of Taxation; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-320__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Nevada Tax Commission.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-320__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the Office of Economic Development
approves an application for a partial abatement pursuant to this section:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-320__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The partial abatement must be for a duration
of not less than 1 year but not more than 5 years.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-320__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the abatement is from the property tax
imposed pursuant tochapter 361of NRS, the
partial abatement must not exceed 75 percent of the taxes on personal property
payable by a business each year pursuant to that chapter.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-320__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If an applicant for a partial abatement
pursuant to this section fails to execute the agreement described in paragraph</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-320__subsec_6__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 3 within 1 year after the date on which the application was
received by the Office, the applicant shall not be approved for a partial
abatement pursuant to this section unless the applicant submits a new request
pursuant to subsection 1.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-320__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a business whose partial abatement
has been approved pursuant to this section and is in effect ceases:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-320__subsec_7__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>To meet the eligibility requirements for the
partial abatement; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-320__subsec_7__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Operation before the time specified in the
agreement described in paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-320__subsec_7__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 3,
ï¿½the business
shall repay to the Department of Taxation the amount of the partial abatement
that was allowed pursuant to this section before the failure of the business to
comply unless the Nevada Tax Commission determines that the business has
substantially complied with the requirements of this section. Except as
otherwise provided inNRS 360.232and360.320, the business shall, in addition to
the amount of the partial abatement required to be paid pursuant to this
subsection, pay interest on the amount due at the rate most recently
established pursuant toNRS 99.040for each
month, or portion thereof, from the last day of the month following the period
for which the payment would have been made had the partial abatement not been
approved until the date of payment of the tax.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-320__subsec_8">
            <num>8.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Office of Economic Development may
adopt such regulations as the Office determines to be necessary or advisable to
carry out the provisions of this section.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-320__subsec_9">
            <num>9.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An applicant for an abatement who is
aggrieved by a final decision of the Office of Economic Development may
petition for judicial review in the manner provided inchapter 233Bof NRS.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2005,
640; A2011,
3454;2013,
27th Special Session, 23;2015,
1076,3054;2019,
2228;2021,
2313)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_274-330">
          <num>274.330</num>
          <heading>Abatement for businesses in certain areas of economic
development that hire dislocated workers: Endorsement required; application;
requirements for approval; certificate of eligibility; duration and amount of
abatement; repayment required under certain circumstances; regulations;
judicial review. [Effective through June 30, 2032.]</heading>
          <subsection eId="274-330__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who owns a business which is
located within an enterprise community established pursuant to 24 C.F.R. Part
597 in this State may submit a request to the governing body of the county,
city or town in which the business is located for an endorsement of an
application by the person to the Office of Economic Development for a partial
abatement of one or more of the taxes imposed pursuant tochapter 361of NRS or the local sales and use
taxes. The governing body of the county, city or town shall provide notice of
the request to the board of trustees of the school district in which the
business operates. The notice must set forth the date, time and location of the
hearing at which the governing body will consider whether to endorse the
application. As used in this subsection, ï¿½local sales and use taxesï¿½ means the
taxes imposed on the gross receipts of any retailer from the sale of tangible
personal property sold at retail, or stored, used or otherwise consumed, in the
political subdivision in which the business is located, except the taxes
imposed by the Sales and Use Tax Act and the Local School Support Tax Law.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-330__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The governing body of a county, city or
town shall develop procedures for:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-330__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Evaluating whether such an abatement would be
beneficial for the economic development of the county, city or town.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-330__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Issuing a certificate of endorsement for an
application for such an abatement that is found to be beneficial for the
economic development of the county, city or town.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-330__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person whose application has been
endorsed by the governing body of the county, city or town, as applicable,
pursuant to this section may submit the application to the Office of Economic
Development. The Office shall approve the application if the Office makes the
following determinations:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-330__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The business is consistent with:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="274-330__subsec_3__subsec_a__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The State Plan for Economic
Development developed by the Administrator pursuant to subsection 2 ofNRS 231.053; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="274-330__subsec_3__subsec_a__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Any guidelines adopted by the
Administrator to implement the State Plan for Economic Development.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-330__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Not later than 1 year after the date on which
the application was received by the Office, the applicant has executed an
agreement with the Office which states:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="274-330__subsec_3__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The date on which the abatement
becomes effective, as agreed to by the applicant and the Office, which must not
be earlier than the date on which the Office received the application and not
later than 1 year after the date on which the Office approves the application;
and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="274-330__subsec_3__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>That the business will, after the date
on which the abatement becomes effective:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (I) Continue in operation in the
enterprise community for a period specified by the Office, which must be at
least 5 years; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (II) Continue to meet the
eligibility requirements set forth in this subsection.
ï¿½The
agreement must bind successors in interest of the business for the specified
period.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-330__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The business is registered pursuant to the
laws of this State or the applicant commits to obtain a valid business license
and all other permits required by the county, city or town in which the
business operates.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-330__subsec_3__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The business:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="274-330__subsec_3__subsec_d__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Employs one or more dislocated workers
who reside in the enterprise community; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="274-330__subsec_3__subsec_d__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Pays such employees a wage of not less
than 100 percent of the federally designated level signifying poverty for a
family of four persons and provides medical benefits to the employees and their
dependents which meet the minimum requirements for medical benefits established
by the Office.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-330__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the Office of Economic Development
approves an application for a partial abatement, the Office shall:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-330__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Determine the percentage of employees of the
business which meet the requirements of paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-330__subsec_4__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 3 and grant
a partial abatement equal to that percentage; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-330__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Immediately forward a certificate of
eligibility for the abatement to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="274-330__subsec_4__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The Department of Taxation;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="274-330__subsec_4__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The Nevada Tax Commission; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="274-330__subsec_4__subsec_b__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If the partial abatement is from the
property tax imposed pursuant tochapter 361of NRS, the county treasurer of the county in which the business is located.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-330__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the Office of Economic Development
approves an application for a partial abatement pursuant to this section:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-330__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The partial abatement must be for a duration
of not less than 1 year but not more than 5 years.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-330__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the abatement is from the property tax
imposed pursuant tochapter 361of NRS, the
partial abatement must not exceed 75 percent of the taxes on personal property
payable by a business each year pursuant to that chapter.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-330__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If an applicant for a partial abatement
pursuant to this section fails to execute the agreement described in paragraph</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-330__subsec_6__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 3 within 1 year after the date on which the application was
received by the Office, the applicant shall not be approved for a partial
abatement pursuant to this section unless the applicant submits a new request
pursuant to subsection 1.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-330__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a business whose partial abatement
has been approved pursuant to this section and is in effect ceases:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-330__subsec_7__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>To meet the eligibility requirements for the
partial abatement; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-330__subsec_7__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Operation before the time specified in the
agreement described in paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-330__subsec_7__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 3,
ï¿½the business
shall repay to the Department of Taxation or, if the partial abatement was from
the property tax imposed pursuant tochapter 361of NRS, to the county treasurer, the amount of the partial abatement that was
allowed pursuant to this section before the failure of the business to comply
unless the Nevada Tax Commission determines that the business has substantially
complied with the requirements of this section. Except as otherwise provided inNRS 360.232and360.320, the business shall, in addition to
the amount of the partial abatement required to be paid pursuant to this
subsection, pay interest on the amount due at the rate most recently
established pursuant toNRS 99.040for
each month, or portion thereof, from the last day of the month following the
period for which the payment would have been made had the partial abatement not
been approved until the date of payment of the tax.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-330__subsec_8">
            <num>8.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Office of Economic Development:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-330__subsec_8__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Shall adopt regulations relating to the
minimum level of benefits that a business must provide to its employees to
qualify for an abatement pursuant to this section.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-330__subsec_8__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>May adopt such other regulations as the
Office determines to be necessary or advisable to carry out the provisions of
this section.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-330__subsec_9">
            <num>9.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An applicant for an abatement who is
aggrieved by a final decision of the Office of Economic Development may
petition for judicial review in the manner provided inchapter 233Bof NRS.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="274-330__subsec_10">
            <num>10.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, ï¿½dislocated
workerï¿½ means a person who:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="274-330__subsec_10__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Has been terminated, laid off or received
notice of termination or layoff from employment;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-330__subsec_10__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Is eligible for or receiving or has exhausted
his or her entitlement to unemployment compensation;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-330__subsec_10__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Has been dependent on the income of another
family member but is no longer supported by that income;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-330__subsec_10__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Has been self-employed but is no longer
receiving an income from self-employment because of general economic conditions
in the community or natural disaster; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="274-330__subsec_10__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Is currently unemployed and unable to return
to a previous industry or occupation.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2005,
641; A2011,
3456;2013,
27th Special Session, 25;2015,
1078,3056;2019,
2232;2021,
2315)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>