<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="NRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-155"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-155"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#nevada-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-nv"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="155"/>
          <FRBRname value="NRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-155/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-155/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-155/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-155/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="nevada-legislature" href="https://www.leg.state.nv.us" showAs="Nevada State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_155">
        <num>155</num>
        <heading>NOTICES, TRANSFERS, ORDERS,</heading>
        <section eId="sec_155-005">
          <num>155.005</num>
          <heading>Enlargement.</heading>
          <subsection eId="155-005__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The period may be extended upon the
agreement of all interested persons, by written stipulation of counsel filed in
the action; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-005__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court, for good cause shown, may at
any time:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="155-005__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Regardless of whether there has been a
motion, petition or notice, order that the period be extended if a request for
the extension is made before the expiration of the specified period as
originally prescribed or as extended by a previous order; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-005__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Upon a motion made after the expiration of
the specified period, authorize a person to perform the act if the failure to
perform the act in a timely manner was the result of excusable neglect.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2017,
1685)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-010">
          <num>155.010</num>
          <heading>Method of giving notice; notice to certain persons required;
court may dispense with notice; proof; waiver of notice.</heading>
          <subsection eId="155-010__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in this
section or a specific statute relating to the kind of notice required or
otherwise ordered by the court in a particular instance, a petitioner shall
cause notice of the time and place of the hearing of a petition to be given to
each interested person and to every other person entitled to notice pursuant to
this title or his or her attorney if the person has appeared by attorney or
requested that notice be sent to his or her attorney. Notice must be given:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="155-010__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>By mailing a copy thereof at least 10 days
before the time set for the hearing by certified, registered or ordinary
first-class mail addressed to the person being notified at the post office
address given in the personï¿½s demand for notice, if any, or at his or her
office or place of residence, if known, or by personally delivering a copy
thereof to the person being notified at least 10 days before the time set for
the hearing;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-010__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>By submitting a copy thereof through an
electronic filing system, if the court establishes such a system pursuant to
the Nevada Electronic Filing and Conversion Rules or by any other electronic
means if the interested person or person entitled to notice consents in
writing; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-010__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the address or identity of the person is
not known and cannot be ascertained with reasonable diligence, by publishing at
least once a week for 3 consecutive weeks a copy thereof in a newspaper having
general circulation in the county where the hearing is to be held, the last
publication of which must be at least 10 days before the date set for the
hearing.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-010__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who, for the purposes of the
matter to be considered at a hearing, is not an interested person is not
entitled to notice of that hearing.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-010__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court, for good cause shown, may
provide for a different method or time of giving notice for any hearing, or may
dispense with the notice otherwise required to be given to a person under this
title.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-010__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Proof of the giving of notice must be
made on or before the hearing and filed in the proceeding.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-010__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person entitled to notice may, in
writing, waive notice of the hearing of a petition.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-010__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notice given pursuant to paragraph</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="155-010__subsec_6__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-010__subsec_6__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 1 is complete upon electronic submission of any kind,
unless the petitioner is notified pursuant to the Nevada Electronic Filing and
Conversion Rules that the service was not effectuated on the person intended to
be served by such electronic means.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [283:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.283]—(NRS A1961,
407;1967,
352;1969,
95;1975,
1778;1977,
273;1997,
1492;1999,
2359;2015,
3534;2023,
1319)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-020">
          <num>155.020</num>
          <heading>Method and form for notices.</heading>
          <subsection eId="155-020__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notice of a petition for the probate of
a will and the issuance of letters and the notice to creditors must be given
to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="155-020__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The persons respectively entitled thereto,
including the Director of the Department of Health and Human Services, as
provided inNRS 155.010; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-020__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The public, including creditors whose names
and addresses are not readily ascertainable, by publication on three dates of
publication before the hearing, and if the newspaper is published more than
once each week, there must be at least 10 days from the first to last dates of
publication, including both the first and last days.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-020__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every publication required by this
section must be made in a newspaper published in the county where the
proceedings are pending, but if there is not such a newspaper, then in one
having general circulation in that county.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-020__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The notice of the hearing upon the
petition to administer the estate must be in substantially the following form:
NOTICE
OF THE HEARING UPON THE PETITION TO
ADMINISTER
THE ESTATE
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ Notice is hereby given that
................................ has filed in this court a petition for the
probate of a will and for letters testamentary, or for letters of
administration, of the estate of ................................, deceased,
and a hearing has been set for the .......... day of the month
of................, of the year......, at .......... (a.m. or p.m.) at the
courthouse of the above-entitled court. All persons interested in the estate
are notified to appear and show cause why the petition should not be granted.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ Dated ....................................
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-020__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As soon as practicable after
appointment, a personal representative shall, in addition to publishing the notice
to creditors, mail a copy of the notice to those creditors whose names and
addresses are readily ascertainable as of the date of first publication of the
notice and who have not already filed a claim. The notice must be in
substantially the following form:
NOTICE
TO CREDITORS
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ Notice is hereby given that
the undersigned has been appointed and qualified by the (giving the title of
the court and the date of appointment) as personal representative of the estate
of ................................, deceased. All creditors having claims
against the estate are required to file the claims with the clerk of the court
within .......... (60 or 90) days after the mailing or the first publication
(as the case may be) of this notice.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ Dated ....................................
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-020__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If before the last day for the filing
of a creditorï¿½s claim underNRS 147.040,
the personal representative discovers the existence of a creditor who was not
readily ascertainable at the time of first publication of the notice to
creditors, the personal representative shall immediately mail a copy of the
notice to the creditor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [284:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.284]—(NRS A1961,
408;1975,
1779;1985,
2037;1987,
782;1995,
2577;1997,
1493;1999,
2359;2001,
164;2003,
885)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-030">
          <num>155.030</num>
          <heading>Request for special notice: Filing by interested person after
issuance of letters; filing by interested person in testamentary trust; effect
of substitution or withdrawal of counsel.</heading>
          <subsection eId="155-030__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>At any time after the issuance of
letters in the estate of a decedent, an interested person or the personï¿½s
attorney may serve upon the personal representative or the personal
representativeï¿½s attorney, and file with the clerk of the court wherein
administration of the estate is pending, a written request stating that the
interested person desires special notice and a copy of any further filings,
steps or proceedings in the administration of the estate.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-030__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The request must state the post office
address of the requester or the requesterï¿½s attorney, and thereafter a brief
notice of the filing of any returns, petitions, accounts, reports or other
proceedings, together with a copy of the filing, must be addressed to that
person or the personï¿½s attorney, at his or her stated mailing address, and
deposited with the United States Postal Service with the postage thereon
prepaid, within 2 days after each is filed, or personal service of the notice
may be made on the person or the personï¿½s attorney within the 2 days, and the
personal service is equivalent to deposit in the post office, and proof of
mailing or of personal service must be filed with the clerk before the hearing
of the proceeding.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-030__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If, upon the hearing, it appears to the
satisfaction of the court that the notice has been regularly given, the court
shall so find in its order and the order is final and conclusive upon all
persons.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-030__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An interested person in a testamentary
trust or its property, or the attorney for that person, may serve upon the
trustee or the trusteeï¿½s attorney, and file with the clerk of the court wherein
administration of the trust is pending, a written request stating that he or
she desires notice of the filing of accounts and petitions in connection with
the trust. The provisions of subsections 2 and 3 apply to such a request.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-030__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An attorney whose only appearance on
behalf of an interested person has been the filing of a written request for
notice pursuant to subsection 1 may, without further court order:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="155-030__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Terminate his or her services;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-030__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Serve upon the personal representative or the
personal representativeï¿½s attorney an amended written request for notice
directing that any further notice be sent to the interested person at his or
her last known address; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-030__subsec_5__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>File the amended written request for notice
with the clerk of the court wherein administration of the estate is pending.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-030__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any filing of a motion for substitution
of counsel or order authorizing withdrawal of counsel of record for an attorney
who has filed a written request for notice on behalf of an interested person
pursuant to subsection 1 shall be deemed to be an amended written request for
notice as described in subsection 5, and any further notice must be sent to the
address provided in the motion for substitution of counsel or the order
authorizing the withdrawal of counsel, as applicable.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-030__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>On the filing of an inventory or a
supplementary inventory, the personal representative shall mail a copy to each
person who has requested special notice.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 119:107:1941; A1951,
464]—(NRS A1975,
1780;1987,
702;1999,
2360;2011,
1462)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-040">
          <num>155.040</num>
          <heading>Personal notice by citation.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If
personal notice is required by this title to be given to any person in the
matter of an estate or testamentary trust, and no other mode of giving notice
is prescribed, it must be given by citation, issued by the clerk and directed
to the person to be served, and must command the person to appear before the
court at a time and place to be named in the citation. The nature or character
of the proceedings must be briefly stated in the citation, and a copy of the
petition, if any, must be attached.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [285:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.285]—(NRS A1999,
2361)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-050">
          <num>155.050</num>
          <heading>Service of citation.</heading>
          <subsection eId="155-050__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The citation described inNRS 155.040must be served by:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="155-050__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Certified mail, with a return receipt
requested, on each person required to be served; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-050__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Personal service in the manner provided
pursuant toRule 4</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-050__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of the
Nevada Rules of Civil Procedure.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-050__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If, after due diligence, service cannot
be made upon the person to be served, service of the citation may be made by
publication in the manner provided byRule
4</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="155-050__subsec_2__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of the Nevada Rules of Civil Procedure, by leaving a copy with the
personï¿½s attorney of record or in such other manner as the court may direct.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [286:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.286]—(NRS A2017,
1685)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-060">
          <num>155.060</num>
          <heading>Time for service of citation.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If
no other time is specially prescribed, a citation must be served at least 10
days before the day of the hearing, but the court may, for good cause shown,
shorten the time to no less than 1 full judicial day before the day of the
hearing.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [288:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.288]—(NRS A1999,
2361)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-070">
          <num>155.070</num>
          <heading>Number of publications; extension or shortening of time.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If publication is required, the publication
must be made daily, or otherwise, as often during the prescribed period as the
newspaper is regularly issued, unless otherwise provided in this title. The
court, however, may prescribe less publications during the period for
publication, and the court may, for good cause shown, extend or shorten any of
the times prescribed in this title.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 282:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.282]—(NRS A1999,
2361)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-080">
          <num>155.080</num>
          <heading>Methods of proving publication or service of notice.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>All proofs of publication or other mode or
modes of giving notice or serving papers may be made by the certificate or
affidavit of any person competent to be a witness. The certificate or affidavit
must be filed, and constitutes prima facie evidence of publication or service.
Proof of service may also be made in any manner permitted by the Nevada Rules
of Civil Procedure.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [287:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.287]—(NRS A1979,
450;1999,
2362)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-090">
          <num>155.090</num>
          <heading>Clerk may give notices and certain citations without court
order.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>All notices required to be
given by this title may be given by the clerk of the court without an order
from the court, and, when so given, for the time and in the manner required by
law, they are as legal and valid as though made upon an order from the court.
If use of a citation is authorized or required by statute, the citation may be
issued by the clerk of the court on the request of a party or the partyï¿½s
attorney, without a court order, unless an order is expressly required by the
statute.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [322:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.322]—(NRS A1999,
2362)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-093">
          <num>155.093</num>
          <heading>Definitions.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>As
used inNRS 155.093to155.098, inclusive, unless the context
otherwise requires, the words and terms defined inNRS 155.0935to155.0965, inclusive, have the meanings
ascribed to them in those sections.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2011,
1459; A2015,
3534)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-0935">
          <num>155.0935</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Caregiverï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Caregiverï¿½
means a person who provides health or social services to a dependent adult for
remuneration other than a donative transfer pursuant to this chapter or the
reimbursement of expenses.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2011,
1459; A2015,
3534)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-0937">
          <num>155.0937</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Dependent adultï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <subsection eId="155-0937__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Is unable, without assistance, to
provide properly for his or her personal needs for physical health, food,
clothing or shelter; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-0937__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Has difficulty managing his or her own
financial resources without assistance or resisting fraud or undue influence.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2015,
3533)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-0939">
          <num>155.0939</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Health and social servicesï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Health
and social servicesï¿½ means services provided to a dependent adult because of
his or her dependent condition, including, without limitation, the
administration of medicine, medical testing, wound care, assistance with
hygiene, companionship, housekeeping, shopping, cooking or assistance with
finances.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2015,
3533)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-094">
          <num>155.094</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Independent attorneyï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <subsection eId="155-094__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The term includes, without limitation,
the drafting attorney representing the transferor in preparation of the
transfer instrument if the drafting attorney is not a person described in
paragraph</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="155-094__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-094__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 1.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2011,
1459; A2015,
3535;2021,
978)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-0945">
          <num>155.0945</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Related to, affiliated with or subordinate to any personï¿½
defined.</heading>
          <subsection eId="155-0945__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The personï¿½s spouse;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-0945__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A relative of the person within the
third degree of consanguinity;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-0945__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A co-owner of a business with the
person;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-0945__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An employee of a business if the
person:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="155-0945__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Has an ownership interest in the business; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-0945__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Holds a supervisory position with the
business;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-0945__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An attorney or employee of a law firm
for which the person is or was a client;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-0945__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The spouse of any person described in
subsections 2 to 5, inclusive; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-0945__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any entity owned or controlled by a
person described in subsections 1 to 6, inclusive.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2011,
1459; A2015,
3535)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-0955">
          <num>155.0955</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Transfer instrumentï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <subsection eId="155-0955__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A will;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-0955__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A trust;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-0955__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A deed; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-0955__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any form, contract or other document
which:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="155-0955__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Creates, conveys or transfers any interest in
property;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-0955__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Creates any type of joint ownership;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-0955__subsec_4__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Establishes a right of survivorship;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-0955__subsec_4__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Designates a beneficiary;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-0955__subsec_4__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Adds an authorized signer on any bank or
brokerage account;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-0955__subsec_4__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Creates or attempts to effectuate a
nonprobate transfer to be effective upon the death of the transferor; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-0955__subsec_4__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Is intended to amend, modify, eliminate,
supersede or revoke any other transfer instrument.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2011,
1460; A2015,
3535)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-096">
          <num>155.096</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Transfereeï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Transfereeï¿½
means a devisee, a beneficiary of trust, a grantee of a deed, including a
grantee of a deed pursuant toNRS 111.655to111.699, inclusive, and any other
person designated in a transfer instrument to receive a nonprobate transfer or
other interest in property for less than fair market value.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2011,
1460; A2015,
3535)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-0965">
          <num>155.0965</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Transferorï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Transferorï¿½
means a testator, settlor, grantor of a deed and a decedent whose interest is
transferred pursuant to a nonprobate transfer.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2011,
1460)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-0967">
          <num>155.0967</num>
          <heading>Jurisdiction over assets of estate or trust of decedent;
jurisdiction over certain persons; sanctions.</heading>
          <subsection eId="155-0967__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In a proceeding involving the estate of
a decedent or a testamentary trust, the court has jurisdiction over the assets
of the estate or trust as a proceeding in rem.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-0967__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In addition to any other basis for
claiming jurisdiction over a person, the court has personal jurisdiction over
each person:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="155-0967__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Who is appointed as a personal representative
by the court;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-0967__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Whose appointment as a trustee is confirmed
by the court;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-0967__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Who files with the court a petition, a
motion, other than a motion for dismissal for lack of jurisdiction, an
objection or a joinder to a petition or motion;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-0967__subsec_2__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Who makes an appearance at a hearing of a
proceeding involving the estate of a decedent or a testamentary trust, unless
the appearance is made solely for the purpose of objecting to the jurisdiction
of the court; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-0967__subsec_2__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Who is a party to a proceeding commenced by a
petition filed pursuant toNRS 153.031if notice is given pursuant toNRS 155.010.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-0967__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Sanctions against a person that are
imposed by the court pursuant to any provision of law or the terms of a will or
testamentary trust are limited to that personï¿½s interest in the estate or trust
unless the court has personal jurisdiction over that person.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2015,
3533)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-097">
          <num>155.097</num>
          <heading>Validity; circumstances in which transfer is presumed void;
rebuttable presumption; exceptions.</heading>
          <subsection eId="155-097__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Regardless of when a transfer
instrument is made, to the extent the court finds that a transfer was the
product of fraud, duress or undue influence, the transfer is void and each
transferee who is found responsible for the fraud, duress or undue influence
shall bear the costs of the proceedings, including, without limitation,
reasonable attorneyï¿½s fees.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-097__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 4 andNRS 155.0975, a
transfer is presumed to be void if the transfer is to a transferee who is:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="155-097__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The person who drafted the transfer instrument;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-097__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A caregiver of the transferor who is a
dependent adult;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-097__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A person who materially participated in
formulating the dispositive provisions of the transfer instrument or paid for
the drafting of the transfer instrument; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-097__subsec_2__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A person who is related to, affiliated with
or subordinate to any person described in paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-097__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-097__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-097__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-097__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The presumption created by this section
is a presumption concerning the burden of proof and may be rebutted by proving,
by clear and convincing evidence that the donative transfer was not the product
of fraud, duress or undue influence.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-097__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of subsection 2 do not
apply to a transfer instrument that is intended to effectuate a transfer:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="155-097__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>After the transferorï¿½s death, unless the
transfer instrument is made on or after October 1, 2011; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-097__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>During the transferorï¿½s lifetime, unless the
transfer instrument is made on or after October 1, 2015.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2011,
1460; A2015,
3536)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-0975">
          <num>155.0975</num>
          <heading>Exceptions to presumption that certain transfers are void.</heading>
          <subsection eId="155-0975__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>To the spouse of the transferor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-0975__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>To a transfer of property which is
triggered by the transferorï¿½s death if the transferee is an heir of the
transferor and the combined value of all transfers received by that transferee
is not greater than the share the transferee would be entitled to pursuant tochapter 134of NRS if the testator had died
intestate and the transferorï¿½s estate included all nonprobate transfers which
are triggered by the death of the transferor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-0975__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in this
subsection, if the court determines, upon clear and convincing evidence, that
the transfer was not the product of fraud, duress or undue influence. The
determination of the court pursuant to this subsection must not be based solely
upon the testimony of a person described in subsection 2 ofNRS 155.097.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-0975__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the transfer instrument is reviewed
by an independent attorney who:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="155-0975__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Counsels the transferor about the nature and
consequences of the intended transfer;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-0975__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Attempts to determine if the intended
consequence is the result of fraud, duress or undue influence; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-0975__subsec_4__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Signs and delivers to the transferor an
original certificate of that review in substantially the following form:
CERTIFICATE
OF INDEPENDENT REVIEW
I, ..............................
(attorneyï¿½s name), have reviewed .............................. (name of
transfer instrument) and have counseled my client, ..............................
(name of client), on the nature and consequences of the transfer or transfers
of property to .............................. (name of transferee) contained in
the transfer instrument. I am disassociated from the interest of the transferee
to the extent that I am in a position to advise my client independently,
impartially and confidentially as to the consequences of the transfer. On the
basis of this counsel, I conclude that the transfer or transfers of property in
the transfer instrument that otherwise might be invalid pursuant toNRS 155.097are valid because the transfer
or transfers are not the product of fraud, duress or undue influence.
................................................................................
(Name of Attorney)ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Date)
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-0975__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>To a transferee that is:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="155-0975__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A federal, state or local public entity; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-0975__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An entity that is recognized as exempt under
section 501</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-0975__subsec_5__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="155-0975__subsec_5__subsec_c__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>or 501</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-0975__subsec_5__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="155-0975__subsec_5__subsec_c__subsec_19">
                <num>(19)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>of the Internal Revenue Code, 26 U.S.C. ï¿½
501</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-0975__subsec_5__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="155-0975__subsec_5__subsec_c__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>or 501</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-0975__subsec_5__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="155-0975__subsec_5__subsec_c__subsec_19">
                <num>(19)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>, or a trust holding an interest for such an entity but
only to the extent of the interest of the entity or the interest of the trustee
of the trust.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-0975__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>To a transfer of property if the fair
market value of the property does not exceed $3,000. The exclusion provided by
this subsection does not apply more than once in each calendar year to
transfers made during the transferorï¿½s lifetime. For the purposes of this
subsection, regardless of the number of transfer instruments involved, the
value of property transferred to a transferee pursuant to a transfer that is
triggered by the transferorï¿½s death must include the value of all property
transferred to that transferee or for such transfereeï¿½s benefit after the
transferorï¿½s death.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2011,
1460; A2015,
3536)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-098">
          <num>155.098</num>
          <heading>Common law.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The
provisions ofNRS 155.097and155.0975do not abrogate or limit any
principle or rule of the common law, unless the common law principle or rule is
inconsistent with the provisions ofNRS
155.097and155.0975.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2011,
1461)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-100">
          <num>155.100</num>
          <heading>Entry of minutes by clerk.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The
clerk shall enter a minute of all proceedings in matters of estates, as in
other actions.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 282:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.282]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-110">
          <num>155.110</num>
          <heading>Transcripts of minutes or copies of order and certificate of
clerk have same force as letters.</heading>
          <subsection eId="155-110__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A transcript from the minutes of court,
or a copy of the signed order of the court, showing the appointment of any
person as personal representative, together with the certificate of the clerk
that the person has given bond, if required, and has been qualified, and that
letters have been issued to him or her, and have not been revoked, has the same
effect in evidence as the letters themselves.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-110__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A copy of the letters, with like
certificate, has the same effect.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [95:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.95]—(NRS A1999,
2362)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-120">
          <num>155.120</num>
          <heading>Recordation of order setting apart homestead.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If an order is entered setting apart a
homestead, a certified copy of the order shall be recorded in the office of the
county recorder of the county where the property is located.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [292:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.292]—(NRS A1999,
2362)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-123">
          <num>155.123</num>
          <heading>Temporary restraining orders or injunctions issued to protect
assets of estate or trust.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>In
accordance with the provisions ofNRS 33.010and the Nevada Rules of Civil Procedure, and upon such terms and conditions as
the court deems just and appropriate, the court may issue a temporary
restraining order or an injunction to preserve and protect assets of the estate
or trust.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1999,
2358)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-127">
          <num>155.127</num>
          <heading>Order nunc pro tunc to correct previous order: Issuance; form;
use of original order; manner of correction.</heading>
          <subsection eId="155-127__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If through inadvertence or mistake an
order entered fails to state correctly the order made by the court, and the
inadvertence or mistake is brought to the attention of the court by petition or
the court acts on its own motion, the court may enter an order nunc pro tunc
correcting the previous order.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-127__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The order nunc pro tunc must be in the
form of an amended order and bear the caption ï¿½Amended Order of .....ï¿½ The body
of the amended order must be identical to the order being corrected, except for
the correction, and conclude with language substantially as follows: ï¿½This is
an order nunc pro tunc correcting the previous order of ...., dated .....ï¿½
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-127__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the order to be amended is many
pages in length, the court may cause to be filed a document captioned
ï¿½Amendment to Order of ....ï¿½ which addresses only the correction, together with
sufficient language to identify the correction, and concludes with the same
language as an amended order. Such an amendment to an order must be accompanied
by a verified petition, or an affidavit of counsel, specifying the reasons for
the correction.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-127__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The original order may not be
physically changed, but must be used in conjunction with the order nunc pro
tunc correcting it. In making corrections in the amendment document, a complete
clause or sentence must be stricken and replaced, even if the only change is to
correct a single word or figure.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1999,
2358; A2001,
164)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-130">
          <num>155.130</num>
          <heading>Proceedings concerning estate are proceedings of record.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>All proceedings in matters of estate shall be
proceedings of record as other actions and proceedings.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 307:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.307]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-140">
          <num>155.140</num>
          <heading>General rules: Contents of pleading; effect of certain orders
binding persons; notices; appointment of guardian ad litem or attorney;
attorneyï¿½s fees and costs.</heading>
          <subsection eId="155-140__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In a proceeding involving the estate of
a decedent or a testamentary trust:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="155-140__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Interests to be affected must be described in
pleadings that give reasonable information to owners by name or class, by reference
to the instrument creating the interest or in another appropriate manner.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-140__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An order binding the sole holder or all
co-holders of a power of revocation or presently exercisable general power of
appointment, including a power of amendment, binds other persons to the extent
their interests, as objects, takers in default or otherwise, are subject to the
power.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-140__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>To the extent there is no conflict of
interest between them or among persons represented:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="155-140__subsec_1__subsec_c__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>An order binding a guardian of the
estate binds the person whose estate the guardian controls.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="155-140__subsec_1__subsec_c__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>An order binding a guardian of the
person binds the protected person if no separate guardian of the estate of the
protected person has been appointed.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="155-140__subsec_1__subsec_c__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>An order binding a trustee binds
beneficiaries of the trust in a proceeding to probate a will establishing or
adding to the trust, to review the acts or accounts of a previous fiduciary, or
involving creditors or other third parties.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="155-140__subsec_1__subsec_c__subsec_4">
                <num>(4)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>An order binding a personal
representative binds persons interested in the undistributed assets of the
estate of a decedent in an action or proceeding by or against the estate.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-140__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If there is no conflict of interest and no
guardian of the estate has been appointed, a parent may represent his or her
minor child.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-140__subsec_1__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An unborn or unascertained person who is not
otherwise represented is bound by an order to the extent his or her interest is
adequately represented by another person having a substantially identical
interest in the proceeding.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-140__subsec_1__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Notice as prescribed by this title must be
given to every interested person or to one who can bind an interested person
under paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-140__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-140__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-140__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>. Notice may be given both to a person and to
another who can bind him or her.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-140__subsec_1__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Notice is given to unborn or unascertained
persons who are not represented under paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-140__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-140__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-140__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>by giving
notice to all known persons whose interest in the proceeding is substantially
identical to that of the unborn or unascertained persons.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-140__subsec_1__subsec_h">
              <num>(h)</num>
              <content>
                <p>At any stage of a proceeding, the court may
appoint a guardian ad litem or an attorney to represent the interest of a
minor, an incapacitated, unborn or unascertained person, or a person whose
identity or address is unknown, if the court determines that representation of
the interest would otherwise be inadequate. If not precluded by conflict of
interest, a guardian ad litem or an attorney may be appointed to represent
several persons or interests. The court shall set out its reasons for
appointing a guardian ad litem or an attorney as a part of the record of the
proceeding.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-140__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If an attorney has been appointed for
minors or other interested persons, the attorney, until another may be
appointed, shall represent the person or persons for whom the attorney has been
appointed in all subsequent proceedings.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-140__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In any proceeding filed pursuant to
this title, the court has jurisdiction and authority to fix and adjudicate fees
and costs due an attorney from his or her client for services performed by the
attorney in connection with the proceeding.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-140__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, ï¿½protected
personï¿½ has the meaning ascribed to it inNRS 159.027.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 291:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.291]—(NRS A1999,
2362;2011,
1463)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-150">
          <num>155.150</num>
          <heading>Issues of fact and questions of costs.</heading>
          <subsection eId="155-150__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>All issues of fact in matters of an
estate must be disposed of in the same manner as is by law provided upon the
trial of issues of fact in a common-law action, but all matters must be tried
by the court except as otherwise provided inNRS
137.020.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-150__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>All questions of cost may be determined
by the court, and execution may issue therefor in accordance with the order of
the court.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [290:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.290]—(NRS A1999,
2363)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-160">
          <num>155.160</num>
          <heading>Responses and objections to proceedings.</heading>
          <subsection eId="155-160__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An interested person may appear and
make a response or objection in writing at or before the hearing.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-160__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An interested person may appear and
make a response or objection orally at the hearing. The court may hear and
determine the response or objection at the hearing or grant a continuance to
allow the response or objection to be made in writing.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-160__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the court is not in session at the
time set for the hearing of any matter concerning the settlement of the estate
of a decedent, anyone opposing the petition therein made may file objections
thereto with the clerk.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [323:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.323]—(NRS A1999,
2363)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-165">
          <num>155.165</num>
          <heading>Finding of vexatious litigant; sanctions; standing of interested
party and vexatious litigant under certain circumstances.</heading>
          <subsection eId="155-165__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court may find that a person,
including, without limitation, a personal representative or trustee, is a
vexatious litigant if the person files a petition, objection, motion or other
pleading which is without merit, intended to harass or annoy the personal
representative or a trustee or intended to unreasonably oppose or frustrate the
efforts of an interested person who is acting in good faith to enforce his or
her rights. The court may find that a personal representative or trustee is a
vexatious litigant if the personal representative or trustee has expended the
funds of the estate or trust to unreasonably oppose the good faith efforts of
an interested person to enforce his or her rights. In determining whether the
person is a vexatious litigant, the court may take into consideration whether
the person has previously filed pleadings in a proceeding that were without
merit, intended to harass or annoy a fiduciary or intended to unreasonably
oppose or frustrate the efforts of an interested person who is acting in good
faith to enforce his or her rights.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-165__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a court finds that a person is a
vexatious litigant pursuant to subsection 1, the court may impose sanctions on
the person in an amount sufficient to reimburse the estate or trust for all or
part of the expenses, including, without limitation, reasonable attorneyï¿½s
fees, incurred by the estate or trust to respond to the petition, objection,
motion or other pleading and for any other pecuniary losses which are
associated with the actions of the vexatious litigant. If a court finds that a
personal representative or trustee is a vexatious litigant, the court may
remove the personal representative or trustee and any sanctions imposed by the
court must be imposed against the personal representative or trustee personally
and not against the estate or trust. The court may make an order directing
entry of judgment for the amount of such sanctions.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-165__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The court may deny standing to an
interested party to bring a petition or motion if the court finds that:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="155-165__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The subject matter of the petition or motion
is unrelated to the interests of the interested party;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-165__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The interests of the interested party are
minimal as it relates to the subject matter of the petition or motion; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-165__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The interested party is a vexatious litigant
pursuant to subsection 1.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-165__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a court finds that a person is a
vexatious litigant pursuant to subsection 1, that person does not have standing
to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="155-165__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Object to the issuance of letters; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-165__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Request the removal of a personal
representative or a trustee.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2011,
1461; A2015,
3537)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-170">
          <num>155.170</num>
          <heading>Civil procedure.</heading>
          <subsection eId="155-170__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>May obtain discovery, perpetuate
testimony or conduct examinations in any manner authorized by law or by the
Nevada Rules of Civil Procedure relevant to such proceeding; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-170__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Is not required to satisfy any rule
requiring the initial disclosure of experts, attendance at an early case
conference or the filing of a report on an early case conference as a
prerequisite to commencing an action described in subsection 1.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [289:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.289]—(NRS A1999,
2364;2011,
1464)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-180">
          <num>155.180</num>
          <heading>Applicability of laws and rules regulating civil actions and
appeals.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Except as otherwise
specially provided in this title, all the provisions of law and the Nevada
Rules of Civil Procedure regulating proceedings in civil cases apply in matters
of probate, when appropriate, or may be applied as auxiliary to the provisions
of this title. The Nevada Rules of Appellate Procedure regulating appeals in
civil cases apply to appeals taken pursuant toNRS 155.190.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [319:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.319]—(NRS A1999,
2364)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-185">
          <num>155.185</num>
          <heading>Facsimile of petitions, notices, objections and other papers may
be filed.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If a petition, notice,
objection, consent, waiver or other paper may be filed, a true and correct
facsimile of it may be filed, if the original is filed within a reasonable
time.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1999,
2358)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-190">
          <num>155.190</num>
          <heading>Appealable orders.</heading>
          <subsection eId="155-190__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 2, in addition to any order from which an appeal is expressly
permitted by this title, an appeal may be taken to the appellate court of
competent jurisdiction pursuant to the rules fixed by the Supreme Court
pursuant toSection 4 of Article 6of the Nevada Constitution within 30 days after the notice of entry of an
order:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="155-190__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Granting or revoking letters testamentary or
letters of administration.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-190__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Admitting a will to probate or revoking the
probate thereof.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-190__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Setting aside an estate claimed not to exceed
$100,000 in value.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-190__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Setting apart property as a homestead, or
claimed to be exempt from execution.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-190__subsec_1__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Granting or modifying a family allowance.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-190__subsec_1__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Directing or authorizing the sale or
conveyance or confirming the sale of property.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-190__subsec_1__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Settling an account of a personal
representative or trustee.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-190__subsec_1__subsec_h">
              <num>(h)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Instructing or appointing a trustee.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-190__subsec_1__subsec_i">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Instructing or directing a personal
representative.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-190__subsec_1__subsec_j">
              <num>(j)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Directing or allowing the payment of a debt,
claim, devise or attorneyï¿½s fee.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-190__subsec_1__subsec_k">
              <num>(k)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Determining heirship or the persons to whom
distribution must be made or trust property must pass.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-190__subsec_1__subsec_l">
              <num>(l)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Distributing property.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-190__subsec_1__subsec_m">
              <num>(m)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Refusing to make any order mentioned in this
section.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-190__subsec_1__subsec_n">
              <num>(n)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Making any decision wherein the amount in
controversy equals or exceeds, exclusive of costs, $10,000.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-190__subsec_1__subsec_o">
              <num>(o)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Granting or denying a motion to enforce the
liability of a surety filed pursuant toNRS
142.035.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-190__subsec_1__subsec_p">
              <num>(p)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Granting an order for conveyance or transfer
pursuant toNRS 148.410.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-190__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a party timely files in the district
court any of the following motions under the Nevada Rules of Civil Procedure,
the time to file a notice of appeal pursuant to this section runs for all
parties from entry of an order disposing of the last such remaining motion, and
the notice of appeal must be filed not later than 30 days after the date of
service of written notice of entry of that order:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="155-190__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A motion for judgment under Rule 50</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-190__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-190__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A motion under Rule 52</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-190__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>to amend or make
additional findings of fact;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-190__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A motion under Rule 59 to alter or amend the
judgment; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="155-190__subsec_2__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A motion for a new trial under Rule 59.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [293:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.293]—(NRS A1981,
463;1983,
670;1995,
19;1997,
1494;1999,
2364;2001,
2349;2009,
1635;2013,
1748)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-195">
          <num>155.195</num>
          <heading>Effect of appeal of order.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Unless
otherwise ordered by the court, an appeal pursuant toNRS 155.190does not stay any order or
proceeding in the estate or trust. The court may grant a stay, pending the
appeal, of an order from which the appeal was taken, upon such bond,
undertaking or conditions as it deems just or appropriate.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1999,
2358)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-200">
          <num>155.200</num>
          <heading>No undertaking on appeal required of personal representative.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>An appeal by a personal representative who has
given an official bond as provided in this title is complete and effectual
without an undertaking on appeal.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [295:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.295]—(NRS A1999,
2365)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-210">
          <num>155.210</num>
          <heading>Power of appellate court on appeal.</heading>
          <subsection eId="155-210__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon an appeal, the appellate court of
competent jurisdiction pursuant to the rules fixed by the Supreme Court
pursuant toSection 4 of Article 6of the Nevada Constitution may reverse, affirm or modify the order appealed from,
and as to any or all of the parties, and order a remittitur as in other cases,
and may order costs to be paid by any party to the proceeding, or out of the
estate, as justice may require.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="155-210__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Execution for costs may issue out of
the district court.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [294a:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.294a]—(NRS A1999,
2365;2013,
1749)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_155-220">
          <num>155.220</num>
          <heading>Reversal of order appointing personal representative.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If an order appointing a personal
representative is reversed on appeal, all lawful acts in administration of the
estate performed by the personal representative are as valid as if the order
had been affirmed.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 296:107:1941; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 9882.296]—(NRS A1999,
2365)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>