<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="NRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-549"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-549"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#nevada-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-nv"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="549"/>
          <FRBRname value="NRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-549/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-549/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-549/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-549/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="nevada-legislature" href="https://www.leg.state.nv.us" showAs="Nevada State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_549">
        <num>549</num>
        <heading>EXTENSION WORK IN</heading>
        <section eId="sec_549-005">
          <num>549.005</num>
          <heading>State land grant institutions.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The
state land grant institutions of the University of Nevada are the University of
Nevada, Las Vegas, the University of Nevada, Reno, and the Desert Research
Institute.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2021,
2658)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_549-010">
          <num>549.010</num>
          <heading>Cooperative agreements between boards of county commissioners
and Nevada System of Higher Education.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>To
provide for continued educational, research, outreach and service programs
pertaining to agriculture, community development, health and nutrition,
horticulture, personal and family development, and natural resources in the
rural and urban communities in the State of Nevada, the Director of the
Agricultural Extension Department of the Public Service Division of the Nevada
System of Higher Education and the boards of county commissioners of any or all
of the respective counties of the State of Nevada may enter into cooperative
agreements and activities subject to the provisions of this chapter.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1:94:1947; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 356.1]—(NRS A1969,
1444;1993,
413;1999,
2550)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_549-020">
          <num>549.020</num>
          <heading>Preparation and adoption of budget; levy of tax; disposition of
proceeds; payment of claims; Stateï¿½s cooperative share.</heading>
          <subsection eId="549-020__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Director of the Agricultural
Extension Department of the Public Service Division of the Nevada System of
Higher Education shall prepare and submit to the board of county commissioners,
for each county participating, an annual financial budget covering the county,
state and federal funds cooperating in the cost of educational, research,
outreach and service programs pertaining to agriculture, community development,
health and nutrition, horticulture, personal and family development, and
natural resources in the rural and urban communities in the State of Nevada.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="549-020__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The budget must be adopted by the board
of county commissioners and certified as a part of the annual county budget,
and the county tax levy provided for agricultural extension work in the annual
county budget must include a levy of not less than 1 cent on each $100 of
taxable property. If the proceeds of the county tax levy of 1 cent are
insufficient to meet the countyï¿½s share of the cooperative agricultural
extension work, as provided in the combined annual financial budget, the board
of county commissioners may, by unanimous vote, levy an additional tax so that
the total in no instance exceeds 5 cents on each $100 of the county tax rate.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="549-020__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The proceeds of such a tax must be
placed in the agricultural extension fund in each county treasury and must be
paid out on claims drawn by the agricultural extension agent of the county as
designated by the Director of the Agricultural Extension Department of the
Public Service Division of the Nevada System of Higher Education, when approved
by the Director and countersigned by the Treasurer of the Nevada System of
Higher Education.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="549-020__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A record of all such claims approved
and paid, segregated by counties, must be kept by the Treasurer of the Nevada
System of Higher Education. The cost of maintaining the record must be paid
from state funds provided for by this chapter.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="549-020__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Stateï¿½s cooperative share of the
cost of such agricultural extension work, as entered in the budget described in
this section, must not be more than a sum equal to the proceeds of 1 cent of
such county tax rate; but when the proceeds of a 1-cent tax rate are
insufficient to carry out the provisions of the budget previously adopted, the
Director of the Agricultural Extension Department of the Public Service
Division of the Nevada System of Higher Education is authorized to supplement
the Stateï¿½s cooperative share from the funds as may be made available in the
Public Service Division Fund of the Nevada System of Higher Education.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [2:94:1947; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 356.2]—(NRS A1969,
1444;1993,
413;1999,
2550)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_549-030">
          <num>549.030</num>
          <heading>Filing of copy of budget with Nevada System of Higher Education;
modification of budget.</heading>
          <subsection eId="549-030__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A certified copy of the county
extension work budget as adopted and approved pursuant toNRS 549.020must be filed with the
Treasurer of the Nevada System of Higher Education within 10 days after its
approval by the board of county commissioners.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="549-030__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Necessary modifications thereof,
involving county and state funds, resulting from leaves of absence without pay,
resignations, changes in salary, dismissals or employment of any cooperative
agent, variations in expense accounts or otherwise, not involving an increase
in the total expenditures provided to be paid from the funds and consistent
with the purposes of this chapter, may be made by filing with the Treasurer of
the Nevada System of Higher Education and the board of county commissioners a
revised budget, approved by the Director of the Agricultural Extension
Department of the Public Service Division of the Nevada System of Higher
Education and countersigned by the Treasurer of the Nevada System of Higher
Education.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [3:94:1947; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 356.3]—(NRS A1969,
1444;1993,
414)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_549-040">
          <num>549.040</num>
          <heading>Legislative appropriations.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Funds
to carry out the provisions of this chapter shall be provided by direct
legislative appropriation from the General Fund.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [4:94:1947; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 356.4]—(NRS A1961,
513)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_549-050">
          <num>549.050</num>
          <heading>Expenditure of Stateï¿½s cooperative share.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>All moneys appropriated pursuant toNRS 549.040must be expended under the
direction of the Director of the Agricultural Extension Department of the
Public Service Division of the Nevada System of Higher Education to the extent
of the financial budget for cooperation between the State and the respective
counties provided for inNRS 549.020.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [5:94:1947; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 356.5]—(NRS A1969,
1445;1993,
414)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_549-060">
          <num>549.060</num>
          <heading>Participation of counties in extension work.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Any county in the state which has agreed or
shall agree to participate in cooperative work in agricultural extension under
the provisions of this chapter or acts previously passed by the Legislature and
approved by the Governor shall, by the provisions hereof, come under this
chapter.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [6:94:1947; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 356.6]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_549-070">
          <num>549.070</num>
          <heading>Transitional provisions.</heading>
          <subsection eId="549-070__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>All supplies, materials, equipment,
property or land acquired for the use of county agricultural extension offices
under the provisions of chapter 213, Statutes of Nevada 1919, shall remain the
property of the county extension offices set up under the provisions of this
chapter.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="549-070__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any and all contracts for the purchase
of equipment, property or land of any type or description made under the
provisions of chapter 213, Statutes of Nevada 1919, shall remain in full force
and effect until the completion of such contracts.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [7:94:1947; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 356.7]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>