<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="NRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-212"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-212"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#nevada-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-nv"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="212"/>
          <FRBRname value="NRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-212/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-212/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-212/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-212/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="nevada-legislature" href="https://www.leg.state.nv.us" showAs="Nevada State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_212">
        <num>212</num>
        <heading>OFFENSES RELATING TO PRISONS</heading>
        <section eId="sec_212-010">
          <num>212.010</num>
          <heading>Punishment for unauthorized injury of prisoner; forfeiture
abolished except when statutorily authorized.</heading>
          <subsection eId="212-010__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every person sentenced to imprisonment
in any penal institution is under the protection of the law, and any
unauthorized injury to his or her person shall be punished in the same manner
as if he or she were not so convicted or sentenced.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-010__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A conviction of crime does not work a
forfeiture of any property, real or personal, or of any right or interest
therein unless otherwise specifically authorized by statute. All forfeitures in
the nature of deodands, or in case of suicide or where a person flees from
justice, are abolished.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 13; RL ï¿½ 6278; NCL ï¿½ 9962]—(NRS A1985,
1468)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-020">
          <num>212.020</num>
          <heading>Inhumanity to prisoners.</heading>
          <subsection eId="212-020__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A jailer or person who is guilty of
willful inhumanity or oppression to any prisoner under the care or custody of
the jailer or person shall be punished:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-020__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Where the prisoner suffers substantial bodily
harm from the inhumanity or oppression, for a category D felony as provided inNRS 193.130.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-020__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Where no substantial bodily harm results, for
a gross misdemeanor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-020__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Whether or not the prisoner suffers
substantial bodily harm, any public officer guilty of willful inhumanity is
guilty of a malfeasance in office.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 62:108:1866; B ï¿½ 2660; BH ï¿½ 1697; C ï¿½ 1843; RL
ï¿½ 2818; NCL ï¿½ 4818]—(NRS A1967,
524;1995,
1255)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-030">
          <num>212.030</num>
          <heading>Warrant for arrest of escaped prisoner.</heading>
          <subsection eId="212-030__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When any prisoner escapes from an
institution or facility of the Department of Corrections, the Director of the
Department may issue a warrant for the recapture of the escaped prisoner. The
warrant is effective in any county in this State, and may command the sheriff
of any county in this State, or any constable thereof, or any police officer of
any city in this State, to arrest and return the prisoner to the Director.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-030__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When any prisoner escapes from a jail,
branch county jail or other local detention facility, the sheriff, chief of
police or other officer responsible for the operation of the facility may issue
a warrant for the recapture of the escaped prisoner. The warrant is effective in
any county in this State, and may command the sheriff of any county in this
State, or any constable thereof, or any police officer of any city in this
State, to arrest and return the prisoner to the officer who issued the warrant.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1:72:1866; B ï¿½ 3765; BH ï¿½ 1425; C ï¿½ 1446; RL ï¿½ 7594;
NCL ï¿½ 11491]—(NRS A1977,
868;1983,
726;1991,
19;2001
Special Session, 198)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-040">
          <num>212.040</num>
          <heading>Expenses of recapture and return of escaped prisoners.</heading>
          <subsection eId="212-040__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If an escape is not the result of
carelessness, incompetency or other official delinquency of the Director or
other officers of the Department of Corrections, all expenses of enforcing the
provisions ofNRS 212.030or appertaining
to the recapture and return of escaped convicts are a charge against the State,
and must be paid out of the Reserve for Statutory Contingency Account upon
approval by the State Board of Examiners.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-040__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided inNRS 211.060, all expenses of enforcing the
provisions ofNRS 212.030or
appertaining to the recapture and return of escaped convicts are a charge
against the county, city or other local government responsible for the
operation of that facility.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [2:72:1866; A1955,
625]—(NRS A1963,
1111;1977,
868;1991,
19,1755,1823;2001
Special Session, 198)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-050">
          <num>212.050</num>
          <heading>Authority to offer reward in certain cases.</heading>
          <subsection eId="212-050__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any person who has been sentenced to
confinement in the state prison, by any court having competent authority within
this State, escapes therefrom, or is charged with murder or the perpetration of
any crime punishable with death, the Governor may, upon satisfactory evidence
of the guilt of the accused, offer a reward for information that leads to his
or her apprehension. The reward offered by the Governor must not exceed the sum
of $5,000, and must be paid out of the Reserve for Statutory Contingency Account
upon approval by the State Board of Examiners.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-050__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any person who has been sentenced to
confinement in a jail, branch county jail or other local detention facility by
any court having competent authority within this State, escapes therefrom, or
is charged with murder or the perpetration of any crime punishable with death,
the board of county commissioners of the county, the governing body of the city
or other local government responsible for the operation of the facility may,
upon satisfactory evidence of the guilt of the accused, offer a reward for information
that leads to his or her apprehension. The reward offered by the board,
governing body or other local government must not exceed the sum of $5,000.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [80:108:1866; B ï¿½ 2678; BH ï¿½ 1715; C ï¿½ 1861; RL ï¿½
2831; NCL ï¿½ 4831]—(NRS A1963,
1111;1971,
8;1991,
19,1755,1823)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-070">
          <num>212.070</num>
          <heading>Expenses of prosecuting prisoner and person acting in concert with
prisoner who escapes or commits crime while incarcerated.</heading>
          <subsection eId="212-070__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The expenses and costs of prosecuting
any person for escaping from, or breaking out of, the state prison, or
attempting so to do, or for the commission of any crime while a prisoner
therein, or any person acting in concert with such a prisoner, whether as a
principal or accessory, are a charge against the State and must be paid from
the Reserve for Statutory Contingency Account upon approval by the State Board
of Examiners.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-070__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The expenses and costs of prosecuting
any person or persons for escaping from, or breaking out of, a jail, branch
county jail or other local detention facility or attempting so to do, or for
the commission of any crime while a prisoner therein, or any person acting in
concert with such a prisoner, whether as a principal or accessory, are a charge
against the county, city or other local government responsible for the
operation of that facility.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 555; A1955,
625]—(NRS A1963,
1112;1991,
20,1755,1824;1993,
457)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-080">
          <num>212.080</num>
          <heading>Recapture and imprisonment.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Every
person in custody, under sentence of imprisonment for any crime, who shall
escape from custody, may be recaptured and imprisoned for a term equal to the
unexpired portion of the original term.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 73; RL ï¿½ 6338; NCL ï¿½ 10022]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-090">
          <num>212.090</num>
          <heading>Penalties for prisoner who escapes.</heading>
          <subsection eId="212-090__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A felony, shall be punished:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-090__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Where a dangerous weapon is used or one or
more hostages are taken to facilitate the escape or attempted escape, or
substantial bodily harm results to anyone as a direct result of the escape or
attempted escape, for a category B felony by imprisonment in the state prison
for a minimum term of not less than 2 years and a maximum term of not more than
20 years, and may be further punished by a fine of not more than $20,000. The
sentence imposed pursuant to this paragraph must run consecutively after any
sentence imposed for the original felony, and is not subject to suspension or
the granting of probation.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-090__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Where none of the aggravating factors
specified in paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-090__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>are present, for a category B felony by imprisonment
in the state prison for a minimum term of not less than 1 year and a maximum
term of not more than 10 years, and may be further punished by a fine of not
more than $10,000.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-090__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A gross misdemeanor or misdemeanor,
shall be punished:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-090__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Where a dangerous weapon is used to
facilitate the escape or attempted escape, for a category B felony by
imprisonment in the state prison for a minimum term of not less than 1 year and
a maximum term of not more than 6 years, and may be further punished by a fine
of not more than $5,000.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-090__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Where no dangerous weapon is used, for a
gross misdemeanor.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 74; A1955,
191]—(NRS A1967,
524;1973,
67;1979,
1456;1995,
1255)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-093">
          <num>212.093</num>
          <heading>Manufacture or possession by prisoner of items adapted, designed
or commonly used to escape prohibited; penalty; exception.</heading>
          <subsection eId="212-093__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 4, a prisoner who is in lawful custody or confinement, other than
residential confinement, shall not knowingly manufacture, possess or have in
his or her custody or control any key, picklock, bolt cutters, wire cutters,
saw, digging tool, rope, ladder, hook or any other tool or item adapted,
designed or commonly used for the purpose of escaping or attempting to escape
from lawful custody or confinement, whether or not such an escape or attempted
escape actually occurs.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-093__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A prisoner who violates any provision
of subsection 1 and who is in lawful custody or confinement for a charge,
conviction or sentence for:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-093__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A felony, shall be punished for a category B
felony by imprisonment in the state prison for a minimum term of not less than
1 year and a maximum term of not more than 6 years, and may be further punished
by a fine of not more than $5,000.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-093__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A gross misdemeanor or misdemeanor, shall be
punished for a gross misdemeanor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-093__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A sentence imposed upon a prisoner pursuant
to this section:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-093__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Is not subject to suspension or the granting
of probation; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-093__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Must run consecutively after the prisoner has
served any sentences imposed upon the prisoner for the offense or offenses for
which the prisoner was in lawful custody or confinement when the prisoner
violated the provisions of subsection 1.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-093__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of this section do not
apply to a prisoner who commits an act described in subsection 1 if the act is
authorized by the warden, sheriff, administrator or other person responsible
for administering the prison, or his or her designee, and the prisoner performs
the act in accordance with the directions or instructions given to the prisoner
by that person.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2003,
1184)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-095">
          <num>212.095</num>
          <heading>Unauthorized absences which constitute escape from prison;
punishment; exception.</heading>
          <subsection eId="212-095__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any unauthorized absence from the place
of assignment by an offender who is on temporary furlough, participating in a
work or educational release program or otherwise in a classification assignment
under the provisions ofchapter 209of NRS,
constitutes an escape from prison which is a category B felony and the offender
shall be punished as provided inNRS 212.090.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-095__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>This section does not apply to
offenders released on parole.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1977,
854; A1995,
1255)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-100">
          <num>212.100</num>
          <heading>Aiding prisoner to escape.</heading>
          <subsection eId="212-100__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>For a felony, for a category B felony
by imprisonment in the state prison for a minimum term of not less than 1 year
and a maximum term of not more than 10 years, and may be further punished by a
fine of not more than $10,000.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-100__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>For a gross misdemeanor or misdemeanor:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-100__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Where a dangerous weapon is used to effect or
facilitate the escape or attempted escape, for a category B felony by
imprisonment in the state prison for a minimum term of not less than 1 year and
a maximum term of not more than 6 years, and may be further punished by a fine
of not more than $5,000.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-100__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Where no dangerous weapon is used, for a
gross misdemeanor.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 75; RL ï¿½ 6340; NCL ï¿½ 10024]—(NRS A1967,
524;1979,
1457;1995,
1256)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-110">
          <num>212.110</num>
          <heading>Custodian permitting escape.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>A
person who willfully allows a prisoner lawfully in the custody of the person to
escape, or connives at or assists such an escape, or willfully omits any act or
duty by reason of which an escape is occasioned, contributed to or assisted, is
guilty of a category B felony and shall, if the person connives at or assists
the escape, be punished by imprisonment in the state prison for a minimum term
of not less than 1 year and a maximum term of not more than 6 years, and may be
further punished by a fine of not more than $10,000, and in any other case, is
guilty of a gross misdemeanor.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 76; RL ï¿½ 6341; NCL ï¿½ 10025]—(NRS A1967,
525;1979,
1457;1995,
1256)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-120">
          <num>212.120</num>
          <heading>Ministerial officer permitting escape.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>An
officer who asks or receives, directly or indirectly, any compensation,
gratuity or reward, or promise thereof, to procure, assist, connive at or
permit any prisoner in the custody of the officer to escape, whether the escape
is attempted or not, or commits any unlawful act tending to hinder justice, is
guilty of a category B felony and shall be punished by imprisonment in the
state prison for a minimum term of not less than 1 year and a maximum term of not
more than 6 years, and may be further punished by a fine of not more than
$10,000.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 77; RL ï¿½ 6342; NCL ï¿½ 10026]—(NRS A1967,
525;1979,
1457;1995,
1256)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-130">
          <num>212.130</num>
          <heading>Concealing escaped prisoner.</heading>
          <subsection eId="212-130__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>For a category C felony as provided inNRS 193.130, if the prisoner was held for a
felony.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-130__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>For a gross misdemeanor, if the
prisoner was held for a gross misdemeanor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-130__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>For a misdemeanor, if the prisoner was
held for a misdemeanor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 78; RL ï¿½ 6343; NCL ï¿½ 10027]—(NRS A1967,
525;1979,
1458;1995,
1256)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-135">
          <num>212.135</num>
          <heading>Definitions.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>As
used inNRS 212.135to212.189, inclusive, unless the context
otherwise requires, the words and terms defined inNRS 212.137,212.138and212.139have the meanings ascribed to them
in those sections.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2015,
897)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-137">
          <num>212.137</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Contractorï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Contractorï¿½
means a person who provides services on a recurring basis to a prison pursuant
to a contractual agreement with the Department of Corrections or the sheriff,
chief of police or other officer responsible for the operation of the prison.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2015,
897)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-138">
          <num>212.138</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Employeeï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Employeeï¿½
means a person who works directly for a prison.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2015,
897)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-139">
          <num>212.139</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Volunteerï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Volunteerï¿½
means a person who donates his or her time and effort on a recurring basis to a
prison to enhance the activities and programs of the prison.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2015,
897)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-140">
          <num>212.140</num>
          <heading>Unauthorized communication with prisoner.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Every person who, not being authorized by law
or by any officer authorized thereby, shall have any verbal communication with
any prisoner in any jail, prison or other penal institution, or shall bring into
or convey out of the same any writing, clothing, food, tobacco or any article
whatsoever, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 108; RL ï¿½ 6373; NCL ï¿½ 10057]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-150">
          <num>212.150</num>
          <heading>Communication with person charged or convicted of felony in
county jail.</heading>
          <subsection eId="212-150__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person shall not visit, or in any
manner communicate with, any prisoner convicted of or charged with any felony,
imprisoned in the county jail, other than the officer having such prisoner in
charge, the prisonerï¿½s attorney or the district attorney, unless the person has
a written permission so to do, signed by the district attorney, or has the
consent of the Director of the Department of Corrections or the sheriff having
such prisoner in charge.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-150__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person violating, aiding in,
conniving at or participating in the violation of this section is guilty of a
gross misdemeanor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 552; RL ï¿½ 6817; NCL ï¿½ 10497]—(NRS A1967,
525;1977,
869;2001
Special Session, 198;2015,
2521)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-160">
          <num>212.160</num>
          <heading>Furnishing weapon, facsimile, intoxicant or controlled substance
to state prisoner; possession of controlled substance, marijuana or marijuana
paraphernalia by state prisoner.</heading>
          <subsection eId="212-160__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person, who is not authorized by law,
who knowingly furnishes, attempts to furnish, or aids or assists in furnishing
or attempting to furnish to a prisoner confined in an institution of the
Department of Corrections, or any other place where prisoners are authorized to
be or are assigned by the Director of the Department, any deadly weapon,
explosive, a facsimile of a firearm or an explosive, any controlled substance
or intoxicating liquor, shall be punished:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-160__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Where a deadly weapon, controlled substance,
explosive or a facsimile of a firearm or explosive is involved, for a category
B felony by imprisonment in the state prison for a minimum term of not less
than 1 year and a maximum term of not more than 6 years, and may be further
punished by a fine of not more than $5,000.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-160__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Where an intoxicant is involved, for a gross
misdemeanor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-160__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Knowingly leaving or causing to be left
any deadly weapon, explosive, facsimile of a firearm or explosive, controlled
substance or intoxicating liquor where it may be obtained by any prisoner
constitutes, within the meaning of this section, the furnishing of the article
to the prisoner.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-160__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A prisoner confined in an institution
of the Department of Corrections, or any other place where prisoners are
authorized to be or are assigned by the Director of the Department, who
possesses a controlled substance without lawful authorization or marijuana or
marijuana paraphernalia, regardless of whether the person holds a valid registry
identification card to engage in the medical use of cannabis pursuant tochapter 678Cof NRS, is guilty of a category D
felony and shall be punished as provided inNRS
193.130.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1:163:1949; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 11474.01]—(NRS A1963,
520;1967,
525;1971,
2026;1977,
869;1979,
1458;1985,
596;1987,
1548;1995,
1257;2001
Special Session, 198;2017,
3711;2019,
3848)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-165">
          <num>212.165</num>
          <heading>Prohibition on furnishing portable telecommunications device to
prisoner and on possession of such devices in jail or institution or facility
of Department of Corrections; penalties; petition for modification of sentence.</heading>
          <subsection eId="212-165__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person shall not, without lawful
authorization, knowingly furnish, attempt to furnish, or aid or assist in
furnishing or attempting to furnish to a prisoner confined in an institution or
a facility of the Department of Corrections, or any other place where prisoners
are authorized to be or are assigned by the Director of the Department, a
portable telecommunications device. A person who violates this subsection is
guilty of a category E felony and shall be punished as provided inNRS 193.130.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-165__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person shall not, without lawful
authorization, carry into an institution or a facility of the Department, or
any other place where prisoners are authorized to be or are assigned by the
Director of the Department, a portable telecommunications device. A person who
violates this subsection is guilty of a misdemeanor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-165__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A prisoner confined in an institution
or a facility of the Department, or any other place where prisoners are
authorized to be or are assigned by the Director of the Department, shall not,
without lawful authorization, possess or have in his or her custody or control
a portable telecommunications device. A prisoner who violates this subsection
is guilty of a category D felony and shall be punished as provided inNRS 193.130.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-165__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A prisoner confined in a jail or any
other place where such prisoners are authorized to be or are assigned by the
sheriff, chief of police or other officer responsible for the operation of the
jail, shall not, without lawful authorization, possess or have in his or her
custody or control a portable telecommunications device. A prisoner who
violates this subsection and who is in lawful custody or confinement for a
charge, conviction or sentence for:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-165__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A felony is guilty of a category D felony and
shall be punished as provided inNRS 193.130.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-165__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A gross misdemeanor is guilty of a gross
misdemeanor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-165__subsec_4__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A misdemeanor is guilty of a misdemeanor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-165__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A sentence imposed upon a prisoner pursuant
to subsection 3 or 4:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-165__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Is not subject to suspension or the granting
of probation; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-165__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Must run consecutively after the prisoner has
served any sentences imposed upon the prisoner for the offense or offenses for
which the prisoner was in lawful custody or confinement when the prisoner
violated the provisions of subsection 3 or 4.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-165__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who was convicted and
sentenced pursuant to subsection 4 may file a petition, if the underlying
charge for which the person was in lawful custody or confinement has been
reduced to a charge for which the penalty is less than the penalty which was
imposed upon the person pursuant to subsection 4, with the court of original
jurisdiction requesting that the court, for good cause shown:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-165__subsec_6__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Order that his or her sentence imposed
pursuant to subsection 4 be modified to a sentence equivalent to the penalty
imposed for the underlying charge for which the person was convicted; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-165__subsec_6__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Resentence him or her in accordance with the
penalties prescribed for the underlying charge for which the person was
convicted.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-165__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who was convicted and
sentenced pursuant to subsection 4 may file a petition, if the underlying
charge for which the person was in lawful custody or confinement has been
declined for prosecution or dismissed, with the court of original jurisdiction
requesting that the court, for good cause shown:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-165__subsec_7__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Order that his or her original sentence
pursuant to subsection 4 be reduced to a misdemeanor; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-165__subsec_7__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Resentence him or her in accordance with the
penalties prescribed for a misdemeanor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-165__subsec_8">
            <num>8.</num>
            <content>
              <p>No person has a right to the
modification of a sentence pursuant to subsection 6 or 7, and the granting or
denial of a petition pursuant to subsection 6 or 7 does not establish a basis
for any cause of action against this State, any political subdivision of this
State or any agency, board, commission, department, officer, employee or agent
of this State or a political subdivision of this State.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-165__subsec_9">
            <num>9.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-165__subsec_9__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Facilityï¿½ has the meaning ascribed to it inNRS 209.065.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-165__subsec_9__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Institutionï¿½ has the meaning ascribed to it
inNRS 209.071.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-165__subsec_9__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Jailï¿½ means a jail, branch county jail or
other local detention facility.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-165__subsec_9__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Telecommunications deviceï¿½ has the meaning
ascribed to it in subsection 6 ofNRS
209.417.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2007,
72; A2013,
2095;2015,
3081;2017,
3660)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-170">
          <num>212.170</num>
          <heading>Furnishing intoxicant to person lawfully confined in jail or
detention facility.</heading>
          <subsection eId="212-170__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person who sells, barters,
exchanges or in any manner disposes of any spirituous or malt liquor or beverage
to any person confined in any county or city jail or detention facility is
guilty of a gross misdemeanor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-170__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>This section does not apply to any
physician prescribing or furnishing liquor to any such person, when the liquor
is prescribed or furnished for medicinal purposes only.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 220; RL ï¿½ 6485; NCL ï¿½
10167]—(NRS A1967,
526;1989,
1177)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-180">
          <num>212.180</num>
          <heading>Sale of liquor within half mile of institution of Department of
Corrections unlawful; restriction on granting of new licenses; exception.</heading>
          <subsection eId="212-180__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 2, it is unlawful for any person, unless the person was licensed to
sell alcoholic beverages at that address before July 1, 1983, to sell by
wholesale or retail any alcoholic beverage within one-half mile of any
institution under the jurisdiction of the Department of Corrections which is
designed to house 125 or more offenders within a secure perimeter, and no
license may be granted authorizing the sale of any alcoholic beverage within
one-half mile of such an institution.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-180__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of subsection 1 do not
prohibit the sale or consumption of beer and wine at any event held pursuant to
a special use permit or agreement with the Nevada State Prison Preservation
Society, or any successor or similar nonprofit corporation, within the historic
structures, buildings and other property of the Nevada State Prison so long as
the beer and wine is served in temporary containers and beer or wine is not
stored at the historic structures, buildings and other property of the Nevada
State Prison.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-180__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-180__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Beerï¿½ has the meaning ascribed to it inNRS 369.010.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-180__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Historic structures, buildings and other
property of the Nevada State Prisonï¿½ means the structures, buildings and other
property described in paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-180__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 1 ofNRS 321.004.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-180__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Wineï¿½ has the meaning ascribed to it inNRS 369.140.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 239; RL ï¿½ 6504; NCL ï¿½ 10186]—(NRS A1979,
1458;1983,
381;2001
Special Session, 199;2021,
2080)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-185">
          <num>212.185</num>
          <heading>Possession or control of dangerous weapon or facsimile by
incarcerated person prohibited.</heading>
          <subsection eId="212-185__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who is incarcerated in the
state prison or any county or city jail or detention facility or other
correctional facility in this State, or is transferred for medical or
psychiatric treatment at another institution, or is in transit to or from such
facility, or is in the legal custody of any correctional officer or employee,
and who possesses or has in his or her custody or control any:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-185__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Instrument or weapon of the kind commonly
known as a blackjack, slungshot, billy, sand-club, sandbag or metal knuckles;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-185__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Explosive substance, including fixed
ammunition, or any incendiary or explosive device;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-185__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Dirk, dagger, switchblade knife or sharp
instrument;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-185__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Pistol, revolver or other firearm;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-185__subsec_1__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Facsimile of a firearm or an explosive;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-185__subsec_1__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Device capable of propelling a projectile
with sufficient force to cause bodily harm, including, but not limited to, a
pellet gun, slingshot, blowgun, crossbow or bow and arrow; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-185__subsec_1__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Other similar weapon, instrument or device,
ï¿½is guilty of
a category B felony and shall be punished by imprisonment in the state prison
for a minimum term of not less than 1 year and a maximum term of not more than
6 years.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-185__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the purposes of this section,
incarceration begins upon assignment to a cell or other place within the
correctional facility after completion of the initial booking procedure.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1977,
269; A1985,
596;1989,
1177;1995,
1257)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-187">
          <num>212.187</num>
          <heading>Voluntary sexual conduct between prisoner and person other than
employee of or contractor or volunteer for prison; penalty.</heading>
          <subsection eId="212-187__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A prisoner who is in lawful custody or
confinement, other than in the custody of the Division of Parole and Probation
of the Department of Public Safety pursuant toNRS 209.4886or209.4888or residential confinement, and
who voluntarily engages in sexual conduct with another person who is not an
employee of or a contractor or volunteer for a prison is guilty of a category D
felony and shall be punished as provided inNRS
193.130.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-187__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided inNRS 212.188, a person who voluntarily
engages in sexual conduct with a prisoner who is in lawful custody or
confinement, other than in the custody of the Division of Parole and Probation
of the Department of Public Safety pursuant toNRS 209.4886or209.4888or residential confinement, is
guilty of a category D felony and shall be punished as provided inNRS 193.130.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-187__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, ï¿½sexual
conductï¿½:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-187__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Includes acts of masturbation, sexual
penetration or physical contact with another personï¿½s clothed or unclothed
genitals or pubic area to arouse, appeal to or gratify the sexual desires of a
person.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-187__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Does not include acts of a person who has
custody of a prisoner or an employee of or a contractor or volunteer for the
prison in which the prisoner is confined that are performed to carry out the
necessary duties of such a person, employee, contractor or volunteer.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1981,
613; A1997,
1643;1999,
2882;2001,
1164,1937;2001
Special Session, 157;2003,
26,29,2581;2013,
1169;2015,
899)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-188">
          <num>212.188</num>
          <heading>Sexual abuse of prisoner or unauthorized custodial conduct by
employee of or contractor or volunteer for prison; penalties.</heading>
          <subsection eId="212-188__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An employee of or a contractor or
volunteer for a prison who voluntarily engages in, or attempts to engage in,
with a prisoner who is in lawful custody or confinement, other than in the
custody of the Division of Parole and Probation of the Department of Public
Safety pursuant toNRS 209.4886or209.4888or residential confinement, any
of the acts set forth in:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-188__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-188__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 3, commits sexual
abuse of a prisoner.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-188__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-188__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 3, commits
unauthorized custodial conduct.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-188__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Unless a greater penalty is provided
pursuant to any other applicable provision of law, an employee of or a
contractor or volunteer for a prison who commits:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-188__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Sexual abuse of a prisoner is guilty of a
category D felony and shall be punished as provided inNRS 193.130.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-188__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Unauthorized custodial conduct by engaging in
any of the acts described in paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-188__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 3 is guilty of a gross
misdemeanor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-188__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Unauthorized custodial conduct by attempting
to engage in any of the acts described in paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-188__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 3 is
guilty of a misdemeanor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-188__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-188__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Sexual abuseï¿½:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="212-188__subsec_3__subsec_a__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Includes any of the following acts
between an employee of or a contractor or volunteer for a prison and a
prisoner, regardless of whether the prisoner consents to the act:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (I) Sexual intercourse or anal
intercourse, including penetration, however slight;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (II) Fellatio, cunnilingus or
contact between the mouth and the anus;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (III) Penetration, however slight,
of an object into the genital or anal opening of the body of a prisoner
committed with the intent to abuse the prisoner or to arouse, appeal to or
gratify the sexual desires of either person;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (IV) Any other intentional contact
with a prisonerï¿½s unclothed genitals, pubic area, anus, buttocks, inner thigh
or breasts committed with the intent to abuse the prisoner or to arouse, appeal
to or gratify the sexual desires of either person;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (V) Watching a prisoner change
clothing or use a shower, toilet or urinal;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (VI) Requiring a prisoner to expose
his or her genitals, buttocks or breasts; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (VII) Capturing an image of the
private area of a prisoner in violation ofNRS
200.604.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="212-188__subsec_3__subsec_a__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Does not include acts of an employee
of or a contractor or volunteer for the prison in which the prisoner is
confined that are performed to carry out the official duties of such an
employee, contractor or volunteer.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-188__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Unauthorized custodial conductï¿½:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="212-188__subsec_3__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Includes any of the following acts
between an employee of or a contractor or volunteer for a prison and a
prisoner, regardless of whether the prisoner consents to the act:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (I) Contact between the mouth and
any part of the body committed with the intent to abuse the prisoner or to
arouse, appeal to or gratify the sexual desires of either person;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (II) Any other intentional contact
with a prisonerï¿½s clothed genitals, pubic area, anus, buttocks, inner thigh or
breasts committed with the intent to abuse the prisoner or to arouse, appeal to
or gratify the sexual desires of either person;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (III) Any threat or request by an
employee or a contractor or volunteer to engage in any act described in
sub-subparagraphs (I) or (II); or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (IV) Any display by an employee or a
contractor or volunteer of his or her unclothed genitals, buttocks or breasts
in the presence of a prisoner.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="212-188__subsec_3__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Does not include acts of an employee
of or a contractor or volunteer for the prison in which the prisoner is
confined that are performed to carry out the official duties of such an
employee, contractor or volunteer.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2015,
897)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-189">
          <num>212.189</num>
          <heading>Unlawful acts related to human excrement or bodily fluid;
penalty; investigation; testing for communicable diseases; plea bargaining
prohibited.</heading>
          <subsection eId="212-189__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 10, a prisoner who is under lawful arrest, in lawful custody or in
lawful confinement shall not knowingly:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Store or stockpile any human excrement or
bodily fluid;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Sell, supply or provide any human excrement
or bodily fluid to any other person;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Buy, receive or acquire any human excrement
or bodily fluid from any other person; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Use, propel, discharge, spread or conceal, or
cause to be used, propelled, discharged, spread or concealed, any human
excrement or bodily fluid:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="212-189__subsec_1__subsec_d__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>With the intent to have the excrement
or bodily fluid come into physical contact with any portion of the body of
another person, including, without limitation, an officer or employee of a
prison or law enforcement agency, whether or not such physical contact actually
occurs; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="212-189__subsec_1__subsec_d__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Under circumstances in which the
excrement or bodily fluid is reasonably likely to come into physical contact
with any portion of the body of another person, including, without limitation,
an officer or employee of a prison or law enforcement agency, whether or not
such physical contact actually occurs.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-189__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 4, if a prisoner who is under lawful arrest or in lawful custody
violates any provision of subsection 1, the prisoner is guilty of:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For a first offense, a gross misdemeanor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For a second offense or any subsequent
offense, a category D felony and shall be punished as provided inNRS 193.130.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-189__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 4, if a prisoner who is in lawful confinement, other than
residential confinement, violates any provision of subsection 1, the prisoner
is guilty of a category B felony and shall be punished by imprisonment in the
state prison for a minimum term of not less than 2 years and a maximum term of
not more than 10 years, and may be further punished by a fine of not more than
$10,000.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-189__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a prisoner who is under lawful
arrest, in lawful custody or in lawful confinement violates any provision of
paragraph</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_4__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 1 and, at the time of the offense, the prisoner
knew that any portion of the excrement or bodily fluid involved in the offense
contained a communicable disease that causes or is reasonably likely to cause
substantial bodily harm, the communicable disease is likely to be transmitted
as a result of the offense and the communicable disease was actually
transmitted to a victim as a result of the offense, the prisoner is guilty of a
category A felony and shall be punished by imprisonment in the state prison:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For life with the possibility of parole, with
eligibility for parole beginning when a minimum of 10 years has been served; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For a definite term of 25 years, with
eligibility for parole beginning when a minimum of 10 years has been served,
ï¿½and may be
further punished by a fine of not more than $50,000.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-189__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A sentence imposed upon a prisoner
pursuant to subsection 2, 3 or 4:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Is not subject to suspension or the granting
of probation; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Must run consecutively after the prisoner has
served any sentences imposed upon the prisoner for the offense or offenses for
which the prisoner was under lawful arrest, in lawful custody or in lawful
confinement when the prisoner violated the provisions of subsection 1.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-189__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In addition to any other penalty, the
court shall order a prisoner who violates any provision of paragraph</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_6__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of
subsection 1 to reimburse the appropriate person or governmental body for the
cost of any examinations or testing:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_6__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Conducted pursuant to paragraphs</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_6__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_6__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 8; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_6__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Paid for pursuant to subparagraph</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="212-189__subsec_6__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>of
paragraph</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_6__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 8.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-189__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The warden, sheriff, administrator or
other person responsible for administering a prison shall immediately and fully
investigate any act described in subsection 1 that is reported or suspected to
have been committed in the prison.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-189__subsec_8">
            <num>8.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If there is probable cause to believe
that an act described in paragraph</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_8__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 1 has been committed in a
prison:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_8__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Each prisoner believed to have committed the
act or to have been the bodily source of any portion of the excrement or bodily
fluid involved in the act shall submit to any appropriate examinations and
testing to determine whether each such prisoner has any communicable disease.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_8__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If possible, a sample of the excrement or
bodily fluid involved in the act must be recovered and tested to determine
whether any communicable disease is present in the excrement or bodily fluid.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_8__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the excrement or bodily fluid involved in
the act came into physical contact with any portion of the body of an officer
or employee of a prison or law enforcement agency:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="212-189__subsec_8__subsec_c__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The results of any examinations or
testing conducted pursuant to paragraphs</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_8__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_8__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>must be provided to each
such officer, employee or other person; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="212-189__subsec_8__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>For each such officer or employee:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (I) Of a prison, the person or
governmental body operating the prison where the act was committed shall pay
for any appropriate examinations and testing requested by the officer or
employee to determine whether a communicable disease was transmitted to the
officer or employee as a result of the act; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (II) Of any law enforcement agency,
the law enforcement agency that employs the officer or employee shall pay for
any appropriate examinations and testing requested by the officer or employee
to determine whether a communicable disease was transmitted to the officer or
employee as a result of the act.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_8__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The results of the investigation conducted
pursuant to subsection 7 and the results of any examinations or testing
conducted pursuant to paragraphs</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_8__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_8__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>must be submitted to the district
attorney of the county in which the act was committed or to the Office of the
Attorney General for possible prosecution of each prisoner who committed the
act.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-189__subsec_9">
            <num>9.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a prisoner is charged with
committing an act described in paragraph</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_9__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 1 and a victim or an
intended victim of the act was an officer or employee of a prison or law
enforcement agency, the prosecuting attorney shall not dismiss the charge in
exchange for a plea of guilty, guilty but mentally ill or nolo contendere to a
lesser charge or for any other reason unless the prosecuting attorney knows or
it is obvious that the charge is not supported by probable cause or cannot be
proved at the time of trial.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-189__subsec_10">
            <num>10.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of this section do not
apply to a prisoner who is in residential confinement or to a prisoner who
commits an act described in subsection 1 if the act:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_10__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Is otherwise lawful and is authorized by the
warden, sheriff, administrator or other person responsible for administering
the prison, or his or her designee, and the prisoner performs the act in
accordance with the directions or instructions given to the prisoner by that
person;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_10__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Involves the discharge of human excrement or
bodily fluid directly from the body of the prisoner and the discharge is the
direct result of a temporary or permanent injury, disease or medical condition
afflicting the prisoner that prevents the prisoner from having physical control
over the discharge of his or her own excrement or bodily fluid; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-189__subsec_10__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Constitutes voluntary sexual conduct with
another person in violation of the provisions ofNRS 212.187.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1999,
2676; A2003,
1485;2007,
1442;2009,
150;2023,
3491)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-1895">
          <num>212.1895</num>
          <heading>Applicability of certain provisions to custodian and prisoner
assigned to private facility or institution; training to perform duties of
correctional officer at private facility or institution; reimbursement to State
for expenses relating to prisoner who escapes from private facility or
institution.</heading>
          <subsection eId="212-1895__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of this section andNRS 212.030to212.130, inclusive, and212.160to212.189, inclusive, apply to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-1895__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A person who has custody of a prisoner
assigned to a private facility or institution in this State; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-1895__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A prisoner assigned to a private facility or
institution in this State,
ï¿½to the same
extent that those provisions would apply if the prisoner had been assigned to a
facility or institution operated by the Department of Corrections.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-1895__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A private organization that operates a
private facility or institution must provide training to any person employed by
the private facility or institution to perform the duties of a correctional
officer described in subsection 5 ofNRS
209.131. The training must be equivalent to the training provided to a
correctional officer in this State.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-1895__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The private organization that operates
a private facility or institution must reimburse the State for any expenses
charged against the State or paid by the State pursuant toNRS 212.040,212.050or212.070concerning a prisoner who escapes
from the private facility or institution.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-1895__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-1895__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Prisonerï¿½ means any person who is:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="212-1895__subsec_4__subsec_a__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Convicted of a crime under the laws of
this State and sentenced to imprisonment in the state prison; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="212-1895__subsec_4__subsec_a__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Convicted of a crime under the laws of
another jurisdiction and sentenced to imprisonment by that jurisdiction.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-1895__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Private facility or institutionï¿½ has the
meaning ascribed to it inNRS 209.083.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2009,
2821)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-190">
          <num>212.190</num>
          <heading>Penalty.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If any
person shall, willfully and intentionally, break down, pull down, or otherwise
destroy or injure, in whole or in part, any public jail or other place of
confinement, every person so offending is guilty of a public offense
proportionate to the value of the loss resulting therefrom, and in no event
less than a gross misdemeanor.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 493; RL ï¿½ 6758; NCL ï¿½ 10440]—(NRS A1967,
526)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_212-220">
          <num>212.220</num>
          <heading>Penalties for absence without authorization or tampering with
electronic device; restitution.</heading>
          <subsection eId="212-220__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided inNRS 213.400, a person who has been arrested
for, charged with or convicted of a felony or a gross misdemeanor, who is being
supervised electronically pursuant to such an arrest, charge or conviction and
who:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-220__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Is absent or attempts to be absent from his
or her residence, employment or other activity authorized by the supervising
agency without authorization; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-220__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Removes or disables or attempts to remove or
disable the electronic device used to supervise the person,
ï¿½is guilty of
a gross misdemeanor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-220__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who has been arrested for,
charged with or convicted of a misdemeanor, who is supervised electronically
pursuant to such an arrest, charge or conviction and who:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="212-220__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Is absent or attempts to be absent from his
or her residence, employment or other activity authorized by the supervising
agency without authorization; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="212-220__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Removes or disables or attempts to remove or
disable the electronic device used to supervise the person,
ï¿½is guilty of
a misdemeanor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-220__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In addition to any other penalty, the
court shall order the person to pay restitution for any damage to or loss of
the electronic device used to supervise the person.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="212-220__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A sentence imposed pursuant to this
section must run consecutively with the sentence imposed for the original
offense.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1997,
1225)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>