<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="NRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-690B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-690B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#nevada-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-nv"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="690B"/>
          <FRBRname value="NRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-690B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-690B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-690B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-690B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="nevada-legislature" href="https://www.leg.state.nv.us" showAs="Nevada State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_690B">
        <num>690B</num>
        <heading>CASUALTY INSURANCE</heading>
        <section eId="sec_690B-010">
          <num>690B.010</num>
          <heading>Other applicable provisions.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>All
contracts of casualty insurance covering subjects resident, located or to be
performed in this State are subject to the applicable provisions ofchapter 687Bof NRS (the insurance contract),
and to other applicable provisions of this Code.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1971,
1777)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-012">
          <num>690B.012</num>
          <heading>Claims: Approval or denial; request for additional information
or time; payment; interest on unpaid claim.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-012__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsections 2, 3 and 4, an insurer shall approve or deny a claim of its insured
relating to a contract of casualty insurance within 30 days after the insurer
receives the claim. If the claim is approved, the insurer shall pay the claim
within 30 days after it is approved. If the approved claim is not paid within
that period, the insurer shall pay interest on the claim at the rate of
interest established pursuant toNRS 99.040.
The interest must be calculated from the date the payment is due until the
claim is paid.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-012__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the insurer requires additional
information or time to determine whether to approve or deny a claim, it shall
notify the policyholder of its request for the additional information or time
within 20 days after it receives the policyholderï¿½s claim, and at least once
every 30 days thereafter, until the claim is approved or denied. The notice
must set forth the reason why the additional information or time is required.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-012__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The insurer shall approve or deny the
claim within:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-012__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Thirty days after it receives the additional
information; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-012__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Thirty-one days after the last timely notice
was provided pursuant to subsection 2,
ï¿½whichever is
later.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-012__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the claim is approved, the insurer
shall pay the claim within 30 days after it is approved. If the approved claim
is not paid within that period, the insurer shall pay interest on the claim in
the manner prescribed in subsection 1.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1991,
1329)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-016">
          <num>690B.016</num>
          <heading>Insurer required to notify insured or claimant of right to have
repairs made at licensed body shop of his or her choice; prohibition against
insurerï¿½s knowing recommendation of unlicensed body shop or required
patronization of particular body shop; insurer entitled to rely on validity of
license number in estimates or invoices from body shop.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-016__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An insured or a claimant under a policy
of insurance may have repairs to a motor vehicle made at the licensed body shop
of the insuredï¿½s or claimantï¿½s choice. An insurer of motor vehicles shall
notify the insured or the claimant of this right when the insurer is first
contacted concerning a claim for damage to a motor vehicle.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-016__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An insurer of motor vehicles or a
representative of the insurer shall not:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-016__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Knowingly recommend to an insured or a
claimant, or direct an insured or a claimant to, a body shop in this State
which is not licensed pursuant toNRS
487.630;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-016__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Require an insured or a claimant to patronize
any licensed body shop in this State in preference to another such business.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-016__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of this section do not
require an insurer to pay more than the reasonable rate required pursuant to a
policy of insurance for repairs to a motor vehicle.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-016__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the purposes of this section, an
insurer is entitled to rely upon the validity of the license number included by
the body shop on its estimates and invoices for repairs.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1989,
1002; A1989,
2045;2003,
516;2005,
927)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-017">
          <num>690B.017</num>
          <heading>Provisions for arbitration not binding.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>No
provision for arbitration contained in an automobile liability or motor vehicle
liability insurance policy delivered, issued for delivery or renewed in this
State is binding upon the named insured or any other person who makes a claim
under the policy.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1979,
1517)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-020">
          <num>690B.020</num>
          <heading>Coverage for uninsured or hit-and-run vehicles required;
exceptions; insolvency of insurer; payment; presumption.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-020__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in this
section andNRS 690B.035, no policy
insuring against liability arising out of the ownership, maintenance or use of
any motor vehicle may be delivered or issued for delivery in this State unless
coverage is provided therein or supplemental thereto for the protection of
persons insured thereunder who are legally entitled to recover damages, from
owners or operators of uninsured or hit-and-run motor vehicles, for bodily
injury, sickness or disease, including death, resulting from the ownership,
maintenance or use of the uninsured or hit-and-run motor vehicle. No such
coverage is required in or supplemental to a policy issued to the State of
Nevada or any political subdivision thereof, or where rejected in writing, on a
form furnished by the insurer describing the coverage being rejected, by an
insured named therein, or upon any renewal of such a policy unless the coverage
is then requested in writing by the named insured. The coverage required in
this section may be referred to as ï¿½uninsured vehicle coverage.ï¿½
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-020__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The amount of coverage to be provided
must be not less than the minimum limits for liability insurance for bodily
injury provided for underchapter 485of NRS,
but may be in any greater amount.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-020__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the purposes of this section, the
term ï¿½uninsured motor vehicleï¿½ means a motor vehicle:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-020__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>With respect to which there is not available
at the Department of Motor Vehicles evidence of financial responsibility as
required bychapter 485of NRS;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-020__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>With respect to the ownership, maintenance or
use of which there is no liability insurance for bodily injury or bond
applicable at the time of the crash or, to the extent of such deficiency, any
liability insurance for bodily injury or bond in force is less than the amount
required byNRS 485.210;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-020__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>With respect to the ownership, maintenance or
use of which the company writing any applicable liability insurance for bodily
injury or bond denies coverage or is insolvent;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-020__subsec_3__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Used without the permission of its owner if
there is no liability insurance for bodily injury or bond applicable to the
operator;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-020__subsec_3__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Used with the permission of its owner who has
insurance which does not provide coverage for the operation of the motor
vehicle by any person other than the owner if there is no liability insurance
for bodily injury or bond applicable to the operator; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-020__subsec_3__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The owner or operator of which is unknown or
after reasonable diligence cannot be found if:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="690B-020__subsec_3__subsec_f__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The bodily injury or death has
resulted from physical contact of the automobile with the named insured or the
person claiming under the named insured or with an automobile which the named
insured or such a person is occupying; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="690B-020__subsec_3__subsec_f__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The named insured or someone on behalf
of the named insured has reported the crash within the time required byNRS 484E.030,484E.040or484E.050to the police department of the
city where it occurred or, if it occurred in an unincorporated area, to the
sheriff of the county or to the Nevada Highway Patrol.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-020__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the purposes of this section, the
term ï¿½uninsured motor vehicleï¿½ also includes, subject to the terms and
conditions of coverage, an insured other motor vehicle where:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-020__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The liability insurer of the other motor
vehicle is unable because of its insolvency to make payment with respect to the
legal liability of its insured within the limits specified in its policy;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-020__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The occurrence out of which legal liability
arose took place while the uninsured vehicle coverage required under paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-020__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>was in effect; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-020__subsec_4__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The insolvency of the liability insurer of
the other motor vehicle existed at the time of, or within 2 years after, the
occurrence.
ï¿½Nothing
contained in this subsection prevents any insurer from providing protection
from insolvency to its insureds under more favorable terms.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-020__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If payment is made to any person under
uninsured vehicle coverage, and subject to the terms of the coverage, to the
extent of such payment the insurer is entitled to the proceeds of any
settlement or recovery from any person legally responsible for the bodily
injury as to which payment was made, and to amounts recoverable from the assets
of the insolvent insurer of the other motor vehicle.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-020__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A vehicle involved in a crash which
results in bodily injury or death shall be presumed to be an uninsured motor
vehicle if no evidence of financial responsibility is supplied to the
Department of Motor Vehicles in the manner required bychapter 485of NRS within 60 days after the crash
occurs.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1971,
1777; A1971,
1954;1973,
839;1977,
438;1979,
1518;1985,
1999;1987,
1098;2001,
2635;2011,
114;2015,
1695;2021,
127)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-023">
          <num>690B.023</num>
          <heading>Evidence of insurance: Insurer required to provide to insured on
approved form; contents; electronic format; liability for damages to mobile
electronic device presented to provide such evidence.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-023__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 2, if insurance for the operation of a motor vehicle required
pursuant toNRS 485.185is provided by a
contract of insurance, the insurer shall:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-023__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Provide evidence of insurance to the insured
on a form approved by the Commissioner. The evidence of insurance must include:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="690B-023__subsec_1__subsec_a__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The name and address of the
policyholder;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="690B-023__subsec_1__subsec_a__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The name and address of the insurer;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="690B-023__subsec_1__subsec_a__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Vehicle information, consisting of:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (I) The year, make and complete
identification number of the insured vehicle or vehicles; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (II) The word ï¿½Fleetï¿½ and the name
of the registered owner if the vehicle is covered under a fleet policy written
on an any auto basis or blanket policy basis;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="690B-023__subsec_1__subsec_a__subsec_4">
                <num>(4)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The term of the insurance, including
the day, month and year on which the policy:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (I) Becomes effective; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (II) Expires;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="690B-023__subsec_1__subsec_a__subsec_5">
                <num>(5)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The number of the policy;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="690B-023__subsec_1__subsec_a__subsec_6">
                <num>(6)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A statement that the coverage meets
the requirements set forth inNRS 485.185;
and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="690B-023__subsec_1__subsec_a__subsec_7">
                <num>(7)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The statement ï¿½This evidence of
insurance must be carried in the insured motor vehicle for production upon
demand.ï¿½ The statement must be prominently displayed.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-023__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Provide new evidence of insurance if:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="690B-023__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The information regarding the insured
vehicle or vehicles required pursuant to subparagraph</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="690B-023__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>of paragraph</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-023__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>no
longer is accurate;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="690B-023__subsec_1__subsec_a__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>An additional motor vehicle is added
to the policy;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="690B-023__subsec_1__subsec_a__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A new number is assigned to the
policy; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="690B-023__subsec_1__subsec_a__subsec_4">
                <num>(4)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The insured notifies the insurer that
the original evidence of insurance has been lost.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-023__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon the request of an insured and to
the extent available, the insurer may provide the evidence of insurance in an
electronic format, approved by the Commissioner, that can be displayed on a
mobile electronic device. The electronic format must provide for the inclusion
of all information required by paragraph</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-023__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 1. An insured who
makes such a request may also request that the insurer provide the insured with
the form provided for in subsection 1.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-023__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who presents a mobile
electronic device to another person to provide evidence of insurance assumes
all liability for any resulting damage to the mobile electronic device.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1981,
1695; A1985,
1560;1987,
1100,1498,1499;1991,
1632;1993,
2490;1995,
2743;2011,
3385;2013,
1890;2015,
798,3485)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-024">
          <num>690B.024</num>
          <heading>Authority of claimant to authorize other party to receive
certain information; obligation of insurer of other party to provide certain
information relating to claim for compensation under policy of motor vehicle
insurance.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-024__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A claimant or any attorney representing
the claimant may provide to the party against whom a claim is asserted for
compensation or damages for any mental or physical injury under a policy of
motor vehicle insurance or any attorney of the party and to the insurer of the
party a written authorization to receive all medical reports, records, films
and bills related to the claim from the providers of health care. An
authorization so provided may not be revoked without cause.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-024__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a written authorization is provided
pursuant to subsection 1, the insurer of the party shall, within 5 business
days after receiving the written authorization, disclose to the claimant or any
attorney representing the claimant a copy of the declarations page of the
policy of motor vehicle insurance. The insurer of the party may redact personal
information from the declarations page of the policy, except that the name of
the party and the policy limits must not be redacted.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-024__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>At the written request of the claimant
or the attorney of the claimant, copies of all medical reports, records, films
and bills obtained by a written authorization pursuant to subsection 1 must be
provided to the claimant or the attorney of the claimant within 30 days after
the date they are received by the party, any attorney of the party or the
insurer of the party. If the claimant or the attorney of the claimant makes a
written request for the medical reports, records, films and bills, the claimant
or the attorney of the claimant shall pay for the reasonable costs of copying
the medical reports, records, films and bills.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-024__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, ï¿½provider of
health careï¿½ has the meaning ascribed to it inNRS 629.031.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2019,
2499; A2021,
1420)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-025">
          <num>690B.025</num>
          <heading>Primary and excess coverage; garage operator who loans vehicle
to customer required to provide notice to customer regarding coverage;
modification of provision by written agreement; applicability.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-025__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If two or more policies of liability
insurance covering the same motor vehicle are in effect when the motor vehicle
is involved in an incident which results in a claim against the policies:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-025__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the motor vehicle was being operated by a
person engaged in the business of selling, repairing, servicing, delivering,
testing, road testing, parking or storing motor vehicles, or by an agent or
employee of the person while in pursuit of that business, the policy issued to
that business shall be deemed to be primary and any other policy shall be
deemed to provide excess coverage.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-025__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the motor vehicle was being operated by a
person described in paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-025__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>in any pursuit other than of that business,
or by some other person, the policy issued to the operator of the vehicle shall
be deemed to be primary and any policy issued to the business shall be deemed
to provide excess coverage.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-025__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If, while the vehicle of the customer was
being repaired or serviced in the bailment of a garage operator engaged in the
business of repairing or servicing motor vehicles, the customer is lent by the
garage operator a motor vehicle for use during the time required to complete
the repairs or service, the policy issued to the customer shall be deemed to be
primary and all other policies shall be deemed to provide excess coverage. A
garage operator engaged in the business of repairing or servicing motor
vehicles who loans a customer a vehicle for use during the time required to
complete the repairs or service shall provide express notice to the customer
that the customerï¿½s policy of insurance will provide primary coverage while the
customer is operating that vehicle.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-025__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions in subsection 1 may be
modified but only by a written agreement signed by all the insurers who have
issued policies applicable to a claim described in subsection 1 and by all the
insureds under those policies.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-025__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>This section applies only to policies
of liability insurance issued or renewed on or after July 1, 1981.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1981,
180; A1987,
451)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-028">
          <num>690B.028</num>
          <heading>Insurer prohibited from taking adverse action because of
violation of speed limit in certain cases.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>An
insurer shall not impose on an insured or group of insured an increase in rates
for motor vehicle insurance because of a conviction or a finding by a juvenile
court of a violation of the speed limit under the circumstances described in
subsection 1 ofNRS 484B.617, nor
shall an insurer cancel or refuse to renew a policy of insurance for that
reason.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1997,
2525)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-029">
          <num>690B.029</num>
          <heading>Mandatory provision for reduction of premiums for persons 55
years of age or older in certain circumstances; requirements relating to course
of traffic safety; approval of policy by Commissioner.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-029__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A policy of insurance against liability
arising out of the ownership, maintenance or use of a motor vehicle delivered
or issued for delivery in this State to a person who is 55 years of age or
older must contain a provision for the reduction in the premiums for 3-year
periods if the insured:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-029__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Successfully completes, after attaining 55
years of age and every 3 years thereafter, a course of traffic safety approved
by the Department of Motor Vehicles; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-029__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For the 3-year period before completing the
course of traffic safety and each 3-year period thereafter:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="690B-029__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Is not involved in a crash involving a
motor vehicle for which the insured is at fault;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="690B-029__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Maintains a driving record free of
violations; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="690B-029__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Has not been convicted of, or entered
a plea of guilty, guilty but mentally ill or nolo contendere to, a moving
traffic violation or an offense involving:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (I) The operation of a motor vehicle
while under the influence of intoxicating liquor or a controlled substance; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (II) Any other conduct prohibited byNRS 484C.110,484C.120,484C.130or484C.430or a law of any other
jurisdiction that prohibits the same or similar conduct.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-029__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The reduction in the premiums provided
for in subsection 1 must be based on the actuarial and loss experience data
available to each insurer and must be approved by the Commissioner. Each
reduction must be calculated based on the amount of the premium before any
reduction in that premium is made pursuant to this section, and not on the
amount of the premium once it has been reduced.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-029__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A course of traffic safety that an
insured is required to complete as the result of moving traffic violations must
not be used as the basis for a reduction in premiums pursuant to this section.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-029__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The organization that offers a course
of traffic safety approved by the Department of Motor Vehicles shall issue a
certificate to each person who successfully completes the course. A person must
use the certificate to qualify for the reduction in the premiums pursuant to
this section.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-029__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commissioner shall review and
approve or disapprove a policy of insurance that offers a reduction in the
premiums pursuant to subsection 1. An insurer must receive written approval
from the Commissioner before delivering or issuing a policy with a provision
containing such a reduction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1989,
1679; A1995,
2481;1999,
3436;2001,
2636;2003,
1505;2005,
172;2007,
1484;2009,
1890;2015,
1697)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-031">
          <num>690B.031</num>
          <heading>Reduction in premium of certain policies of insurance required
if motor vehicle is equipped with air bag and other safety device; calculation;
approval of Commissioner.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-031__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A policy of insurance providing
coverage arising out of the ownership, maintenance or use of a motor vehicle,
other than a motorcycle, which is delivered or issued for delivery in this
State and includes coverage for the payment of reasonable and necessary medical
expenses or uninsured and underinsured motorists coverage, or both, must
contain a provision for the reduction in the premium for such coverage if the
motor vehicle:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-031__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Is equipped with an air bag on the driverï¿½s
side of the front seat or air bags on the driverï¿½s side and passengerï¿½s side of
the front seat; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-031__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Contains any other safety device, other than
safety belts, which substantially enhances the safety of the occupants of the
motor vehicle.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-031__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The reduction in premiums required by
subsection 1 must be based upon the actuarial and loss experience data
available to each insurer and must be approved by the Commissioner. The insurer
may offer additional reductions in premiums pursuant to the requirements set
forth in subsection 1 if they are approved by the Commissioner. Each reduction
must be calculated based on the amount of the premium before any reduction in
that premium is made pursuant to this section, and not on the amount of the
premium once it has been reduced.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-031__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commissioner shall review and
approve or disapprove each policy of insurance that offers a reduction in the
premiums provided for in this section. An insurer must receive the written
approval of the Commissioner before delivering or issuing for delivery a policy
that provides for such a reduction.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1993,
2495; A2021,
502)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-035">
          <num>690B.035</num>
          <heading>Policy covering damage to one or more of operatorï¿½s vehicles.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>An insurer may issue to a holder of an
operatorï¿½s policy of liability insurance a policy covering damage to one or
more of the operatorï¿½s vehicles. The policy is not required to provide
liability insurance or uninsured vehicle coverage.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1987,
1098)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-037">
          <num>690B.037</num>
          <heading>Authority of owner or authorized agent to give consent for
towing and storage of damaged motor vehicle.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-037__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the insurer provides notice to the
owner or the authorized agent of the owner that the motor vehicle is a total
loss vehicle as that term is defined inNRS
487.790, the motor vehicle to be towed and placed in storage at the
direction and expense of the insurer; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-037__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the insurer provides notice to the
owner or the authorized agent of the owner that the motor vehicle is a
repairable vehicle, the motor vehicle to be towed to a repair shop designated
by the owner or the authorized agent of the owner.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2011,
1404)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-040">
          <num>690B.040</num>
          <heading>Policy providing certain automobile coverage in Mexico.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>An authorized casualty insurer may issue
through its licensed agents an automobile insurance policy in which coverage
for liability resulting from bodily injury and property damage occurring in
Mexico is provided by an insurer authorized to transact and transacting such
insurance in Mexico under the laws of Mexico, in a portion of such policy or
endorsement thereon or rider attached thereto executed by or on behalf of such
other insurer, and whether or not such other insurer is authorized to transact
insurance in this State.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1971,
1778)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-090">
          <num>690B.090</num>
          <heading>Issuance authorized.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-090__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any casualty insurer may provide
industrial insurance pursuant to the general provisions ofchapters 616Ato617,
inclusive, of NRS concerning the respective rights and obligations of employees
and their employers, if the insurer:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-090__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Has a certificate of authority issued by the
Commissioner pursuant tochapter 680Aof
NRS; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-090__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Is specifically qualified pursuant to
paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-090__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 1 ofNRS
681A.020.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-090__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The insurance may be purchased by
qualified employers to secure the payment of compensation for employees injured
in the course of employment.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-090__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The employer shall bear the costs for
private insurance.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1995,
2059)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-100">
          <num>690B.100</num>
          <heading>Definitions.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-100__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>ï¿½Homeï¿½ means a structure used primarily
for residential purposes and includes, without limitation:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-100__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A single-family dwelling;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-100__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A unit in a multiple-family structure;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-100__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A mobile home; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-100__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The common elements of a common-interest
community, as defined inNRS 116.017,
and any appurtenance to the common elements.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-100__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>ï¿½Insurance for home protectionï¿½ means a
contract of insurance, which affords coverage over a specified term for a
predetermined fee, under which a person, other than the manufacturer, builder,
seller or lessor of the home, agrees to repair, replace or indemnify from the
cost of repair or replacement based upon the failure of any structure,
component, system or appliance of the home. The term does not include:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-100__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A contract which insures against any
consequential losses caused by the defects or failures.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-100__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An annual home service agreement on household
appliances, systems and components if the agreement principally provides for
service, repair or replacement due to normal wear and tear or inherent defect.
Such agreements may include provisions for incidental indemnity or for service
or repair of roof leaks.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1981,
1321; A1995,
1630,2558;1997,
650;1999,
1447;2003,
3317)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-110">
          <num>690B.110</num>
          <heading>Applicability of other provisions.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-110__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as provided in subsection 2 andNRS 690B.100to690B.180, inclusive, insurance for home
protection is subject to all applicable provisions of this Code.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-110__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions ofchapters 687Aand692Cof NRS do not apply to insurance for home protection.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1981,
1323)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-120">
          <num>690B.120</num>
          <heading>Exemption of person selling insurance from licensing
requirements as agent, broker or solicitor.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-120__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The personï¿½s sales activity is
conducted pursuant to a written contract with the insurer which regulates his
or her activity.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-120__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The person holds a valid brokerï¿½s,
broker-salespersonï¿½s or salespersonï¿½s license issued pursuant tochapter 645of NRS.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1981,
1323)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-130">
          <num>690B.130</num>
          <heading>Deposit of securities or surety bond; maintenance of capital
stock or surplus, premium reserves and losses and loss expense reserves.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-130__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 2, an insurer who issues policies of insurance for home protection,
other than casualty insurance, shall deposit, in accordance withchapter 682Bof NRS, securities having a market
value of not less than $50,000, unless the insurer furnishes evidence
satisfactory to the Commissioner of maintaining a deposit of not less than that
amount which complies with the requirements of the state of domicile of the
insurer and is held for the protection of all holders of insurance contracts.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-130__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In lieu of the deposit of securities,
the insurer may post with the Commissioner a surety bond of not less than
$50,000 executed by an insurer who has a valid certificate of authority issued
by the Commissioner.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-130__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The insurer shall maintain:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-130__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Unimpaired paid-in capital stock or
unimpaired basic surplus, or a combination thereof, in an amount not less than
10 percent of the amount charged as premiums for insurance currently in effect,
but not less than $50,000, nor more than is required byNRS 680A.120for a certificate of
authority.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-130__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Unearned premium reserves as required byNRS 681B.060.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-130__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Losses and loss expense reserves as required
by subsection 1 ofNRS 681B.050.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1981,
1321; A1991,
2034;1995,
1630)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-140">
          <num>690B.140</num>
          <heading>Investments in tangible personal property: Limitation; waiver.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>An insurer who issues policies of insurance
for home protection, other than casualty insurance, may make investments in
tangible personal property for use in fulfilling its obligations to repair or
replace components, systems or appliances of the home under its contracts of
insurance for home protection, in an amount not to exceed 35 percent of its
assets, as determined pursuant toNRS
681B.010, unless the Commissioner, whenever the Commissioner deems it
appropriate, waives this limitation by regulation.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1981,
1322; A1999,
1448)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-150">
          <num>690B.150</num>
          <heading>Filing of annual and quarterly statements.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-150__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The annual statement required byNRS 680A.270in the form prescribed by the
Commissioner on or before March 1 of each year to cover the preceding calendar
year; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-150__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The quarterly statements required byNRS 680A.270in accordance with the
provisions of subsection 5 of that section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1981,
1322; A1991,
2034;2019,
1706)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-155">
          <num>690B.155</num>
          <heading>Provision requiring binding arbitration authorized; procedures
for arbitration.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-155__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Subject to the approval of the
Commissioner, a contract of insurance for home protection may include a
provision which requires the parties to the contract to submit for binding
arbitration any dispute between the parties concerning any matter directly or
indirectly related to, or associated with, the contract.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-155__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 3, the arbitration must be conducted pursuant to the rules for
commercial arbitration established by the American Arbitration Association. The
insurer is responsible for any administrative fees and expenses relating to the
arbitration, except that the insurer is not responsible for attorneyï¿½s fees and
fees for expert witnesses unless those fees are awarded by the arbitrator.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-155__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a provision described in subsection
1 is included in a contract of insurance for home protection, the provision
shall not be deemed unenforceable as an unreasonable contract of adhesion if
the provision is included in compliance with the provisions of subsection 1.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1995,
2557)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-160">
          <num>690B.160</num>
          <heading>Contracts: Specifications; cancellation; renewal.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-160__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A contract of insurance for home
protection must specify:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-160__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The structures, components, systems and
appliances covered by the provisions of the contract.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-160__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any exclusions from and limitations on
coverage.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-160__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The period during which the contract will be
in effect, and the renewal terms, if any.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-160__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The services to be performed by the insurer
and the terms and conditions of the insurerï¿½s performance.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-160__subsec_1__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The copayment, service fee or deductible
charge, if any, to be charged to the insured.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-160__subsec_1__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>All limitations regarding the performance of
services, including any restrictions as to the time during or geographical area
within which services may be requested or will be performed.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-160__subsec_1__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>That the insurer will commence an
investigation of a claim upon a request from the insured by telephone, without
any requirement that claim forms or applications be filed before the
commencement of the investigation.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-160__subsec_1__subsec_h">
              <num>(h)</num>
              <content>
                <p>That, except in an emergency, including,
without limitation, the loss of heating, cooling, plumbing or electrical
service by the insured, services will be initiated by or under the direction of
the insurer within 48 hours after the conclusion of an investigation of a
claim. Work must commence on an emergency not later than 24 hours after the
report of the claim. The Commissioner may adopt regulations to define
ï¿½emergencyï¿½ for the purposes of this paragraph.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-160__subsec_1__subsec_i">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Other conditions and provisions pertaining to
the coverage as required by the insurance laws of this State or regulations
adopted by the Commissioner.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-160__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Insurance for home protection may not
be cancelled during the term for which it is issued, except:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-160__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For nonpayment of the fee for the contract.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-160__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For fraud or misrepresentation of facts
material to the issuance or renewal of the contract.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-160__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Insurance which provides coverage before the
home is sold if the sale is not made. The cancellation must be made in
accordance with the contract provisions.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-160__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Insurance for home protection is not
renewable unless its terms provide otherwise.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1981,
1322; A1999,
1448)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-170">
          <num>690B.170</num>
          <heading>Contracts: Regulations on content.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-170__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Obtain fairness in the exclusions from
the coverage provided; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-170__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Avoid illusory coverage caused by the
nature or extent of the coverage exclusions.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1981,
1323)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-175">
          <num>690B.175</num>
          <heading>Regulations regarding administrative expenses for insurers and
accounting standards.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-175__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Defining administrative expenses for
insurers who issue policies of insurance for home protection, and setting
limitations on the amounts of such expenses as a percentage of total premiums;
and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-175__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Defining accounting standards to be
used for such insurers.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1995,
1630)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-180">
          <num>690B.180</num>
          <heading>Prohibited acts.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-180__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Engage in any other business of
insurance or real estate pursuant tochapters 645to645H, inclusive, of NRS.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-180__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Assume reinsurance from any other
insurer.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1981,
1322; A1999,
1449;2017,
3105)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-200">
          <num>690B.200</num>
          <heading>Definitions.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>As
used inNRS 690B.200to690B.360, inclusive, unless the context
otherwise requires, the words and terms defined inNRS 690B.210to690B.240, inclusive, have the meanings
ascribed to them in those sections.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2003,
921,3479;
A2017,
2376)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-210">
          <num>690B.210</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Claims-made policyï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Claims-made
policyï¿½ means a policy of professional liability insurance that provides
coverage only for claims that arise from incidents or events which occur while
the policy is in force and which are reported to the insurer while the policy
is in force.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2003,
921,3479)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-220">
          <num>690B.220</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Extended reporting endorsementï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Extended reporting endorsementï¿½ means an
endorsement to a claims-made policy which requires the payment of a separate
premium and which provides coverage for claims that arise from incidents or
events which occur while the claims-made policy is in force but which are
reported to the insurer after the claims-made policy is terminated.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2003,
921,3479)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-230">
          <num>690B.230</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Practitionerï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Practitionerï¿½
means a practitioner who provides health care.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2003,
922,3479)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-240">
          <num>690B.240</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Professional liability insuranceï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Professional liability insuranceï¿½ means a
policy of insurance covering the liability of a practitioner for a breach of
his or her professional duty toward a patient.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2003,
922,3479)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-250">
          <num>690B.250</num>
          <heading>Practitioners of the healing arts: Reports to licensing boards;
availability for public inspection.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-250__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each insurer which issues a policy of
insurance covering the liability of a practitioner licensed pursuant tochapters 630to640,
inclusive, of NRS or who holds a license or limited license issued pursuant tochapter 653of NRS for a breach of his or her
professional duty toward a patient shall report to the board which licensed the
practitioner within 45 days each settlement or award made or judgment rendered
by reason of a claim, if the settlement, award or judgment is for more than
$5,000, giving the name of the claimant and the practitioner and the
circumstances of the case.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-250__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A practitioner licensed pursuant tochapters 630to640,
inclusive, of NRS or who holds a license or limited license issued pursuant tochapter 653of NRS who does not have insurance
covering liability for a breach of his or her professional duty toward a
patient shall report to the board which issued the practitionerï¿½s license
within 45 days of each settlement or award made or judgment rendered by reason
of a claim, if the settlement, award or judgment is for more than $5,000,
giving the practitionerï¿½s name, the name of the claimant and the circumstances
of the case.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-250__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>These reports are public records and
must be made available for public inspection within a reasonable time after
they are received by the licensing board.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1981,
589; A1985,
2246;2002
Special Session, 24;2003,
3480;2017,
2376;2019,
2740;2023,
1710)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-270">
          <num>690B.270</num>
          <heading>Disclosure to practitioner of reasons for failure to issue
professional liability insurance.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If
an insurer declines to issue to a practitioner licensed pursuant tochapter 630,631,632or633of
NRS a policy of professional liability insurance, the insurer shall, upon the
request of the practitioner, disclose to the practitioner the reasons the
insurer declined to issue the policy.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2003,
3361)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-280">
          <num>690B.280</num>
          <heading>Disclosure to practitioner of reasons for higher premium.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If an insurer, for a policy of professional
liability insurance for a practitioner licensed pursuant tochapter 630,631,632or633of
NRS, sets the premium for the policy for the practitioner at a rate that is
higher than the standard rate of the insurer for the applicable type of policy
and specialty of the practitioner, the insurer shall, upon the request of the
practitioner, disclose the reasons the insurer set the premium for the policy
at the higher rate.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2003,
3361)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-290">
          <num>690B.290</num>
          <heading>Insurer offering to issue claims-made policy required to offer
extended reporting endorsement to certain practitioners; disclosure of formula
used to determine premium.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-290__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Offer to issue an extended reporting
endorsement to the practitioner; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-290__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Disclose to the practitioner the cost
formula that the insurer uses to determine the premium for the extended
reporting endorsement. The cost formula must be based on:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-290__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An amount that is not more than twice the
amount of the premium for the claims-made policy at the time of the termination
of that policy; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-290__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The rates filed by the insurer and approved
by the Commissioner.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2003,
922)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-300">
          <num>690B.300</num>
          <heading>Prohibition against setting different premium rates based on
number of babies delivered for certain practitioners; exception.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-300__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in this
section, if an insurer issues a policy of professional liability insurance to a
practitioner licensed pursuant tochapter 630,632or633of
NRS who delivers one or more babies per year, the insurer shall not set the
premium for the policy at a rate that is different from the rate set for such a
policy issued by the insurer to any other practitioner licensed pursuant tochapter 630,632or633of NRS who delivers one or more babies
per year if the difference in rates is based in whole or in part upon the
number of babies delivered per year by the practitioner.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-300__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If an insurer issues a policy of
professional liability insurance to a practitioner licensed pursuant tochapter 630,632or633of NRS who delivers one or more babies
per year, the insurer may set the premium for the policy at a rate that is different,
based in whole or in part upon the number of babies delivered per year by the
practitioner, from the rate set for such a policy issued by the insurer to any
other practitioner licensed pursuant tochapter
630,632or633of NRS who delivers one or more babies per year if the insurer:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-300__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Bases the difference upon actuarial and loss
experience data available to the insurer; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-300__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Obtains the approval of the Commissioner for
the difference in rates.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-300__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of this section do not
prohibit an insurer from setting the premium for a policy of professional liability
insurance issued to a practitioner licensed pursuant tochapter 630,632or633of NRS who delivers one or more babies
per year at a rate that is different from the rate set for such a policy issued
by the insurer to any other practitioner licensed pursuant tochapter 630,632or633of NRS who delivers one or more babies
per year if the difference in rates is based solely upon factors other than the
number of babies delivered per year by the practitioner.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2003,
922)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-310">
          <num>690B.310</num>
          <heading>Prohibition against confidentiality of certain information
relating to settlement of claim or action for breach of professional duty of
certain practitioners.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-310__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If an agreement settles a claim or
action against a practitioner licensed pursuant tochapter
630,631,632or633of NRS for a breach of his or her
professional duty toward a patient, the following terms of the agreement must
not be made confidential:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-310__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The names of the parties;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-310__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The date of the incidents or events giving
rise to the claim or action;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-310__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The nature of the claim or action as set
forth in the complaint and the answer that is filed with the district court;
and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-310__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The effective date of the agreement.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-310__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any provision of an agreement to settle
a claim or action that conflicts with this section is void.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2003,
924)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-320">
          <num>690B.320</num>
          <heading>Additional requirements for insurer offering to issue
claims-made policy to certain practitioners.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-320__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If an insurer offers to issue a
claims-made policy to a practitioner licensed pursuant tochapters 630to640,
inclusive, of NRS or who holds a license or limited license issued pursuant tochapter 653of NRS, the insurer shall:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-320__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Offer to issue to the practitioner an
extended reporting endorsement without a time limitation for reporting a claim.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-320__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Disclose to the practitioner the premium for
the extended reporting endorsement and the cost formula that the insurer uses
to determine the premium for the extended reporting endorsement.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-320__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Disclose to the practitioner the portion of
the premium attributable to funding the extended reporting endorsement offered
at no additional cost to the practitioner in the event of the practitionerï¿½s
death, disability or retirement, if such a benefit is offered.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-320__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Disclose to the practitioner the vesting
requirements for the extended reporting endorsement offered at no additional
cost to the practitioner in the event of the practitionerï¿½s death or
retirement, if such a benefit is offered. If such a benefit is not offered, the
absence of such a benefit must be disclosed.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-320__subsec_1__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Include, as part of the insurance contract,
language which must be approved by the Commissioner and which must be
substantially similar to the following:
If we adopt any revision that would
broaden the coverage under this policy without any additional premium either
within the policy period or within 60 days before the policy period, the
broadened coverage will immediately apply to this policy.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-320__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The disclosures required by subsection
1 must be made as part of the offer and acceptance at the inception of the
policy and again at each renewal in the form of an endorsement attached to the
insurance contract and approved by the Commissioner.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-320__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The requirements set forth in this
section are in addition to the requirements set forth inNRS 690B.290.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2003,
3479; A2019,
2740;2023,
1711)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-330">
          <num>690B.330</num>
          <heading>Required reduction in premium for implementation of qualified
risk management system; regulations; applicability.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-330__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In each rating plan of an insurer that
issues a policy of professional liability insurance to a practitioner licensed
pursuant tochapter 630or633of NRS, the insurer shall provide for a
reduction in the premium for the policy if the practitioner implements a
qualified risk management system. The amount of the reduction in the premium
must be determined by the Commissioner in accordance with the applicable
standards for rates established inNRS
686B.010to686B.1799, inclusive.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-330__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A qualified risk management system must
comply with all requirements established by the Commissioner.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-330__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commissioner shall adopt
regulations to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-330__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Establish the requirements for a qualified
risk management system; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-330__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Carry out the provisions of this section.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-330__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of this section apply to
all rating plans which an insurer that issues a policy of professional
liability insurance to a practitioner licensed pursuant tochapter 630or633of NRS files with the Commissioner on and after the effective date of the
regulations adopted by the Commissioner pursuant to this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2003,
3480; A2019,
1440)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-350">
          <num>690B.350</num>
          <heading>Essential medical specialties: Determination, cancellation,
termination or nonrenewal of professional liability insurance.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-350__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The requirements of this section apply
only if, after a hearing convened at the discretion of the Commissioner, the
Commissioner determines that the market for professional liability insurance
issued to any class, type or specialty of practitioner licensed pursuant tochapter 630,631or633of NRS is not competitive and that such
insurance is unavailable or unaffordable for a substantial number of such
practitioners.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-350__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the Commissioner convenes a hearing
pursuant to subsection 1 and issues a finding that the market for professional
liability insurance issued to any class, type or specialty of practitioner
licensed pursuant tochapter 630,631or633of
NRS is not competitive, the Commissioner may designate that class, type or
specialty of practitioner to be an essential medical specialty.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-350__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in this
section, if an insurer intends to cancel, terminate or otherwise not renew all
policies of professional liability insurance that it has issued to any class,
type or specialty of practitioner licensed pursuant tochapter 630,631or633of NRS, the insurer must provide 120
daysï¿½ notice of its intended action to the Commissioner and the practitioners
before its intended action becomes effective.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-350__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If an insurer intends to cancel,
terminate or otherwise not renew a specific policy of professional liability
insurance that it has issued to a practitioner who is practicing in one or more
of the essential medical specialties designated by the Commissioner:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-350__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The insurer must provide 120 daysï¿½ notice to
the practitioner before its intended action becomes effective; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-350__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Commissioner may require the insurer to
delay its intended action for a period of not more than 60 days if the
Commissioner determines that a replacement policy is not readily available to
the practitioner.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-350__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If an insurer intends to cancel,
terminate or otherwise not renew all policies of professional liability
insurance that it has issued to practitioners who are practicing in one or more
of the essential medical specialties designated by the Commissioner:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-350__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The insurer must provide 120 daysï¿½ notice of
its intended action to the Commissioner and the practitioners before its
intended action becomes effective; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-350__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Commissioner may require the insurer to
delay its intended action for a period of not more than 60 days if the
Commissioner determines that replacement policies are not readily available to
the practitioners.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-350__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commissioner may adopt any
regulations that are necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2003,
922; A2003,
3361;2017,
2377)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-360">
          <num>690B.360</num>
          <heading>Information pertinent to monitoring compliance with applicable
standards for rates: Commissioner authorized to collect; analysis; report to
Legislature required under certain circumstances.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-360__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commissioner may collect all
information which is pertinent to monitoring whether an insurer that issues
professional liability insurance for a practitioner licensed pursuant tochapter 630,631,632or633of
NRS is complying with the applicable standards for rates established inNRS 686B.010to686B.1799, inclusive. Such information
may include, without limitation:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-360__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The amount of gross premiums collected with
regard to each medical specialty;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-360__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Information relating to loss ratios; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-360__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Information reported pursuant toNRS 679B.430and679B.440.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-360__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In addition to the information
collected pursuant to subsection 1, the Commissioner may request any additional
information from an insurer:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-360__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Whose rates and credit utilization are
materially different from other insurers in the market for professional
liability insurance for a practitioner licensed pursuant tochapter 630,631,632or633of
NRS in this State;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-360__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Whose credit utilization shows a substantial
change from the previous year; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-360__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Whose information collected pursuant to
subsection 1 indicates a potentially adverse trend.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-360__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the Commissioner requests additional
information from an insurer pursuant to subsection 2, the Commissioner may:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-360__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Determine whether the additional information
offers a reasonable explanation for the results described in paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-360__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>,</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-360__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-360__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 2; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-360__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Take any steps permitted by law that are
necessary and appropriate to assure the ongoing stability of the market for
professional liability insurance for a practitioner licensed pursuant tochapter 630,631,632or633of
NRS in this State.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-360__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>On an ongoing basis, the Commissioner
may analyze and evaluate the information collected pursuant to this section to
determine trends in and measure the health of the market for professional
liability insurance for a practitioner licensed pursuant tochapter 630,631,632or633of
NRS in this State.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-360__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the Commissioner convenes a hearing
pursuant to subsection 1 ofNRS 690B.350and determines that the market for professional liability insurance issued to
any class, type or specialty of practitioner licensed pursuant tochapter 630,631or633of NRS is not competitive and that such
insurance is unavailable or unaffordable for a substantial number of such
practitioners, the Commissioner shall prepare and submit a report of the
Commissionerï¿½s findings and recommendations to the Director of the Legislative
Counsel Bureau for transmittal to members of the Legislature.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2003,
923; A2017,
2378;2019,
1440,1706)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-400">
          <num>690B.400</num>
          <heading>Definitions.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>As
used inNRS 690B.400to690B.495, inclusive, the words and terms
defined inNRS 690B.410to690B.430, inclusive, have the meanings
ascribed to them in those sections.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2015,
1375,1398;
A2021,
3763)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-410">
          <num>690B.410</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Driverï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Driverï¿½
has the meaning ascribed to it inNRS
706A.040.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2015,
1375,1398)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-415">
          <num>690B.415</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Monitored autonomous vehicle providerï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Monitored autonomous vehicle providerï¿½ has
the meaning ascribed to it inNRS 706A.047.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2021,
3762)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-420">
          <num>690B.420</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Transportation network companyï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Transportation network companyï¿½ has the
meaning ascribed to it inNRS 706A.050.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2015,
1375,1398)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-425">
          <num>690B.425</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Transportation network company insuranceï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Transportation network company insuranceï¿½
means a policy of insurance that includes coverage specifically for the use of
a vehicle by a driver or monitored autonomous vehicle provider pursuant toNRS 690B.400to690B.495, inclusive.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2015,
1375,1398;
A2021,
3763)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-430">
          <num>690B.430</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Transportation servicesï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Transportation
servicesï¿½ has the meaning ascribed to it inNRS
706A.060.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2015,
1375,1398)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-450">
          <num>690B.450</num>
          <heading>Applicability.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The
provisions ofNRS 690B.400to690B.495, inclusive, do not apply to a
person who is regulated pursuant tochapter 704or706of NRS unless the person holds a permit
issued pursuant toNRS 706A.130.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2015,
1375,1398;
A2021,
3763)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-460">
          <num>690B.460</num>
          <heading>Required disclosures by transportation network companies to
drivers.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-460__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Disclose the insurance coverage and
limits of liability that the transportation network company provides for a
driver while the driver is providing transportation services; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-460__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notify the person that:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-460__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>His or her insurance for the operation of a
motor vehicle required pursuant toNRS
485.185may not provide coverage for the use of a motor vehicle to provide
transportation services.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-460__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If comprehensive or collision coverage was
purchased in addition to such insurance, the comprehensive or collision
coverage may not apply to any damage which results from the use of the motor
vehicle while a driver is providing transportation services or logged into the
digital network or software application service of a transportation network
company and available to receive requests for transportation services.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-460__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Disclose to the person that, if there
is a lien against a vehicle used by a driver to provide transportation
services, the driver must notify the lienholder that the vehicle is being used
to provide transportation services.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-460__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Disclose to the person that the use of
a vehicle to provide transportation services may violate the contract between a
driver and a lienholder.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2015,
1376,1398)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-470">
          <num>690B.470</num>
          <heading>Transportation network company insurance: Minimum coverage
requirements for drivers, transportation network companies and monitored autonomous
vehicle providers; additional coverage; duties of insurer; payment of claims;
transportation network company not deemed owner of vehicle.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-470__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every transportation network company or
driver shall continuously provide, during any period in which the driver is
providing transportation services, transportation network company insurance
provided by an insurance company licensed by the Division of Insurance of the
Department of Business and Industry and approved to do business in this State
or a broker licensed pursuant tochapter 685Aof NRS or procured directly from a nonadmitted insurer, as defined inNRS 685A.0375:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-470__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In an amount of not less than $1,500,000 for
bodily injury to or death of one or more persons and injury to or destruction
of property of others in any one accident or motor vehicle crash that occurs
while the driver is providing transportation services;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-470__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In an amount of not less than $50,000 for
bodily injury to or death of one person in any one accident or motor vehicle
crash that occurs while the driver is logged into the digital network or
software application service of the transportation network company and
available to receive requests for transportation services but is not otherwise
providing transportation services;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-470__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Subject to the minimum amount for one person
required by paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-470__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>, in an amount of not less than $100,000 for bodily
injury to or death of two or more persons in any one accident or motor vehicle
crash that occurs while the driver is logged into the digital network or
software application service of the transportation network company and
available to receive requests for transportation services but is not otherwise
providing transportation services; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-470__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In an amount of not less than $25,000 for
injury to or destruction of property of others in any one accident or motor
vehicle crash that occurs while the driver is logged into the digital network
or software application service of the transportation network company and
available to receive requests for transportation services but is not otherwise
providing transportation services,
ï¿½for the
payment of tort liabilities arising from the maintenance or use of the motor
vehicle.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-470__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every monitored autonomous vehicle
provider shall continuously provide, during any period in which a monitored
autonomous vehicle provider is operating a monitored autonomous vehicle,
transportation network company insurance provided by an insurance company
licensed by the Division of Insurance of the Department of Business and
Industry and approved to do business in this State or a broker licensed
pursuant tochapter 685Aof NRS or procured
directly from a nonadmitted insurer, as defined inNRS 685A.0375, in an amount of not less
than $1,500,000 for bodily injury to or destruction of property of others in
any one accident or motor vehicle crash that occurs while the monitored
autonomous vehicle provider is operating a monitored autonomous vehicle for the
payment of tort liabilities arising from the maintenance or use of the monitored
autonomous vehicle.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-470__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The transportation network company
insurance required by subsection 1 or 2, as applicable, may be provided through
one or a combination of insurance policies provided by the transportation
network company, the driver, the monitored autonomous vehicle provider, both
the transportation network company and the driver or both the transportation
network company and the monitored autonomous vehicle provider.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-470__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every transportation network company
shall continuously provide, during any period in which the driver or monitored
autonomous vehicle provider is providing transportation services,
transportation network company insurance provided by an insurance company
licensed by the Division of Insurance of the Department of Business and
Industry and approved to do business in this State or a broker licensed
pursuant tochapter 685Aof NRS or procured
directly from a nonadmitted insurer, as defined inNRS 685A.0375, which meets the
requirements of subsection 1 or 2, as applicable, as primary insurance if the
insurance provided by the driver or monitored autonomous vehicle provider:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-470__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Lapses; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-470__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Fails to meet the requirements of subsection
1 or 2, as applicable.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-470__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding the provisions ofNRS 485.185and485.186which require the owner or operator
of a motor vehicle to provide insurance, transportation network company
insurance shall be deemed to satisfy the requirements ofNRS 485.185or485.186, as appropriate, regardless of
whether the insurance is provided by the transportation network company, the
driver, the monitored autonomous vehicle provider, both the transportation
network company and the driver or both the transportation network company and
the monitored autonomous vehicle provider, if the transportation network
company insurance otherwise satisfies the requirements ofNRS 485.185or485.186, as appropriate.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-470__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In addition to the coverage required
pursuant to subsection 1 or 2, as applicable, a policy of transportation
network company insurance may include additional coverage, including, without
limitation, coverage for medical payments, coverage for uninsured or
underinsured motorists, comprehensive coverage and collision coverage.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-470__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An insurer who provides transportation
network company insurance shall not require a policy of insurance for the
operation of a motor vehicle required pursuant toNRS 485.185or485.186, as appropriate, to deny a claim
before the transportation network company insurance provides coverage for a
claim.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-470__subsec_8">
            <num>8.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An insurer who provides transportation
network company insurance has a duty to defend and indemnify the driver or
monitored autonomous vehicle provider and the transportation network company.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-470__subsec_9">
            <num>9.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An insurer who provides transportation
network company insurance which includes comprehensive coverage or collision
coverage for the operation of a motor vehicle against which a lienholder holds
a lien shall issue any payment for a claim under such coverage:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-470__subsec_9__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Directly to the person who performs repairs
upon the vehicle; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-470__subsec_9__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Jointly to the owner of the vehicle and the
lienholder.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-470__subsec_10">
            <num>10.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A transportation network company that
provides transportation network company insurance for a motor vehicle is not
deemed to be the owner of the motor vehicle.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-470__subsec_11">
            <num>11.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, ï¿½monitored
autonomous vehicleï¿½ has the meaning ascribed to it inNRS 706A.045.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2015,
1376,1398;
A2021,
3763)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-480">
          <num>690B.480</num>
          <heading>Insurer not required to offer transportation network company
insurance; authority of insurer to offer transportation network company
insurance and charge additional premium; rights of insurer excluding
transportation network company insurance coverage.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-480__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A policy of insurance for the operation
of a motor vehicle required pursuant toNRS
485.185or485.186, as appropriate,
is not required to include transportation network company insurance. An insurer
providing a policy which excludes transportation network company insurance does
not have a duty to defend or indemnify a driver or monitored autonomous vehicle
provider for any claim arising during any period in which the driver or
monitored autonomous vehicle provider is logged into the digital network or
software application service of the transportation network company, available
to receive requests for transportation services or providing transportation
services.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-480__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An insurer who provides a policy of
insurance for the operation of a motor vehicle required pursuant toNRS 485.185or485.186, as appropriate, may include
transportation network company insurance in such a policy. An insurer may
charge an additional premium for the inclusion of transportation network
company insurance in such a policy.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-480__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>An insurer who:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-480__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Defends or indemnifies a driver or monitored
autonomous vehicle provider for a claim arising during any period in which the
driver or monitored autonomous vehicle provider is logged into the digital
network or software application service of the transportation network company,
available to receive requests for transportation services or providing
transportation services; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-480__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Excludes transportation network company
insurance from the policy of insurance for the operation of a motor vehicle
provided to the driver or monitored autonomous vehicle provider,
ï¿½has the
right of contribution against other insurers who provide coverage to the driver
or monitored autonomous vehicle provider to satisfy the coverage required byNRS 690B.470at the time of the loss.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2015,
1377,1400;
A2021,
3765)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-490">
          <num>690B.490</num>
          <heading>Required cooperation and sharing of information during
investigation.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-490__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The date and time of an accident or
motor vehicle crash involving a driver or monitored autonomous vehicle
provider.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-490__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The dates and times that the driver or
monitored autonomous vehicle provider involved in an accident or motor vehicle
crash logged into the digital network or software application service of the
transportation network company for a period of 12 hours immediately preceding
and 12 hours immediately following the accident or motor vehicle crash.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-490__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The dates and times that the driver or
monitored autonomous vehicle provider involved in an accident or motor vehicle
crash logged out of the digital network or software application service of the
transportation network company for a period of 12 hours immediately preceding
and 12 hours immediately following the accident or motor vehicle crash.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-490__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A clear description of the coverage, exclusions
and limits provided under any policy of transportation network company
insurance which applies.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2015,
1378,1400;
A2021,
3766)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-493">
          <num>690B.493</num>
          <heading>Monitored autonomous vehicle required to contain evidence of
coverage; provision of proof of coverage and certain disclosure to law
enforcement and other party if vehicle involved in accident or motor vehicle
crash.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-493__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A monitored autonomous vehicle provider
shall ensure that proof of coverage under a policy of transportation network
company insurance is contained within the monitored autonomous vehicle of the
monitored autonomous vehicle provider at all times when the monitored
autonomous vehicle provider is operating the monitored autonomous vehicle.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-493__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the monitored autonomous vehicle of
a monitored autonomous vehicle provider is involved in an accident or motor
vehicle crash, the monitored autonomous vehicle provider shall ensure that any
law enforcement officer and any party with whom the monitored autonomous
vehicle is involved in the accident or motor vehicle crash is provided with:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="690B-493__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Proof of coverage under a policy of transportation
network company insurance; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="690B-493__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A disclosure as to whether the monitored
autonomous vehicle provider was logged into the digital network or software
application service of the transportation network company, available to receive
requests for transportation services or providing transportation services at
the time of the accident or motor vehicle crash.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-493__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, ï¿½monitored
autonomous vehicleï¿½ has the meaning ascribed to it inNRS 706A.045.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2021,
3762)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_690B-495">
          <num>690B.495</num>
          <heading>Driver required to carry evidence of coverage; required
provision of proof of coverage and certain disclosure to law enforcement
officer and party required if driver involved in accident or motor vehicle
crash.</heading>
          <subsection eId="690B-495__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A driver shall carry proof of coverage
under a policy of transportation network company insurance at all times when
the driver is logged into the digital network or software application service
of the transportation network company, available to receive requests for
transportation services or providing transportation services.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="690B-495__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A driver shall provide proof of
coverage under a policy of transportation network company insurance and
disclose whether he or she was logged into the digital network or software
application service of the transportation network company, available to receive
requests for transportation services or providing transportation services at
the time of an accident or motor vehicle crash upon request to a law
enforcement officer and to any party with whom the driver is involved in an
accident or motor vehicle crash.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2015,
1378,1401)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>