<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="NRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-282"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-282"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#nevada-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-nv"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="282"/>
          <FRBRname value="NRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-282/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-282/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-282/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-282/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="nevada-legislature" href="https://www.leg.state.nv.us" showAs="Nevada State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_282">
        <num>282</num>
        <heading>OFFICIAL BONDS AND OATHS</heading>
        <section eId="sec_282-010">
          <num>282.010</num>
          <heading>Oaths and official bonds of officers; when term of office
begins.</heading>
          <subsection eId="282-010__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Members of the Legislature and all
officers, executive, judicial and ministerial, shall, before entering upon the
duties of their respective offices, provide the official bond required by law,
when such bond shall be required, and take and subscribe to the official oath.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-010__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>All officers elected, except Senators
and members of the Assembly, shall qualify, and execute and deliver their
official bonds when required, as provided in this section, prior to the Tuesday
after the first Monday in January ensuing their election.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-010__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>All officers appointed to fill
vacancies, in the cases provided by law, shall qualify and give bond when
required, within 30 days from the time of their appointment.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-010__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The term of office of all officers,
elected or appointed, shall begin from the time of their qualification, unless
some other express provision is made by law.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [22:108:1866; B ï¿½ 2620; BH ï¿½ 1657; C ï¿½ 1803; RL ï¿½
2786; NCL ï¿½ 4786]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-020">
          <num>282.020</num>
          <heading>Form of official oath.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Members
of the Legislature and all officers, executive, judicial and ministerial,
shall, before they enter upon the duties of their respective offices, take and
subscribe to the following oath:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ I, .........................,
do solemnly swear (or affirm) that I will support, protect and defend the Constitution
and Government of the United States, and the Constitution and government of the
State of Nevada, against all enemies, whether domestic or foreign, and that I
will bear true faith, allegiance and loyalty to the same, any ordinance,
resolution or law of any state notwithstanding, and that I will well and
faithfully perform all the duties of the office of ................, on which I
am about to enter; (if an oath) so help me God; (if an affirmation) under the
pains and penalties of perjury.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1:185:1915; 1919 RL ï¿½ 2891; NCL ï¿½ 4925]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-030">
          <num>282.030</num>
          <heading>No fee to be charged for administering and certifying oath.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>No fees shall be charged by any person for
administering and certifying the oath of office.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [37:49:1883; BH ï¿½ 2378; C ï¿½ 2502; RL ï¿½ 2039; NCL ï¿½
2970]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-040">
          <num>282.040</num>
          <heading>Form.</heading>
          <subsection eId="282-040__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In form joint and several.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-040__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Made payable to the State of Nevada.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-040__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In such penal sum and with such
conditions as may be required by law.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1:135:1865; B ï¿½ 2917; BH ï¿½ 1738; C ï¿½ 1892; RL ï¿½
2868; NCL ï¿½ 4890]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-050">
          <num>282.050</num>
          <heading>Bond in force during term of office; effect of subsequent law;
conditions.</heading>
          <subsection eId="282-050__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every official bond executed by any
officer pursuant to law shall be deemed and taken to be in force, and shall be
obligatory upon the principal and sureties thereon for any and all breaches of
the condition or conditions thereof committed during the time such officer
shall continue to discharge any of the duties of or hold such office.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-050__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every such bond shall be deemed to be
in force and obligatory upon the principal and sureties thereon for the
faithful discharge of all duties which may be required of such officer by any
law enacted subsequently to the execution of such bond, and such condition
shall be expressed therein.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [2:135:1865; B ï¿½ 2918; BH ï¿½ 1739; C ï¿½ 1893; RL ï¿½
2869; NCL ï¿½ 4891]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-060">
          <num>282.060</num>
          <heading>Bond for benefit of injured or aggrieved person; action on bond
without assignment.</heading>
          <subsection eId="282-060__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every official bond executed by any
officer pursuant to law shall be in force and obligatory upon the principal and
sureties thereon, to and for the State of Nevada, and to and for the use and
benefit of all persons who may be injured or aggrieved by the wrongful act or
default of such officer in the officerï¿½s official capacity.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-060__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person so injured or aggrieved may
bring suit on such bond, in his or her own name, without an assignment thereof.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [3:135:1865; B ï¿½ 2919; BH ï¿½ 1740; C ï¿½ 1894; RL ï¿½
2870; NCL ï¿½ 4892]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-070">
          <num>282.070</num>
          <heading>Defects in bond immaterial.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever
any official bond shall not contain the substantial matter, or condition or
conditions, required by law, or there shall be any defect in the approval or
filing thereof, such bond shall not be void so as to discharge such officer and
the officerï¿½s sureties, but they shall be bound to the State or party
interested, and the State or such party may, by action instituted in any court
of competent jurisdiction, suggest the defect of such bond, or such approval or
filing, and recover the Stateï¿½s or partyï¿½s proper and equitable demand or
damages from such officer, and the person or persons who intended to become and
were included in such bond as sureties.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [4:135:1865; B ï¿½ 2920; BH ï¿½ 1741; C ï¿½ 1895; RL ï¿½
2871; NCL ï¿½ 4893]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-080">
          <num>282.080</num>
          <heading>Approval, filing and recording of official bonds.</heading>
          <subsection eId="282-080__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The official bond of the State
Treasurer shall be approved by the Governor, and filed and recorded in the
Office of the Secretary of State.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-080__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The official bonds of all county and
township officers shall be approved by the board of county commissioners, and
filed and recorded in the office of the county clerk of their respective
counties, except:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="282-080__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>That the bond of the county clerk shall be
filed and recorded in the office of the county recorder of the proper county;
and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="282-080__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>That where the county clerk is ex officio
county recorder, the county clerkï¿½s bond shall be filed, recorded and deposited
for safekeeping in the manner provided inNRS
246.020.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [5:135:1865; B ï¿½ 2921; BH ï¿½ 1742; C ï¿½ 1896; RL ï¿½
2872; NCL ï¿½ 4894] + [Part 1:66:1891; C ï¿½ 2352; RL ï¿½ 2887; NCL ï¿½ 4914]—(NRS A1965,
33;1975,
340)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-090">
          <num>282.090</num>
          <heading>Additional bond of county or township officer: Showing of
insufficiency; execution and filing; office vacated for failure to execute and
file bond.</heading>
          <subsection eId="282-090__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Whenever the sureties, or any one of
them, on the official bond of any county or township officer shall die, remove
without the State, become insolvent or insufficient, or the penalty of such
bond shall become insufficient on account of recoveries had thereon, or
otherwise, the board of county commissioners of the proper county, of its own
motion, or on the showing of any person supported by affidavit, shall summon
the officer to appear before the board, at a time stated, not less than 3 days
after service of such summons, and show cause why the officer should not
execute an additional official bond with good and sufficient sureties.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-090__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Should such officer, after due notice,
fail to appear at the time appointed, the matter may be heard and determined in
the officerï¿½s absence. If, after examination, the board of county commissioners
shall be of the opinion that the bond of such officer has become insufficient,
from any cause whatever, the board shall require an additional bond, with such
security as may be deemed necessary.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-090__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The additional bond shall be executed
and filed within such time as the board of county commissioners may order, and
if any officer shall fail to execute and file such additional bond within the
time specified by the order, the office held by the officer shall become
vacant.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [6:135:1865; B ï¿½ 2922; BH ï¿½ 1743; C ï¿½ 1897; RL ï¿½
2873; NCL ï¿½ 4895] + [7:135:1865; B ï¿½ 2923; BH ï¿½ 1744; C ï¿½ 1898; RL ï¿½ 2874; NCL
ï¿½ 4896]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-100">
          <num>282.100</num>
          <heading>Insufficiency of State Treasurerï¿½s bond: Procedure for
procurement of additional bond.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever
the official bond of the State Treasurer becomes insufficient from any cause,
like proceedings as provided inNRS 282.090may be had with reference thereto before the district court of the district in
which such officer holds office. Proceedings shall be commenced by a written
motion supported by affidavit.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [8:135:1865; B ï¿½ 2924; BH ï¿½ 1745; C ï¿½ 1899; RL ï¿½
2875; NCL ï¿½ 4897]—(NRS A1975,
340)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-110">
          <num>282.110</num>
          <heading>Additional bond: Force and liabilities.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Every
such additional bond shall be of like force and obligation upon the principal
and sureties thereon, and shall subject the officer and the officerï¿½s sureties
to the same liabilities as are prescribed respecting the original bonds of
officers.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [9:135:1865; B ï¿½ 2925; BH ï¿½ 1746; C ï¿½ 1900; RL ï¿½
2876; NCL ï¿½ 4898]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-120">
          <num>282.120</num>
          <heading>Number of sureties on official bond.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Unless
otherwise expressly provided, there shall be at least two sureties upon the
official bond of every officer.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [10:135:1865; B ï¿½ 2926; BH ï¿½ 1747; C ï¿½ 1901; RL ï¿½
2877; NCL ï¿½ 4899]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-130">
          <num>282.130</num>
          <heading>Subscription to official bond: Manner; liability.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Subscriptions to official bonds shall be taken
singly, and for a liability not exceeding the amount subscribed.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1:14:1883; BH ï¿½ 1755; C ï¿½ 1885; RL ï¿½ 2885; NCL ï¿½
4912]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-140">
          <num>282.140</num>
          <heading>Justification of surety on bond of county or township officer.</heading>
          <subsection eId="282-140__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>On a bond given by a county officer,
that the surety is a resident and freeholder or householder within that county.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-140__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>That the surety is worth the amount for
which the surety becomes surety over and above all the suretyï¿½s debts and
liabilities in property situated within this state which is not exempt from
sale or execution.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [11:135:1865; A1889,
34; C ï¿½ 1902; RL ï¿½ 2878; NCL ï¿½ 4900]—(NRS A1975,
340;1985,
1217)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-150">
          <num>282.150</num>
          <heading>Liability of sureties when penal sum exceeds $2,000: Several
liability for portions not less than $500.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>When
the penal sum of any bond amounts to more than $2,000, the sureties may become
severally liable for portions not less than $500 of such penal sum, making in
the aggregate at least two sureties for the whole penal sum.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [12:135:1865; B ï¿½ 2928; BH ï¿½ 1749; C ï¿½ 1903; RL ï¿½
2879; NCL ï¿½ 4901]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-160">
          <num>282.160</num>
          <heading>Liability of sureties for ratable proportion; release of surety
on payment of pro rata liability; limitation on amount of judgment.</heading>
          <subsection eId="282-160__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the official bond of the State
Treasurer or any county or township officer becomes insufficient by reason of
the insolvency of any of the sureties thereon, or from any other cause, so that
it does not contain at least two good and sufficient sureties for the whole
penal sum named in the bond, and any liability occurs or becomes fixed by
reason of the defalcation, omission, neglect, misconduct or any act of the
officer who is the principal in the bond, then any surety or sureties, upon the
payment of the suretyï¿½s ratable proportion of the liability on such bond, shall
be released from all further liability thereon, so far as any loss to the State
or county wherein such officer held office is concerned.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-160__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such ratable proportion shall be
ascertained by considering each of the sureties on the bond as solvent, liable
and able to contribute the suretyï¿½s proportion of the whole amount of liability
incurred on the bond.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-160__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The State Board of Examiners, in the
case of the State Treasurer, or the boards of county commissioners of the
several counties, in the case of county officers, shall in such cases, make
settlement with any or all such sureties who propose to pay and do pay their
ratable proportions of the liability accrued on the bond.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-160__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any surety or sureties neglecting or
refusing to pay such ratable proportion, or defending an action for the
recovery of any liability on any official bond, is subject to such prosecution,
judgments and penalties as are provided for by law; but no judgment shall be
rendered against such surety or sureties for an amount above the suretyï¿½s pro
rata liability on such bond, and costs of suit.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [2:14:1883; A1885,
81; BH ï¿½ 1756; C ï¿½ 1886; RL ï¿½ 2886; NCL ï¿½ 4913]—(NRS A1975,
340)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-163">
          <num>282.163</num>
          <heading>Blanket bonds.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>A
blanket fidelity bond or blanket position bond may be furnished at county
expense for all elected county officers except the county treasurer. This
blanket bond must be in an amount not less than $10,000, and conditioned on the
faithful performance of the respective duties of the several officers covered.
The board of county commissioners may also authorize similar blanket bonds for
such other county officers or employees as it may designate.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1979,
288)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-165">
          <num>282.165</num>
          <heading>City employee regularly handling public money required to
furnish corporate surety bond; form and approval of bond.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Every employee of an incorporated city who
regularly handles public funds as part of the employeeï¿½s official duties shall
be required to furnish a corporate surety bond from an insurance company
licensed in the State of Nevada. The form of the bond shall be determined by
the State Board of Examiners, and all bonds shall be subject to the approval of
the Board.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1963,
430)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-170">
          <num>282.170</num>
          <heading>Companies which may execute bond; payment of premiums;
acceptance of bond.</heading>
          <subsection eId="282-170__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The State Treasurer and every district,
county, township and city officer within the State of Nevada, who is required
by law to give an official bond, may have a surety company, which has complied
with all the laws of this state relating to surety companies, execute such bond
for the faithful performance of the duties of the respective office.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-170__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The premium for any surety bond must be
paid for by the State, if the bond is required for the State Treasurer, or by
the district, county or city, as the bond may be required, or by the county if
the bond is required of a township officer, out of any money in their
respective treasuries not otherwise appropriated by law subject to the
limitation that no premium or charge on the bond of the State Treasurer may
exceed one-half of 1 percent per annum on the amount of the bond.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-170__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Whenever any of the officials mentioned
in this section tenders bonds of any surety company for approval to the
Governor, to the district judge, to the board of county commissioners of their
respective counties, or to any official board or person required by law to
approve such bonds, the board or person shall accept such bonds if they are
found good and sufficient.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1:170:1925; NCL ï¿½ 4902] + [2:170:1925; A1933,
34; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 4903] + [3:170:1925; NCL ï¿½ 4904]—(NRS A1975,
341;1985,
1217)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-180">
          <num>282.180</num>
          <heading>Procedure.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Any
surety on the official bond of the State Treasurer or any county or city
officer, or on the official bond of any executor or administrator, or on the
bond or undertaking of any person, where, by law, a bond or undertaking is
required, may be released from all liability thereon accruing, from and after
proper proceedings had therefor, as provided inNRS 282.180to282.220, inclusive.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1:15:1867; B ï¿½ 2929; BH ï¿½ 1750; C ï¿½ 1887; RL ï¿½ 2880;
NCL ï¿½ 4907]—(NRS A1975,
341)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-190">
          <num>282.190</num>
          <heading>Suretyï¿½s statement desiring release from liability: Filing and
service of notice; publication.</heading>
          <subsection eId="282-190__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any surety desiring to be released from
liability on the bond of the State Treasurer shall file with the Governor or
Secretary of State a statement in writing duly subscribed by the surety, or
someone in the suretyï¿½s behalf, setting forth:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="282-190__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The name and office of the person for whom
the surety is surety;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="282-190__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The amount for which the surety is liable as
surety; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="282-190__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The suretyï¿½s desire to be released from
further liability on account thereof.
ï¿½A notice
containing the objects of such statement shall be served personally on the
State Treasurer unless the State Treasurer has left the State, in which case
the notice may be served by publication for 20 days in some newspaper printed
at Carson City, or if none is printed there, then in such newspaper as shall be
designated by the Governor or Secretary of State.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-190__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any surety desiring to be released from
the official bond of any county officer shall file and serve a similar
statement. The statement, except when it concerns the county clerk personally,
shall be filed with the clerk of the board of county commissioners, and when
the county clerk is personally concerned, the statement shall be filed with the
county auditor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-190__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any surety desiring to be released from
liability on the bond of a city officer shall file and serve a similar
statement with the city clerk or other proper officer.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-190__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any surety desiring to be released from
an executorï¿½s or administratorï¿½s bond or undertaking shall file and serve a similar
statement with the clerk of the district court.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-190__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any surety desiring to be released from
any other official bond or undertaking shall file and serve a similar statement
with the proper officer, person or authority.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-190__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>All statements provided for in this
section must be served as provided in subsection 1, except:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="282-190__subsec_6__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>That the notice, if served by publication,
may be published in a newspaper in the same county, and if no newspaper is
published therein, then in an adjoining or other county, without any order from
any court or other authority.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="282-190__subsec_6__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>That in all cases for which publication is
provided, a printed or written notice, posted in at least 10 conspicuous places
within the county, for the time specified, shall be deemed legal notice thereof.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [2:15:1867; B ï¿½ 2930; BH ï¿½ 1751; C ï¿½ 1888; RL ï¿½ 2881;
NCL ï¿½ 4908]—(NRS A1975,
342)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-200">
          <num>282.200</num>
          <heading>Forfeiture of office or appointment upon failure to file new or
additional bond; suspension of functions of office.</heading>
          <subsection eId="282-200__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any officer or person fails within
10 days from the date of a personal service, or within 30 days from the date of
the first insertion of a publication or posted service, to file a new or
additional bond or undertaking, the office or appointment of the person or
officer so failing shall become vacant, and such officer or person shall
forfeit such office or appointment. The office or appointment shall be filled
as in other cases of vacancy, and in the manner provided by law, and the person
applying to be released from liability on the bond or undertaking shall not be
liable thereon after the date provided for the vacating and forfeiting of such
office or appointment.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-200__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a number of sureties on any bond or
undertaking, representing half the amount of the penalty thereof, unite in the
same, or file and serve separate statements as provided inNRS 282.180to282.220, inclusive, the right of such
officer or person to exercise the duties and functions of such office or
appointment immediately ceases until the officer or person files and has
accepted and approved a new or additional bond or undertaking.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-200__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Whenever, by operation ofNRS 282.180to282.220, inclusive, the functions of any
sheriff become suspended, the county clerk shall succeed to all the powers and
discharge all the duties of the sheriff of the county, during such suspension
of the functions of the sheriff.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [3:15:1867; B ï¿½ 2931; BH ï¿½ 1752; C ï¿½ 1889; RL ï¿½ 2882;
NCL ï¿½ 4909]—(NRS A1959,
25)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-210">
          <num>282.210</num>
          <heading>Liability of sureties on original and new or additional bond.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>In case a new or additional bond or
undertaking is filed, the sureties on the original bond or undertaking, not
asking to be released, and on the new or additional bond or undertaking shall
be and continue liable for the official acts of such officer or person jointly
and severally, the same as if all were sureties on one and the same instrument.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [4:15:1867; B ï¿½ 2932; BH ï¿½ 1753; C ï¿½ 1890; RL ï¿½ 2883;
NCL ï¿½ 4910]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-220">
          <num>282.220</num>
          <heading>Amount or penalty of new or additional bond or undertaking: How
determined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever a statement
is filed, or filed and served, as provided inNRS
282.180to282.220, inclusive, the
proper authority shall prescribe the penalty or amount in which a new or
additional bond or undertaking shall be filed, and if no such order be made,
then such new or additional bond or undertaking shall be executed for the same
amount as the original.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [5:15:1867; B ï¿½ 2933; BH ï¿½ 1754; C ï¿½ 1891; RL ï¿½ 2884;
NCL ï¿½ 4911]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-290">
          <num>282.290</num>
          <heading>Faith of State pledged; consent of State to suit on bond;
restitution.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The faith of the
State is pledged to the provisions of all surety bonds which have been issued or
undertaken under the provisions of chapter 193, Statutes of Nevada 1937, as
amended, which established the bond trust fund, and the State consents to suit
against it on such bonds. In cases of loss to a county, township, incorporated
city or irrigation district, under circumstances upon which its surety bonds
are conditioned, the State is charged with the responsibility of making
restitution to any funds suffering loss up to the full amount specified in the
surety bond.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [6:193:1937; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 4915.26]—(NRS A1959,
836;1975,
342)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-305">
          <num>282.305</num>
          <heading>Secretary of State to ensure compliance by state officers.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The Secretary of State shall ensure that state
officers comply with the provisions of this chapter.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1993,
1550)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-315">
          <num>282.315</num>
          <heading>Costs of investigations paid from Reserve for Statutory
Contingency Account; limitations.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The
State Treasurer is hereby authorized to pay from the Reserve for Statutory
Contingency Account on warrants issued by the State Controller, a total sum not
to exceed $2,500 in any 1 year in payment of approved claims for costs of
investigations incurred by the State Board of Examiners in carrying out the
provisions of subsection 5 ofNRS 282.330.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1957,
632; A1975,
342;1991,
1759)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-330">
          <num>282.330</num>
          <heading>Certain officers to report losses to State Board of Examiners;
investigations; procedure for restitution.</heading>
          <subsection eId="282-330__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Losses to counties which occur from
defalcation, misappropriation or negligent loss of public money or from failure
faithfully to perform the duties of office on the part of a county or township
officer or employee must be reported by the district attorney of that county to
the State Board of Examiners.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-330__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Losses to cities which occur from
defalcation, misappropriation or negligent loss of public money or from failure
faithfully to perform the duties of office on the part of a city officer or
employee must be reported by the city attorney of that city to the State Board
of Examiners.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-330__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In the case of the State, any losses
must be reported to the State Board of Examiners by the Attorney General.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-330__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In the case of an irrigation district,
any losses must be reported to the State Board of Examiners by the board of
directors of the irrigation district.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-330__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In each case the State Board of
Examiners shall make, or cause to be made, a full investigation. If, from the
investigation, the State Board of Examiners determines that the loss comes
under the conditions of a surety bond issued pursuant to the provisions of
chapter 193, Statutes of Nevada 1937, as amended, which established the bond
trust fund, the State Board of Examiners shall order that restitution be made
in the following manner:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="282-330__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If there is a sufficient amount in the
Reserve for Statutory Contingency Account to cover the loss, the State
Controller shall draw a warrant on the Reserve for Statutory Contingency
Account for the full amount of the loss as covered by the surety bond, in the
manner in which claims against the State are usually paid, and the State
Treasurer shall pay the warrant.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="282-330__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If there is insufficient money in the Reserve
for Statutory Contingency Account to cover the loss, the State Controller shall
draw a warrant for the full amount in the Reserve for Statutory Contingency
Account for the purpose of making restitution in part, and the State Controller
shall report the condition of the account to the Governor. The Governor shall
take the necessary steps to have the balance due included in the budget, and
report to the next succeeding Legislature. When the balance is thus secured,
the restitution is completed.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [7:193:1937; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 4915.27]—(NRS A1957,
633;1959,
836;1963,
546;1973,
556;1975,
343;1991,
1759)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-340">
          <num>282.340</num>
          <heading>Civil liability on bond of officer or employee: Action for
recovery of loss; lien; judgment; execution.</heading>
          <subsection eId="282-340__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any public officer or employee
defaults, misappropriates or otherwise is responsible for loss of funds committed
to the officerï¿½s or employeeï¿½s care, the officer or employee is civilly liable
for the amount thereof in an action to be prosecuted by:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="282-340__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The district attorney in cases of county and
township officers and employees.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="282-340__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The city attorney in cases of city officers
and employees.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="282-340__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Attorney General in cases of state
officers and irrigation district officers and employees.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-340__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The State, county, city or irrigation
district, as the case may be, has a lien on all real or personal property, not exempt
from execution, of any such officer or employee against whom such an action is
brought for default, misappropriation, or other violation of the conditions of
the officerï¿½s or employeeï¿½s surety bond given under the provisions of chapter
193, Statutes of Nevada 1937, as amended, and such lien becomes effective upon
the execution of such surety bonds by state, county, township, city and
irrigation district officers and employees, and takes precedence over any other
unrecorded lien or encumbrance.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-340__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon judgment being entered in favor of
the State, county, incorporated city or irrigation district, all property
owned, either legally or equitably, by the State, county, township, city or
irrigation district officer or employee violating any condition of such bond,
not exempt from execution, or so much thereof as may be necessary to cover the
amount of the judgment entered, may be sold, as in cases of execution, and the
proceeds applied to payment of the judgment rendered to cover the shortage. If
there is an insufficiency of such property, or the judgment or any part of it
remains unsatisfied, then a deficiency judgment may be entered by the court.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [10:193:1937; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 4915.30]—(NRS A1973,
557;1975,
343)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_282-350">
          <num>282.350</num>
          <heading>Revocation of bond by State Board of Examiners: Grounds.</heading>
          <subsection eId="282-350__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If, after due investigation, notice and
hearing, the officer or employee is found to be addicted to gambling, excessive
drinking of intoxicants or to the use of narcotics.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-350__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon conviction of the officer or
employee of a gross misdemeanor or any more serious crime.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-350__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When the officer or employee is legally
determined to be insane.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="282-350__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>For any other cause deemed reasonable
by the Board.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [11:193:1937; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 4915.31]—(NRS A1957,
634;1973,
558;1975,
344)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>