<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="NRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-503"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-503"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#nevada-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-nv"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="503"/>
          <FRBRname value="NRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-503/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-503/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-503/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-503/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="nevada-legislature" href="https://www.leg.state.nv.us" showAs="Nevada State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_503">
        <num>503</num>
        <heading>HUNTING, FISHING AND</heading>
        <section eId="sec_503-005">
          <num>503.005</num>
          <heading>Manner of hunting: Killing bird or animal while flying in
aircraft prohibited; exceptions; penalty.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-005__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 2, a person shall not kill or attempt to kill any birds or animals
while flying in an aircraft.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-005__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commission may promulgate rules and
regulations whereby the Department may issue permits authorizing the hunting,
killing or nonlethal control of coyotes, bobcats or ravens from an aircraft.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-005__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every person who willfully violates the
provisions of subsection 1 is guilty of a misdemeanor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1973,
1674; A1991,
333;1993,
1670;2003,
1545)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-010">
          <num>503.010</num>
          <heading>Manner of hunting or trapping: Unlawful use of certain modes of
transportation; information and equipment; exceptions.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-010__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in this
section or subsection 2 ofNRS 503.005,
it is unlawful to harass any game mammals or game birds by any means,
including, without limitation, with a manned or unmanned aircraft, firearm,
helicopter, horse, power-driven vessel, motor-driven vehicle, noisemaker or
sailboat.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-010__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in this
subsection, it is unlawful to shoot at any game mammals or game birds with a
weapon from a manned or unmanned aircraft, helicopter or motor-driven vehicle.
A person who is a paraplegic, has had one or both legs amputated or has
suffered a paralysis of one or both legs which severely impedes the personï¿½s
walking may shoot from a stopped motor vehicle which is not parked on the
traveled portion of a public highway, but the person may not shoot from, over
or across a highway or road specified inNRS
503.175.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-010__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is unlawful to spot or locate game
mammals or game birds with any kind of manned or unmanned aircraft or
helicopter and communicate that information, within 24 hours after the aircraft
or helicopter has landed or in violation of a regulation of the Commission, by
any means to a person on the ground for the purpose of hunting or trapping. The
provisions of this subsection do not prohibit an employee or agent of the
Department from providing general information to the public concerning the
location of game birds or game mammals.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-010__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is unlawful to use any information
obtained in violation of the provisions of subsection 3 to hunt or kill game
mammals or game birds.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-010__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is unlawful to use a helicopter to
transport game, hunters or hunting equipment, except when:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-010__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The cargo or passengers, or both, are loaded
and unloaded at airports, airplane landing fields or heliports, which have been
established by a department or agency of the Federal or State Government or by
a county or municipal government and which are accessible by a public road; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-010__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The loading or unloading is done in the
course of an emergency or search and rescue operation.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-010__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is unlawful to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-010__subsec_6__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Use any information obtained from a radio
signal or other transmission received from any transmitting device;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-010__subsec_6__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Make use of equipment designed to receive a
radio signal or other transmission from a transmitting device; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-010__subsec_6__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Use any location information obtained from
records maintained by the Department within 1 year after the date on which the
information was collected, including, without limitation, records of
information received from a transmitting device,
ï¿½to harass or
take any game mammal, game bird or other wildlife.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-010__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is unlawful to make use of equipment
designed to receive a radio signal or other transmission from a transmitting
device for any purpose without written authorization of the Department.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-010__subsec_8">
            <num>8.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of subsection 1 do not
apply to an employee or agent of the Department who, while carrying out his or
her duties, conducts a survey of wildlife with the use of an aircraft.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-010__subsec_9">
            <num>9.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-010__subsec_9__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Aircraftï¿½ includes, without limitation, any
unmanned aerial vehicle, as defined inNRS
493.020, or any other device that is used for navigation of, or flight in,
the air.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-010__subsec_9__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Game birdï¿½ does not include a raven, even if
classified as a game bird pursuant toNRS
501.110.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-010__subsec_9__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Harassï¿½ means to molest, chase, rally,
concentrate, herd, intercept, torment or drive.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-010__subsec_9__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Transmitting deviceï¿½ means any collar or
other device which is attached to any game mammal, game bird or other wildlife
or which is placed for the express purpose of detecting any game mammal, game bird
or other wildlife and emits an electronic signal or uses radio telemetry or a
satellite transmission to determine the location of the game mammal, game bird
or other wildlife.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 8:101:1947; A1949,
292; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 3035.08]—(NRS A1969,
1355;1981,
320;1989,
731;1991,
264,333;2005,
1311;2015,
169;2017,
1567;2019,
450,762)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-015">
          <num>503.015</num>
          <heading>Interference with person lawfully hunting or trapping.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-015__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided inNRS 503.454, it is unlawful for a person,
or a group of people acting together, to intentionally interfere with another
person who is lawfully hunting or trapping. For the purpose of this subsection,
hunting or trapping is ï¿½lawfulï¿½ only if permitted by the owner or person in
possession of the land, other than the government, in addition to any
requirement of license or permit from a public authority.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-015__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of subsection 1 do not
apply to any incidental interference arising from lawful activity by users of
the public land, including without limitation ranchers, miners or persons
seeking lawful recreation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1983,
649; A1991,
969;2017,
2000)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-030">
          <num>503.030</num>
          <heading>Possession of wildlife after end of open season; storage.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-030__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in this
section, it is unlawful for any person to have in his or her control any
wildlife or any part thereof, the killing of which is at any time prohibited,
during the time when such killing is prohibited, and the possession of such
wildlife shall be prima facie evidence that it was the property of the State at
the time it was caught, taken or killed in this State when the killing was
unlawful, and that such taking or killing occurred in the closed season.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-030__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Wildlife legally taken may be stored in
the home of the owner after the end of the open season for hunting or fishing
for it and may be stored in a public warehouse or commercial refrigerator
locker under such rules as may be adopted by the Commission, but in no case
shall more than the amount designated by law as the legal possession limit be
so kept or stored.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-030__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commission is authorized to make
rules requiring evidence of legal taking in this State, or legal taking under
the laws of the state where taken, to be provided in the case of wildlife kept
or stored after the appropriate open season ends in the form of tags,
certificates or otherwise, if deemed necessary or convenient for the
enforcement of this title.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [87:101:1947; A1949,
292; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 3035.87]—(NRS A1969,
1356)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-035">
          <num>503.035</num>
          <heading>Meat or game processor: Disposal for distribution by Department
of game for which processing or storage charges are not paid; immunity; civil
remedies.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-035__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>ï¿½Meat or game processorï¿½ as used in
this section means any person, firm or corporation that receives any game for
the purpose of processing or storage or for the purposes of processing and
storage.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-035__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any meat or game processor who receives
any game for the purpose of processing or storage may, within 90 days after the
receipt thereof, if such game remains in the possession of such meat or game
processor, dispose of such game to the Department if the owner of such game has
not paid such meat or game processor for the processing or storage thereof.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-035__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department shall distribute such
game to public charities on a fair and equitable basis.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-035__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>No action may be commenced against such
meat or game processor by the owner of such game after such game has been
delivered to the Department under the provisions of this section.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-035__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Nothing in this section deprives a meat
or game processor of any remedy at law available to a creditor against a debtor
for the recovery of any money or other legal consideration owing from the owner
of the game to the meat or game processor for such processing or storage.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1959,
365; A1969,
1356;1993,
1671;2003,
1545)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-037">
          <num>503.037</num>
          <heading>Commercial preservation facility: Maintenance of records;
inspection.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-037__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any commercial preservation facility,
including any cold storage locker, trailer or walk-in facility offered by any
commercial enterprise as a service to its customers or as an attraction to that
enterprise, receiving, possessing or having in custody any game mammals, game
birds or game fish shall maintain accurate records showing the numbers and kind
of such wildlife, the dates received and disposed of, and the names and
addresses of the persons from whom such wildlife were received and to whom such
wildlife were delivered.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-037__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person authorized to enforce the
provisions of this title may enter such facilities at all reasonable hours and
inspect the records, premises and operations.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-037__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The records required to be maintained
must be retained by the person or persons responsible for their preparation and
maintenance for a period of 1 year following the end of the open season on such
wildlife received.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
1367; A1991,
264)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-040">
          <num>503.040</num>
          <heading>Transportation of wildlife or raw furs taken within State.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-040__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in this
section, it is unlawful for any person at any time to transport or offer for
transportation to any place within or outside of this State any game mammal,
raw furs, wild mammal taken by trapping, game bird or game fish taken within
this State.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-040__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person who has legally taken any
game mammal, raw furs, wild mammal taken by trapping, game bird or game fish
within this State may use his or her hunting license, trapping license or
fishing license or tag or stamp, when required, as a permit to transport one
possession limit to points within or outside the State.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-040__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person who legally acquires
ownership or custody of any game mammal, raw furs, wild mammal taken by
trapping, game bird or game fish not taken by the person through hunting,
trapping or fishing may transport such mammal, furs, bird or fish within the
State without a transportation permit if such shipment does not exceed one
possession limit and if such shipment is labeled with the name, address, number
and class of license of the hunter, trapper or angler who legally took such
mammal, furs, bird or fish and date taken, if the mammal, furs, bird or fish is
not required by law or regulation to be tagged. Unless otherwise permitted by a
regulation of the Commission, when tagged shipments are involved, a
transportation permit is required as provided in this section.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-040__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any other person who desires to
transport any game mammal, raw furs, wild mammal taken by trapping, game fish
or game bird to a point within or without the State may do so only under the
authority of a transportation permit as provided in this section.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-040__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department shall designate the form
of the transportation permit and such permits may be issued for a fee of $1 by
any game warden or other such persons as may be specifically designated by the
Department. The person legally in possession of the game mammals, raw furs,
wild mammals taken by trapping, game birds or game fish to be transported must
appear before the issuing agent to obtain a transportation permit. The permit
must describe the wildlife to be transported and identify by name, address,
license number and class the person who legally took the furs or wildlife and
by name and address the person transporting it. Whenever raw furs or wildlife
is to be transported by the postal service or by common carrier, freight or
express agency, such an agency may be designated by name alone.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-040__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Game mammals, raw furs, wild mammals
taken by trapping, game birds or game fish transported to another person shall
be deemed to be in the legal possession of the person making shipment until
actual delivery is made.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-040__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any package or container in which game
birds, raw furs, wild mammals taken by trapping, game mammals or game fish are
being transported by common carrier must have the name and address of the
shipper and of the consignee and an accurate statement of the number and kinds
of game birds, raw furs, wild mammals taken by trapping, game mammals or game
fish contained therein attached to the outside thereof.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-040__subsec_8">
            <num>8.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commission may limit the number of
shipments by any one person in any one season of any kind of game bird, game
mammal or game fish.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [32:101:1947; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 3035.32]—(NRS A1969,
1357;1979,
347;1989,
732;1991,
265;1993,
1671;2003,
1546)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-050">
          <num>503.050</num>
          <heading>Unlawful to waste game bird, mammal, fish or amphibian.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-050__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is unlawful for any person to cause
through carelessness, neglect or otherwise any edible portion of any game bird,
game mammal, game fish or game amphibian to go to waste needlessly.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-050__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is unlawful for any person to
capture or destroy any game mammal, except a carnivore, and detach or remove
from the carcass the head, hide, antlers, horns or tusks only and leave the
carcass to waste.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-050__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the purposes of subsection 1, ï¿½game
birdï¿½ does not include a raven, crow or magpie even if classified as a game
bird pursuant toNRS 501.110.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 87 1/2:101:1947; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 3035.87a]—(NRS A1969,
1358;1971,
1541;1991,
266,334)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-090">
          <num>503.090</num>
          <heading>Unlawful to hunt except during open season.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>It is unlawful to hunt game mammals or game
birds at any time during the year other than during an open season designated
by the Commission pursuant to the provisions of this title.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 62:101:1947; A1949,
292;1951,
494;1953,
667]—(NRS A1963,
66;1969,
1359;1991,
266)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-120">
          <num>503.120</num>
          <heading>Hunting game mammals: Designation of sex, age and physical
characteristics of mammals which may be taken.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-120__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Open seasons as provided pursuant to
this title for game mammals may designate the sex and age class or any obvious
physical characteristic for the mammals which may be taken.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-120__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>With regard to game mammals, the
Commission may adopt regulations defining ï¿½bucks onlyï¿½ and ï¿½antlerlessï¿½
mammals.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [61:101:1947; A1949,
292;1955,
86]—(NRS A1969,
1359;1981,
608;1991,
266)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-135">
          <num>503.135</num>
          <heading>Hunting of migratory waterfowl: Requirement of federal stamp.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Except as otherwise authorized by federal law,
it is unlawful for any person subject to the federal migratory bird hunting
stamp tax to hunt any migratory waterfowl unless at the time of such hunting
the person carries on his or her person an unexpired federal migratory bird
hunting stamp validated by his or her signature written by the person in ink
across the face of the stamp prior to the personï¿½s hunting such birds.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1963,
197; A1969,
1359;2015,
83)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-140">
          <num>503.140</num>
          <heading>Hours of hunting.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-140__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is unlawful for any person to hunt
game mammals or game birds other than at the times of day which are set for
such hunting by the Commission.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-140__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Where no time is set by the Commission,
it is unlawful for any person at any time to hunt game mammals or game birds
except between sunrise and sunset, the same to be considered according to
government time reports.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [68:101:1947; A1949,
292;1955,
86]—(NRS A1969,
1359;1991,
266)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-150">
          <num>503.150</num>
          <heading>Manner of hunting game birds or mammals: Unlawful acts; carrying
of certain handguns lawful during certain seasons.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-150__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Unless otherwise specified by
Commission regulation, it is unlawful to hunt:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-150__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any game bird or game mammal with any gun
capable of firing more than one round with one continuous pull of the trigger,
or with any full steel, full steel core, full metal jacket, tracer or
incendiary bullet or shell, or any shotgun larger than number 10 gauge.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-150__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Big game mammals in any manner other than
with a rifle, held in the hand, that exerts at least 1,000 foot-pounds of
energy at 100 yards, or with a longbow and arrow which meet the specifications
established by Commission regulation.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-150__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Small game mammals in any manner other than
with a handgun, shotgun, rifle, longbow and arrow or by means of falconry.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-150__subsec_1__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Game birds with any rifle or handgun, or in
any manner other than with a shotgun held in the hand, with a longbow and arrow
or by means of falconry.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-150__subsec_1__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Migratory game birds with any shotgun capable
of holding more than three shells.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-150__subsec_1__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any game bird or game mammal with the aid of
any artificial light.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-150__subsec_1__subsec_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any big game mammal, except mountain lions,
with a dog of any breed.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-150__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who is hunting during any
period of an open season during which hunting is restricted to the use of only archery
equipment or a muzzle-loading firearm:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-150__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>May carry for self-defense a handgun that:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="503-150__subsec_2__subsec_a__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Has a barrel length of less than 8
inches; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="503-150__subsec_2__subsec_a__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Does not have a telescopic sight.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-150__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>May not use the handgun carried pursuant to
paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-150__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>to hunt any wildlife.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-150__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Nothing in this section prohibits the
use of dogs in the hunting of game birds or small game mammals.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 2:101:1947; A1949,
292; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 3035.02]—(NRS A1957,
175;1959,
385;1969,
1360;1973,
671;1991,
266;2015,
973)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-165">
          <num>503.165</num>
          <heading>Carrying loaded rifle or shotgun in or on vehicle on or along
public way unlawful; exceptions.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-165__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is unlawful to carry a loaded rifle
or loaded shotgun in or on any vehicle which is standing on or along, or is
being driven on or along, any public highway or any other way open to the
public.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-165__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the purposes of this section:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-165__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A rifle or shotgun is loaded when there is an
unexpended cartridge or shell in the firing chamber, but not when the only
cartridges or shells are in the magazine.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-165__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A muzzle-loading rifle or muzzle-loading
musket is not loaded if the priming compound or element, including, without
limitation, the priming powder or the unfired primer or percussion cap, is
removed from the muzzle-loading rifle or muzzle-loading musket.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-165__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of this section do not
apply to paraplegics, persons with one or both legs amputated or who have
suffered a paralysis of one or both legs which severely impedes walking, or
peace officers and members of the Armed Forces of this State or the United
States while on duty or going to or returning from duty.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
1367; A1971,
1542;1981,
321;1987,
596;2019,
402)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-175">
          <num>503.175</num>
          <heading>Penalty for discharging firearm from or over federal or state
highway or county road.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Unless a
greater penalty is provided inNRS 202.287,
a person who discharges a firearm from, upon, over or across any federal
highway, state highway as described inNRS
408.285, or main or general county road as designated inNRS 403.170, is guilty of a misdemeanor.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
1368; A1979,
1174;1989,
1242)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-185">
          <num>503.185</num>
          <heading>Hunting accident causing injury or death of person or property
damage: Report; revocation of license.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-185__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every person involved in a hunting
accident where damage to property results, or which involves the injury of or
death to another person, shall file a report of the accident with the
Department within 30 days after the accident. The report must be on the form
prescribed by the Department.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-185__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department shall revoke any hunting
license held by a person convicted of violatingNRS 503.165or503.175, if the violation results in an
injury to or the death of another person. The Department shall not issue
another such license to the person sooner than 2 years after the revocation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1987,
596; A1993,
1672;2003,
1547)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-200">
          <num>503.200</num>
          <heading>Competitive field trials for hunting dogs and falconry; use of
upland game birds for trials and training.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-200__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department is empowered to
authorize, under permit and for such fee as may be provided inNRS 502.240, competitive field trials for
hunting dogs or competitive field trials for falconry. The Commission shall
prescribe the rules and regulations to be followed by those in charge of such
trials insofar as conduct of the field trials has any effect or bearing upon
wildlife and the laws of this State respecting closed and open seasons.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-200__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the purpose of permitting such
field trials, the Department may authorize shooting of legally acquired upland
game birds during any closed season on the species of bird or birds to be
hunted.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-200__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>All legally acquired upland game birds
used in a field trial or for the purpose of training hunting dogs and for
falconry training must be banded with legbands by the person in charge of such
field trial or training. Such birds may only be released in an area first
approved by the Department, after which the Department shall authorize, under
permit and under such rules and regulations as the Commission may prescribe,
the releasing of such legally acquired upland game birds for the foregoing
purposes.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-200__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>All birds killed under the provisions
of this section must be accompanied by a receipt, giving the permit number, the
date, the name of the person in possession, and signed by the permit holder.
Birds killed and accompanied by a receipt under the provisions of this section
may be legally possessed.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [88 1/2:101:1947; A1951,
377]—(NRS A1959,
385;1967,
989;1969,
1360;1993,
1672;2003,
1547)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-240">
          <num>503.240</num>
          <heading>Unlawful to hunt, trap or fish upon certain private property
without permission.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-240__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is unlawful for any person to hunt,
fish in nonnavigable waters or trap upon land which is private property where
the person has been warned by the owner or occupant of the property not to
trespass in the manner prescribed inNRS
207.200, or where signs are displayed forbidding hunting, trapping or
fishing without permission obtained from the owner or occupant of the private
property.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-240__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person using that private property
for hunting, fishing or trapping shall comply with the provisions ofNRS 207.220.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 501; RL ï¿½ 6766; NCL ï¿½ 10448] + [1911
C&amp;P ï¿½ 502; RL ï¿½ 6767; NCL ï¿½ 10449]—(NRS A1967,
598;1969,
1361;2005,
1312)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-242">
          <num>503.242</num>
          <heading>Unlawful to hunt alternative livestock.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>It
is unlawful to hunt any alternative livestock reared on or derived from a farm
or other operation that raises alternative livestock.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1993,
431)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-245">
          <num>503.245</num>
          <heading>Limitation on hunting upland game birds by nonresidents.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Hunting by nonresidents of this State for
upland game birds or one or more species of such class may be forbidden or the
number of licenses for such birds issued to nonresidents limited by the
Commission in any county, counties or in any portion of a county.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 50a:101:1947; added1949,
292; A1953,
673]—(NRS A1965,
1178;1969,
1355;1979,
901)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-270">
          <num>503.270</num>
          <heading>Open season; hours of fishing.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-270__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is unlawful for any person to fish
in or from any of the waters of the State of Nevada except during the open
season as designated by the Commission under the provisions of this title.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-270__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commission may by regulation allow
fishing for any species of fish during any hour of the day or night.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [38:101:1947; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 3035.38]—(NRS A1961,
116;1969,
1361)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-290">
          <num>503.290</num>
          <heading>Manner and means of fishing; authorized use of not more than two
combinations of hook, line and rod; taking frogs.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-290__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 2, it is unlawful for any person to fish in or from any of the
waters of the State of Nevada for any fish of any species in any manner other
than with hook and line attached to a rod or reel closely attended in the
manner known as angling. Not more than two combinations of hook, line and rod
may be used by one person at any time.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-290__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commission may by regulation
authorize other methods for taking fish. Frogs may be taken by spear, bow and
arrow, hook and line or by other methods authorized by the Commissionï¿½s
regulation.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-290__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the purposes of this section,
ï¿½hookï¿½ includes not more than three baited hooks, not more than three fly hooks
or not more than two plugs or similar lures. No more than two such plugs or
lures, irrespective of the number of hooks or attractor blades attached
thereto, may be attached to the line.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 45:101:1947; A1949,
125;1953,
667]—(NRS A1957,
175;1959,
386;1969,
1362;1983,
853;1995,
82;2003,
1547,2550;2017,
3638)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-300">
          <num>503.300</num>
          <heading>Regulations of Commission: Types and use of bait; chumming.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-300__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commission may prescribe by
regulation the types of bait and methods by which it may or may not be used in
any designated water. It is unlawful for any person to use any bait prohibited
by regulation.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-300__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commission may by regulation control
the practice known as chumming.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 45:101:1947; A1949,
125;1953,
667]—(NRS A1969,
1362)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-310">
          <num>503.310</num>
          <heading>Live bait: Authority of Commission; permit required for sale.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-310__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commission may regulate or prohibit
the use of live bait in fishing so that no undesirable species are introduced
into the public waters of this State.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-310__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person engaged in the sale of live
bait must first obtain a permit from the Department for the fee provided inNRS 502.240. The permit may be revoked for
any violation of regulations.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-310__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commission may prescribe the
species which may be held or sold by the permittee.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 43:101:1947; A1949,
292;1951,
494]—(NRS A1961,
113;1969,
1362;1987,
562;1993,
1673;2003,
1548)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-360">
          <num>503.360</num>
          <heading>Unlawful fishing from hatcheries.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-360__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is unlawful for any person at any
time to fish from any state hatchery, or from any waters set aside or used for
the purpose of rearing or growing fish for transplanting by the State.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-360__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Nothing in this section prohibits
employees of the Department from handling, at any time, all such fish, as may
be required in the propagation, care and distribution of the fish.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [41:101:1947; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 3035.41]—(NRS A1969,
1363;1981,
543;1993,
1673;2003,
1548)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-380">
          <num>503.380</num>
          <heading>Commercial taking of unprotected wildlife.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The Department may take or permit the
commercial taking of unprotected wildlife in any manner approved by the
Commission. The Commission may fix a price to be paid for wildlife so taken.
Unprotected wildlife taken under this authorization may be sold.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 44:101:1947; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 3035.44]—(NRS A1969,
1363;1987,
562;1993,
1673;2003,
1548)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-400">
          <num>503.400</num>
          <heading>Fishways and fish ladders: Construction and maintenance;
penalty.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-400__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every person who has erected, or who
may hereafter erect, any dams, water weirs or other obstructions to the free
passage of fish in the rivers, streams, lakes or other waters of the State of
Nevada shall construct and keep in repair, to the satisfaction of the
Department, fishways or fish ladders at all such dams, water weirs or other
obstructions so that at all seasons of the year fish may ascend above such
dams, water weirs or other obstructions to deposit their spawn.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-400__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every person so placing, controlling or
owning any such obstruction who fails to comply with the provisions of this
section after having been notified in writing so to do by the Department, and
every person who at any time willfully or knowingly destroys, injures or
obstructs any fishway or fish ladder which is required by law is guilty of a
misdemeanor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [29:101:1947; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 3035.29]—(NRS A1969,
1363;1993,
1673;2003,
1548)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-410">
          <num>503.410</num>
          <heading>Unlawful interference with flow of water through fish ladder.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-410__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>It shall be unlawful for any person to
dry up, impede or interfere with the free flow of water through any fish ladder
upon any stream in this State, when there is sufficient unappropriated or
unused water in such stream for use therein, by diverting the same from above
and around such fish ladder by means of any ditch, canal or aqueduct, and
permitting the same to waste, spill or flow back into the stream below such
fish ladder by means of a spillway, tailrace, overflow, underpass, headgate or
other appliance not equipped with an efficient and adequate fish ladder.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-410__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>This section shall not be construed to
impair any subsisting right to divert water from such stream for irrigation,
domestic or culinary purposes.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [31:101:1947; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 3035.31]</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-420">
          <num>503.420</num>
          <heading>Fish screens: Installation and maintenance; unlawful acts.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-420__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person, firm or corporation owning
in whole or in part any canal, ditch or any artificial watercourse, taking or
receiving its waters from any river, creek or lake in which fish have been
placed or may exist, shall place or cause to be placed, and such persons shall
maintain at the intake or inlet of such canal, ditch or watercourse, a grating,
screen or other device, either stationary or operated mechanically, of such
construction, fineness, strength and quality as may be designated by the Department,
to prevent any fish from entering such canal, ditch or watercourse.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-420__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If such person, firm or corporation,
after due notice from the Department, fails to install or maintain such
grating, screen or device, the Commission is authorized to enter upon lands
adjacent to the inlet of such canal, ditch or watercourse, and may install
therein, and thereafter maintain, such grating, screen or device as in the
discretion of the Department is proper.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-420__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is unlawful for any person or
persons, except a game warden, to remove, tamper with, destroy or in any way
molest such screens when the same have been installed.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [30:101:1947; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 3035.30]—(NRS A1969,
1363;1993,
1673;2003,
1549)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-425">
          <num>503.425</num>
          <heading>Dredging operations: Permits; unlawful acts.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-425__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Before a person may use any vacuum or
suction dredge equipment in any river, stream or lake of this State, the person
must submit an application to the Department. The application must be
accompanied by a fee of $15 and must specify the type and size of equipment to
be used and its location. If the Department determines that the operations will
not be deleterious to fish, it shall issue a permit to the applicant.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-425__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A permit issued pursuant to subsection
1 does not authorize the recipient to use any equipment in any navigable body
of water unless the recipient has obtained the appropriate permit for such a
use from the State Land Registrar.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-425__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is unlawful for any person to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-425__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Conduct dredging operations without securing
a permit pursuant to subsection 1;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-425__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Operate any equipment other than that
specified in the permit; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-425__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Conduct a dredging operation outside the area
designated on the permit.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
1368; A1981,
357;1993,
1459,1674;1995,
579;2003,
1549,2551)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-430">
          <num>503.430</num>
          <heading>Water pollution: Deposit of substance deleterious to fish or
wildlife; penalties.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Except as
otherwise provided inNRS 445A.615or
unless a greater penalty is prescribed byNRS
459.600, every person who places or allows to pass, or who places where it
can pass or fall, into or upon any of the waters of this State at any time, any
lime, gas tar, slag, acids or other chemical, sawdust, shavings, slabs,
edgings, mill or factory refuse, sewage, garbage or any substance deleterious
to fish or wildlife is guilty of a misdemeanor for the first offense and a
gross misdemeanor for any subsequent offense.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [28:101:1947; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 3035.28]—(NRS A1957,
176;1987,
562;1989,
1269;1991,
830)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-440">
          <num>503.440</num>
          <heading>Open season for fur-bearing mammals.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-440__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided inNRS 503.470, it is unlawful to trap or kill
fur-bearing mammals at any time during the year other than during an open
season as designated by the Commission pursuant to the provisions of this
title.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-440__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commission, in its sole discretion,
may set the open season for fur-bearing mammals.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [73:101:1947; A1949,
292; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 3035.73]—(NRS A1969,
1364;1991,
267)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-450">
          <num>503.450</num>
          <heading>Manner of hunting fur-bearing mammals.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>It
is unlawful for any person at any time to hunt any fur-bearing mammal in any
manner other than by trap, gun or bow and arrow.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 74:101:1947; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 3035.74]—(NRS A1983,
854;1991,
267)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-452">
          <num>503.452</num>
          <heading>Registration or stamping of certain information on traps, snares
and similar devices; fee for registration; exceptions; unlawful possession of
trap registered to another person without written permission; confidentiality
of registration information.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-452__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsections 2 and 3, each trap, snare or similar device used by a person in the
taking of wild mammals must be registered with the Department before it is
used. Each registered trap, snare or similar device must bear a number which is
assigned by the Department and is clearly stamped on the trap, snare or similar
device or on a metal tag that is attached to the trap, snare or similar device.
The registration of a trap, snare or similar device is valid until the trap,
snare or similar device is sold or ownership of the trap, snare or similar
device is otherwise transferred. For each trap, snare or similar device
registered with the Department, the person registering the trap, snare or
similar device must pay a registration fee of $5.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-452__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 3, if a trap, snare or similar device is not registered with the
Department pursuant to subsection 1, before it can be used in the taking of
wild animals, it must have the name and address of the person who owns the
trap, snare or similar device:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-452__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Clearly stamped upon the trap, snare or
similar device; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-452__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>On a metal tag that is attached to the trap,
snare or similar device.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-452__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of subsections 1 and 2
do not apply to a trap, snare or similar device used:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-452__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Exclusively on private property which is
posted or fenced in accordance with the provisions ofNRS 207.200by the owner or occupant of the
property or with the permission of the owner or occupant;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-452__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For the control of rodents by an institution
of the Nevada System of Higher Education;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-452__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>By any federal, state or local governmental
agency; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-452__subsec_3__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For the taking of wild mammals for scientific
or educational purposes under a permit issued by the Department pursuant toNRS 503.650.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-452__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is unlawful:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-452__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For a person to whom a trap, snare or similar
device is registered to allow another person to possess or use the trap, snare
or similar device without providing to that person written authorization to
possess or use the trap, snare or similar device.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-452__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For a person to possess or use a trap, snare
or similar device registered to another person without obtaining the written
authorization required pursuant to paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-452__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>. If a person obtains written
authorization to possess or use a trap, snare or similar device pursuant to
paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-452__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>, the person shall ensure that the written authorization, together
with his or her trapping license, is in his or her possession during any period
in which he or she uses the trap, snare or similar device to take fur-bearing
mammals.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-452__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person to whom a trap, snare or
similar device is registered pursuant to this section shall report any theft of
the trap, snare or similar device to the Department as soon as it is practical
to do so after the person discovers the theft.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-452__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any information in the possession of
the Department concerning the registration of a trap, snare or similar device
is confidential and the Department shall not disclose that information unless
required to do so by law or court order.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-452__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a trap, snare or similar device has
been used exclusively on private property pursuant to paragraph</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-452__subsec_7__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of
subsection 3, before the trap, snare or similar device is used on any public
land in this State, the owner of the trap, snare or similar device must:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-452__subsec_7__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Register the trap, snare or similar device
pursuant to subsection 1; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-452__subsec_7__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Pursuant to subsection 2, have his or her
name and address:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="503-452__subsec_7__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Clearly stamped on the trap, snare or
similar device; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="503-452__subsec_7__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>On a metal tag that is attached to the
trap, snare or similar device.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1979,
346; A1983,
854;1991,
267;1993,
1674;1995,
898;2003,
1549,2551;2013,
1001;2015,
3062;2017,
2000)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-454">
          <num>503.454</num>
          <heading>Trapping license required; unlawful to remove or disturb trap,
snare or similar device of licensee; exceptions.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-454__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every person who takes fur-bearing
mammals by trap, snare or similar device or unprotected mammals by trapping or
sells raw furs for profit shall procure a trapping license.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-454__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 3, it is unlawful to remove or disturb the trap, snare or similar
device of any holder of a trapping license while the trap, snare or similar
device is being legally used by the holder on public land or on land where the
holder has permission to trap.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-454__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person may:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-454__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Remove or disturb a trap, snare or similar
device if the trap, snare or similar device creates an immediate risk of
physical injury or death to any person or animal accompanying a person.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-454__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Release any person or animal accompanying a
person from a trap, snare or similar device in which the person or animal is
caught.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1979,
347; A1983,
854;1991,
267,1575;2013,
1002;2017,
2001)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-456">
          <num>503.456</num>
          <heading>Development and posting of warning signs for trapping.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-456__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each state agency which manages any
public land in this State in which trapping may occur shall ensure that each
sign for which the Department develops standard language pursuant to subsection
2 includes that language and is posted:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-456__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>At each visitor center, kiosk, trailhead or
other location specified by the Department; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-456__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In a place in which the sign is readily
observable by members of the public at the visitor center, kiosk, trailhead or
other location.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-456__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department shall:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-456__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Develop standard language for inclusion in
any sign that is used to warn a person that trapping may occur in any area in
this State; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-456__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Develop the standard language specified in
paragraph</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-456__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>in cooperation with each federal or state agency which manages
any public land in this State in which trapping may occur.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2017,
1999)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-470">
          <num>503.470</num>
          <heading>Control of fur-bearing mammals doing damage.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-470__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Fur-bearing mammals injuring any
property may be taken or killed at any time in any manner by the owner or
occupant of the property or with the permission of the owner or occupant.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-470__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>When the Department has determined from
investigations or upon a petition signed by the owners of 25 percent of the
land area in any irrigation district or the area served by a ditch company
alleging that an excessive population of beaver or otter exists or that beaver
or otter are doing damage to lands, streams, ditches, roads or water control
structures, the Department shall remove such excess or depredating beaver or
otter.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 75:101:1947; R1953,
671; added1953,
671]—(NRS A1967,
1201;1969,
1364;1991,
267;1993,
1674;2003,
1549;2015,
3063)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-540">
          <num>503.540</num>
          <heading>Authority of Department to enter land and remove beaver or
otter.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever the Department
determines that beaver or otter are doing damage and that it will be necessary
to remove beaver or otter from the land of a person to protect the lands of
another landowner, the Department is not prevented from taking such beaver or
otter by the refusal of the landowner to allow the employees of the Department
to enter upon the land of the landowner. The Department is authorized to enter
upon the lands of such owner and remove beaver or otter for the relief of other
landowners and the protection of the public welfare.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 75:101:1947; R1953,
671; added1953,
671]—(NRS A1969,
1365;1993,
1674;2003,
1550)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-570">
          <num>503.570</num>
          <heading>Minimum visitation of traps, snares and similar devices; removal
of animals; regulations.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-570__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person taking or causing to be taken
wild mammals by means of traps, snares or similar devices shall, if the traps,
snares or similar devices are placed or set to take mammals, visit or cause to
be visited each trap, snare or similar device at a frequency specified in
regulations adopted by the Commission pursuant to subsection 3 during all of
the time the trap, snare or similar device is placed, set or used to take wild
mammals, and remove therefrom any animals caught therein.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-570__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of subsection 1 do not
apply to employees of the State Department of Agriculture or the United States
Department of Agriculture when acting in their official capacities.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-570__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commission shall adopt regulations
setting forth the frequency at which a person who takes or causes to be taken
wild mammals by means of traps, snares or similar devices must visit a trap,
snare or similar device. The regulations must require the person to visit a
trap, snare or similar device at least once each 96 hours. In adopting the
regulations, the Commission shall consider requiring a trap, snare or similar
device placed in close proximity to a populated or heavily used area by persons
to be visited more frequently than a trap, snare or similar device which is not
placed in close proximity to such an area.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1:107:1937; 1931 NCL ï¿½ 3153.01] + [2:107:1937; 1931
NCL ï¿½ 3153.02]—(NRS A1967,
599;1969,
1365;1979,
348;1981,
608;1991,
268,334;1993,
1674;1999,
3626;2013,
1002;2017,
2002)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-575">
          <num>503.575</num>
          <heading>Sale of live beaver by Department.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The
Department, with the approval of the Commission, may sell live beaver.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 75:101:1947; R1953,
671; added1953,
671]—(NRS A1969,
1365;1993,
1675;2003,
1550)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-580">
          <num>503.580</num>
          <heading>Unlawful to set trap, snare or similar device within 200 feet of
public road or highway; exception.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-580__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the purposes of this section,
ï¿½public road or highwayï¿½ means:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-580__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A highway designated as a United States
highway.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-580__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A highway designated as a state highway
pursuant to the provisions ofNRS 408.285.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-580__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A main or general county road as defined byNRS 403.170.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-580__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is unlawful for any person, company
or corporation to place or set any trap, snare or similar device used for the
purpose of trapping mammals within 200 feet of any public road or highway
within this State.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-580__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>This section does not:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-580__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Prevent the placing or setting of any trap, snare
or similar device inside, along or near a fence which may be situated less than
200 feet from any public road or highway upon privately owned lands.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-580__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Apply to placing or setting a trap, snare or
similar device by an employee or agent of the Department.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1:155:1931] + [2:155:1931]—(NRS A1960,
229;1967,
599;1969,
1365;1979,
1175;1991,
268;2017,
2002;2019,
763)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-582">
          <num>503.582</num>
          <heading>Permit required to hunt, trap, possess or sell birds of prey or
parts thereof; regulations.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-582__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Covering the hunting, trapping, possession
or sale of any of those species.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-582__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Authorizing a person to hunt, trap,
possess or sell any of those species without obtaining a permit pursuant to the
provisions of this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
774; A1971,
1542;1993,
1675;1995,
118;2003,
1550)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-583">
          <num>503.583</num>
          <heading>Falconry license for practicing falconry or training birds of
prey: Requirement; fee; limit; banding; limitations on capture and killing;
exception in regulations.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-583__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in this
section, any person who practices falconry or trains birds of prey must obtain
a falconry license from the Department upon payment of a license fee as
provided inNRS 502.240.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-583__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The licensee, under permit, may obtain
from the wild only two birds per year. All such birds of prey must be banded in
accordance with regulations adopted by the Commission.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-583__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Birds of prey may not be taken,
captured or disturbed during the months in which they breed.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-583__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>This section does not prohibit the
capture or killing of a hawk or an owl by holders of scientific collecting
permits.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-583__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commission may adopt regulations
authorizing a person to practice falconry or train birds of prey without
obtaining a falconry license pursuant to the provisions of subsection 1.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
774; A1969,
1376;1971,
1542;1981,
608;1993,
1675;1995,
118;2003,
1550)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-5831">
          <num>503.5831</num>
          <heading>Development and implementation of process to petition Department
for determination whether a personï¿½s criminal history will disqualify the
person from obtaining falconry license; imposition and waiver of fees;
quarterly reports.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-5831__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department shall develop and
implement a process by which a person with a criminal history may petition the
Department to review the criminal history of the person to determine if the
personï¿½s criminal history will disqualify the person from obtaining a falconry
license pursuant toNRS 503.583.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-5831__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Not later than 90 days after a petition
is submitted to the Department pursuant to subsection 1, the Department shall
inform the person of the determination of the Department of whether the
personï¿½s criminal history will disqualify the person from obtaining a falconry
license. The Department is not bound by its determination of disqualification
or qualification and may rescind such a determination at any time.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-5831__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department may provide instructions
to a person who receives a determination of disqualification to remedy the
determination of disqualification. A person may resubmit a petition pursuant to
subsection 1 not earlier than 6 months after receiving instructions pursuant to
this subsection if the person remedies the determination of disqualification.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-5831__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person with a criminal history may
petition the Department at any time, including, without limitation, before
obtaining any education or paying any fee required to obtain a falconry license
from the Department.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-5831__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person may submit a new petition to
the Department not earlier than 2 years after the final determination of the
initial petition submitted to the Department.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-5831__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department may impose a fee of up
to $50 upon the person to fund the administrative costs in complying with the
provisions of this section. The Department may waive such fees or allow such
fees to be covered by funds from a scholarship or grant.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-5831__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department may post on its Internet
website:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-5831__subsec_7__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The requirements to obtain a falconry license
from the Department; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-5831__subsec_7__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A list of crimes, if any, that would
disqualify a person from obtaining a falconry license from the Department.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-5831__subsec_8">
            <num>8.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department may request the criminal
history record of a person who petitions the Department for a determination
pursuant to subsection 1. To the extent consistent with federal law, if the
Department makes such a request of a person, the Department shall require the
person to submit his or her criminal history record which includes a report
from:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-5831__subsec_8__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Central Repository for Nevada Records of
Criminal History; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-5831__subsec_8__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Federal Bureau of Investigation.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-5831__subsec_9">
            <num>9.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who petitions the Department
for a determination pursuant to subsection 1 shall not submit false or
misleading information to the Department.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-5831__subsec_10">
            <num>10.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department shall, on or before the
20th day of January, April, July and October, submit to the Director of the
Legislative Counsel Bureau in an electronic format prescribed by the Director,
a report that includes:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-5831__subsec_10__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The number of petitions submitted to the
Department pursuant to subsection 1;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-5831__subsec_10__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The number of determinations of
disqualification made by the Department pursuant to subsection 1;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-5831__subsec_10__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The reasons for such determinations; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-5831__subsec_10__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any other information that is requested by
the Director or which the Department determines would be helpful.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-5831__subsec_11">
            <num>11.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Director shall transmit a
compilation of the information received pursuant to subsection 10 to the
Legislative Commission quarterly, unless otherwise directed by the Commission.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2019,
2938)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-5833">
          <num>503.5833</num>
          <heading>Submission of certain information regarding holder of permit or
license to Division of Welfare and Supportive Services of Department of Health
and Human Services. [Effective until the date of the repeal of 42 U.S.C. ï¿½ 666,
the federal law requiring each state to establish procedures for withholding,
suspending and restricting the professional, occupational and recreational
licenses for child support arrearages and for noncompliance with certain
processes relating to paternity or child support proceedings.]</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The Department shall, upon request of the
Division of Welfare and Supportive Services of the Department of Health and
Human Services, submit to the Division of Welfare and Supportive Services the
name, address and social security number of each person who holds a permit or
license issued pursuant toNRS 503.582or503.583and any pertinent changes in
that information.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1997,
2086; A2003,
1550;2019,
391)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-5835">
          <num>503.5835</num>
          <heading>Suspension of permit or license for failure to pay child support
or comply with certain subpoenas or warrants; reinstatement of permit or
license. [Effective until the date of the repeal of 42 U.S.C. ï¿½ 666, the
federal law requiring each state to establish procedures for withholding,
suspending and restricting the professional, occupational and recreational
licenses for child support arrearages and for noncompliance with certain
processes relating to paternity or child support proceedings.]</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-5835__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the Department receives a report issued
pursuant toNRS 425.510that provides
for the suspension of all recreational licenses and permits issued to a person
who is the holder of a permit or license issued pursuant toNRS 503.582or503.583, the Department shall deem the
permit or license issued to that person to be suspended at the end of the 30th
day after the date on which the report was issued unless the Department
receives notice from the district attorney or other public agency pursuant toNRS 425.510stating that the holder of the
permit or license has complied with the subpoena or warrant or has satisfied
the arrearage pursuant toNRS 425.560.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-5835__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department shall reinstate a permit
or license issued pursuant toNRS 503.582or503.583that has been suspended by a
district court pursuant toNRS 425.510if
the Department receives a notice issued by the district attorney or other
public agency pursuant toNRS 425.510stating
that the person whose permit or license was suspended has complied with the subpoena
or warrant or has satisfied the arrearage pursuant toNRS 425.560.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1997,
2086; A2003,
1550;2019,
391)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-584">
          <num>503.584</num>
          <heading>Legislative finding; conservation, protection and propagation of
selected species.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-584__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Legislature finds that:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-584__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The economic growth of the State of Nevada
has been attended with some serious and unfortunate consequences. Nevada has
experienced the extermination or extirpation of some of the Stateï¿½s native
species of animals, including fish and vertebrate wildlife. Serious losses have
occurred and are occurring in other species of native wild animals with
important economic, educational, historical, political, recreational,
scientific and aesthetic values.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-584__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The people of the State of Nevada have an
obligation to conserve and protect the various species of native fish and
wildlife that are threatened with extinction.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-584__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The purpose ofNRS 503.584to503.589, inclusive, is to provide a program
for the:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-584__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Conservation, protection, restoration and
propagation of selected species of native fish and other vertebrate wildlife,
including migratory birds; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-584__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Perpetuation of the populations and habitats
of such species.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
773)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-585">
          <num>503.585</num>
          <heading>Placement of animal threatened with extinction on list of fully
protected species; special permit for capture, removal or destruction.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>A species or subspecies of native fish,
wildlife and other fauna must be regarded as threatened with extinction when
the Commission, after consultation with competent authorities, determines that
its existence is endangered and its survival requires assistance because of
overexploitation, disease or other factors or its habitat is threatened with
destruction, drastic modification or severe curtailment. Any animal so declared
to be threatened with extinction must be placed on the list of fully protected
species, and no member of its kind may be captured, removed or destroyed at any
time by any means except under special permit issued by the Department.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
774; A1969,
1376;1993,
1675;2003,
1551)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-586">
          <num>503.586</num>
          <heading>Translocation or destruction of endangered species found to be
destructive.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Where any bird,
mammal or other wildlife which is declared to be in danger of extinction
pursuant toNRS 503.585is found to be
destructive of domestic animals or fowl or a menace to health, the Department
may provide for its destruction or its removal, alive, for translocating.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
774; A1969,
1376;1993,
1675;2003,
1551)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-587">
          <num>503.587</num>
          <heading>Duties of Commission.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The
Commission shall use its authority to manage land to carry out a program for
conserving, protecting, restoring and propagating selected species of native
fish, wildlife and other vertebrates and their habitats which are threatened
with extinction and destruction.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
774; A1979,
901)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-588">
          <num>503.588</num>
          <heading>Duties of Governor.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>The
Governor shall review the programs which the Governor administers and, to the
extent practicable, utilize such programs in furtherance of the purpose ofNRS 503.584to503.589, inclusive, and shall encourage
other state and federal agencies to use their authorities in such a manner.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
774)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-589">
          <num>503.589</num>
          <heading>Powers and duties of Director.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>In
carrying out the program authorized byNRS
503.584to503.589, inclusive, the
Director shall cooperate, to the maximum extent practicable, with other states
and with the counties in the State of Nevada, and the Director may enter into
agreements with such other states and counties and with other legal entities
for the administration and management of any area established pursuant toNRS 503.584to503.589, inclusive, for the conservation,
protection, restoration and propagation of species of native fish, wildlife and
other fauna which are threatened with extinction.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1969,
774; A1993,
1676;2003,
1551)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-590">
          <num>503.590</num>
          <heading>Noncommercial collections of live wildlife; regulations
concerning fencing or containment of collections of wildlife; provisions
inapplicable to alternative livestock.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-590__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in this
section, a person may maintain a noncommercial collection of legally obtained
live wildlife if:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-590__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Such a collection is not maintained for
public display nor as a part of or adjunct to any commercial establishment; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-590__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The wildlife contained in such a collection
is of a species which may be possessed in accordance with regulations adopted
by the Commission pursuant to subsection 2 ofNRS
504.295.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-590__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commission may adopt reasonable
regulations establishing minimum standards for the fencing or containment of
any collection of wildlife.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-590__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of this section do not
apply to alternative livestock and products made therefrom.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1:72:1947; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 3154.05] + [2:72:1947; 1943
NCL ï¿½ 3154.06] + [3:72:1947; A1955,
196] + [4:72:1947; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 3154.08]—(NRS A1959,
387;1967,
1126;1969,
1366,1453;1971,
1187;1981,
609;1993,
431)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-595">
          <num>503.595</num>
          <heading>Prevention or alleviation of damage caused by wildlife.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>After the owner or tenant of any land or
property has made a report to the Department indicating that such land or
property is being damaged or destroyed, or is in danger of being damaged or
destroyed, by wildlife, the Department may, after thorough investigation and
pursuant to such regulations as the Commission may promulgate, cause such action
to be taken as it may deem necessary, desirable and practical to prevent or
alleviate such damage or threatened damage to such land or property.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [8.5:101:1947; added1955,
73]—(NRS A1969,
1551;1971,
1542;1973,
287;1993,
1676;2003,
1551)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-597">
          <num>503.597</num>
          <heading>Introduction or removal of aquatic life or wildlife: Approval
required; investigation; regulations; penalties.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-597__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in this
section, it is unlawful, except by the written consent and approval of the
Department, for any person at any time to receive, bring or have brought or
shipped into this State, or remove from one stream or body of water in this
State to any other, or from one portion of the State to any other, or to any
other state, any aquatic life or wildlife, or any spawn, eggs or young of any
of them.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-597__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department shall require an
applicant to conduct an investigation to confirm that such an introduction or
removal will not be detrimental to the wildlife or the habitat of wildlife in
this State. Written consent and approval of the Department may be given only if
the results of the investigation prove that the introduction, removal or
importation will not be detrimental to existing aquatic life or wildlife, or
any spawn, eggs or young of any of them.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-597__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commission may through appropriate
regulation provide for the inspection of such introduced or removed creatures
and the inspection fees therefor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-597__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commission may adopt regulations to
prohibit the importation, transportation or possession of any species of
wildlife which the Commission deems to be detrimental to the wildlife or the
habitat of the wildlife in this State.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-597__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person who knowingly or intentionally
introduces, causes to be introduced or attempts to introduce an aquatic
invasive species or injurious aquatic species into any waters of this State is
guilty of:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-597__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For a first offense, a misdemeanor; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-597__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For any subsequent offense, a category E
felony and shall be punished as provided inNRS
193.130.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-597__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A court before whom a defendant is
convicted of a violation of subsection 5 shall, for each violation, order the
defendant to pay a civil penalty of at least $25,000 but not more than
$250,000. The money must be deposited into the Wildlife Account in the State
General Fund and used to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-597__subsec_6__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Remove the aquatic invasive species or
injurious aquatic species;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-597__subsec_6__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Reintroduce any game fish or other aquatic
wildlife destroyed by the aquatic invasive species or injurious aquatic
species;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-597__subsec_6__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Restore any habitat destroyed by the aquatic
invasive species or injurious aquatic species;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-597__subsec_6__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Repair any other damage done to the waters of
this State by the introduction of the aquatic invasive species or injurious
aquatic species; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-597__subsec_6__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Defray any other costs incurred by the
Department because of the introduction of the aquatic invasive species or
injurious aquatic species.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-597__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of this section do not
apply to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-597__subsec_7__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Alternative livestock and products made
therefrom; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-597__subsec_7__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The introduction of any species by the
Department for sport fishing or other wildlife management programs.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-597__subsec_8">
            <num>8.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-597__subsec_8__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Aquatic invasive speciesï¿½ means an aquatic
species which is exotic or not native to this State and which the Commission
has determined to be detrimental to aquatic life, water resources or
infrastructure for providing water in this State.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-597__subsec_8__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Injurious aquatic speciesï¿½ means an aquatic
species which the Commission has determined to be a threat to sensitive,
threatened or endangered aquatic species or game fish or to the habitat of
sensitive, threatened or endangered aquatic species or game fish by any means,
including, without limitation:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="503-597__subsec_8__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Predation;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="503-597__subsec_8__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Parasitism;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="503-597__subsec_8__subsec_b__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Interbreeding; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="503-597__subsec_8__subsec_b__subsec_4">
                <num>(4)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The transmission of disease.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 43:101:1947; A1949,
292;1951,
494]—(NRS A1957,
175;1969,
1358;1993,
431,1676;1995,
514;2003,
1552;2011,
2401;2015,
100)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-610">
          <num>503.610</num>
          <heading>Protection of bald eagle and golden eagle; possession of golden
eagles in certain circumstances; authority for Commission to authorize
transportation, transfer, possession or use of golden eagles in falconry;
regulations.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-610__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in this
section, it is unlawful for any person, firm, company, corporation or
association to kill, destroy, wound, trap, injure, possess dead or alive, or in
any other manner to catch, capture, take or remove from the wild, or to pursue
with such intent, the birds known as the bald eagle and the golden eagle, or to
take or remove from the wild, injure, possess or destroy the nests, eggs or
newly hatched offspring of such birds.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-610__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department may issue permits to
take bald eagles or golden eagles whenever it determines that they have become
seriously injurious to wildlife or agricultural or other interests in any
particular area of the State and the injury complained of is substantial and
can only be abated by taking some or all of the offending birds. The issuance
of such permits must be consistent with federal law.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-610__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Department may authorize a person
who is licensed as a master falconer by the Department pursuant toNRS 503.583and who meets the conditions
set forth in 50 C.F.R. ï¿½ 21.29 to possess a golden eagle that is obtained from
the wild if the golden eagle:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-610__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Is obtained for the rehabilitation of the
golden eagle in accordance with federal law;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-610__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Is obtained in another state in accordance
with federal law, including, without limitation, the federal depredation permit
lottery system, and the laws of that state;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-610__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Is legally possessed by a master falconer in
another state and that master falconer moves to this State; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-610__subsec_3__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Is transferred to the master falconer from
another falconer who is licensed in this State or another state. Such a
transfer may only occur if it is authorized by the Department in the manner set
forth in any regulations adopted by the Commission pursuant to subsection 6, if
applicable.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-610__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the Commission adopts regulations
pursuant to paragraph</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-610__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>of subsection 6 and authorizes the transportation,
transfer, possession or use of a golden eagle in falconry, the Department shall
require a person who possesses a golden eagle pursuant to subsection 3 to
obtain an eagle permit from the Department.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-610__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The eagle permit obtained pursuant to
subsection 4:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-610__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Is deemed to be a permit to possess a golden
eagle for the purposes of 50 C.F.R. ï¿½ 22.24; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-610__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Authorizes the holder to lawfully transport,
transfer, possess or use a golden eagle in falconry in the manner set forth in
the eagle permit that is issued by the Department.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-610__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commission:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="503-610__subsec_6__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>May adopt regulations that authorize a person
who possesses a golden eagle pursuant to subsection 3 to transport, transfer,
possess or use the golden eagle in falconry; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-610__subsec_6__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Shall adopt regulations that establish:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="503-610__subsec_6__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If the Commission adopts regulations
pursuant to paragraph</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="503-610__subsec_6__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (I) The requirements that a person
who possesses a golden eagle pursuant to subsection 3 must comply with to
obtain an eagle permit from the Department; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (II) How the holder of an eagle
permit may transport, transfer, possess or use a golden eagle; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="503-610__subsec_6__subsec_a__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Civil penalties to be imposed against
any person, firm, company, corporation or association who violates subsection
1.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [66:101:1947; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 3035.66] + [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½
546; RL ï¿½ 6811; NCL ï¿½ 10492]—(NRS A1963,
1277;1969,
1366;1993,
1676;2003,
1552;2021,
1085)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-620">
          <num>503.620</num>
          <heading>Protection of birds included in Migratory Bird Treaty Act.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Except as otherwise provided by this title or
a regulation adopted pursuant thereto, it is unlawful for any person to hunt or
take any dead or alive birds, nests of birds or eggs of birds protected by that
certain Act of Congress commonly known and referred to as the Migratory Bird
Treaty Act of July 3, 1918, as amended, 16 U.S.C. ï¿½ï¿½ 703 et seq., or protected
by a regulation of the Commission.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [67:101:1947; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 3035.67] + [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½
547; RL ï¿½ 6812; NCL ï¿½ 10493]—(NRS A1969,
1367;2005,
1312)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-631">
          <num>503.631</num>
          <heading>Dogs running at large: Unlawful to permit tracking, harassing or
killing of big game mammal.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-631__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided inNRS 503.150, it is unlawful for the owner
of any dog to permit such dog to run at large if such dog is actively tracking,
pursuing, harassing, attacking or killing any big game mammal within this
State.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-631__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any such dog running at large may be
destroyed by any peace officer without criminal or civil liability therefor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1973,
845; A1991,
268)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-636">
          <num>503.636</num>
          <heading>Dogs running at large: Unlawful to permit tracking, harassing or
killing of wildlife in state-owned area for management of wildlife.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-636__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is unlawful for the owner of any dog
to permit such dog to run at large if such dog is actively tracking, pursuing,
harassing, attacking or killing any wildlife in a state-owned wildlife
management area, as provided inNRS 504.143.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-636__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any such dog running at large may be
destroyed by any peace officer, without criminal or civil liability therefor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1973,
845)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-650">
          <num>503.650</num>
          <heading>Collection or shipping of wildlife for scientific or educational
purposes; fee for permit.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-650__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Prohibits any person, upon the written
permit of the Department, from taking, killing, possessing or banding any
species of wildlife, or collecting the nest or eggs thereof, for strictly
scientific or educational purposes, the number and species of wildlife to be
limited by the Department.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-650__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Prevents shipping into any other county
or state, under a written permit issued by the Department, any wildlife for
scientific or educational purposes.
ï¿½The amount
of the fee for a permit to collect wildlife for scientific or educational
purposes is $50.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [72:101:1947; 1943 NCL ï¿½ 3035.72]—(NRS A1969,
1367;1971,
1543;1981,
357,609;1991,
268;1993,
1676;2003,
1552,2551)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-655">
          <num>503.655</num>
          <heading>Shed antlers: Regulations.</heading>
          <subsection eId="503-655__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The Commission shall adopt regulations
for the taking of shed antlers.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="503-655__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section, ï¿½shed antlersï¿½
means antlers which have been naturally shed by any big game mammal in this
State.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2011,
1347)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_503-660">
          <num>503.660</num>
          <heading>Unlawful manner of camping near water hole.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>It is unlawful for any person to camp within
100 yards of a water hole in such a manner that wildlife or domestic stock will
be denied access to such water hole.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1975,
1453)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>