<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="NRS">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#arch">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-476"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-476"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#nevada-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-nv"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="476"/>
          <FRBRname value="NRS"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-476/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-476/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-476/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-nv/act/nrs/chapter-476/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="nevada-legislature" href="https://www.leg.state.nv.us" showAs="Nevada State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_476">
        <num>476</num>
        <heading>EXPLOSIVES AND INFLAMMABLE</heading>
        <section eId="sec_476-005">
          <num>476.005</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Explosiveï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>As
used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires, ï¿½explosiveï¿½ means
any explosive material included in the list of explosive materials published in
the Federal Register and revised annually by the Attorney General of the United
States pursuant to 18 U.S.C. ï¿½ï¿½ 841 et seq.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2007,
1009; A2009,
685)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_476-010">
          <num>476.010</num>
          <heading>Distribution of excessive amount of dynamite, nitroglycerine,
gunpowder or other explosives; manufacture, importation, purchase or
distribution of explosives; record required; information required to be
included in record; unlawful to fail to make required entry or to make false or
misleading entry in record; notification of law enforcement agency upon storing
of explosives; penalty; exceptions.</heading>
          <subsection eId="476-010__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except in the due course of trade or as
otherwise provided in subsection 9, it is unlawful for any dealer in dynamite,
nitroglycerine, gunpowder or any other explosive to distribute to any person,
in any unusual manner, an excessive amount of such commodities.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-010__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is unlawful for any person to
manufacture, import, purchase or distribute any explosive without creating and
maintaining a written record that includes the information required pursuant to
this section.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-010__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a person involved in a transaction
is not a business or governmental entity or an agent of a business or
governmental entity, the written record required pursuant to subsection 2 must
include all the following information:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="476-010__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The name of the person.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-010__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The signature of the person.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-010__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The driverï¿½s license number of the person.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-010__subsec_3__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The residential address of the person.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-010__subsec_3__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The date of the transaction.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-010__subsec_3__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A statement of intended use.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-010__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a person involved in a transaction
is a business or governmental entity or an agent of a business or governmental
entity, the written record required pursuant to subsection 2 must include all
the following information with respect to the business or governmental entity
and the agent of the business or governmental entity, if appropriate:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="476-010__subsec_4__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The name of the business or governmental
entity.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-010__subsec_4__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The taxpayer identification number of the
business or governmental entity.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-010__subsec_4__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The principal and local addresses of the
business or governmental entity.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-010__subsec_4__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The name and any other appropriate personal
identifying information that is sufficient to identify the agent authorized to
act for the business or governmental entity.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-010__subsec_4__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The date of the transaction.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-010__subsec_4__subsec_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A statement of intended use.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-010__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>It is unlawful for any person to
knowingly and intentionally:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="476-010__subsec_5__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Make any false or misleading entry in a
written record required pursuant to subsection 2; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-010__subsec_5__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Fail to make an entry in a written record
required pursuant to subsection 2.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-010__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person who keeps any explosive for
any purpose shall do so in conformity with the regulations governing the
storage of explosives promulgated by the Attorney General of the United States
pursuant to 18 U.S.C. ï¿½ 842 and set forth in 27 C.F.R. ï¿½ï¿½ 555.201 et seq.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-010__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person who stores any explosive
shall, within 24 hours after beginning to store the explosive, notify the local
law enforcement agency and local fire department in whose jurisdiction the
explosive is stored of:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="476-010__subsec_7__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The type of explosive that is being stored;
and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-010__subsec_7__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The location of the site where the explosive
is stored.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-010__subsec_8">
            <num>8.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person who violates the provisions
of this section is guilty of a gross misdemeanor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-010__subsec_9">
            <num>9.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of this section do not
apply with respect to a person who is acting in his or her official capacity as
an owner, officer or employee of a company, corporation or partnership engaged
in the business of mining.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-010__subsec_10">
            <num>10.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="476-010__subsec_10__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Distributeï¿½ means to sell, issue, give,
transfer or otherwise dispose of an explosive.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-010__subsec_10__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Personï¿½ means any of the following:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="476-010__subsec_10__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A natural person.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="476-010__subsec_10__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Any form of business or social
organization and any other nongovernmental legal entity, including, without
limitation, a corporation, partnership, association, trust or unincorporated
organization.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="476-010__subsec_10__subsec_b__subsec_3">
                <num>(3)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A government, a political subdivision
of a government or an agency or instrumentality of a government or a political
subdivision of a government.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 309; RL ï¿½ 6574; NCL ï¿½ 10257] + [1911
C&amp;P ï¿½ 310; RL ï¿½ 6575; NCL ï¿½ 10258]—(NRS A2007,
1010)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_476-030">
          <num>476.030</num>
          <heading>Injury to person or property by careless, negligent or
unauthorized use or management of explosive or combustible substance: Penalty.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Every person who, by careless, negligent or
unauthorized use or management of any explosive or combustible substance,
injures or causes injury to the person or property of another is guilty of a
misdemeanor.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [Part 1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 300; RL ï¿½ 6565; NCL ï¿½
10248]—(NRS A1971,
1460;1979,
1482)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_476-040">
          <num>476.040</num>
          <heading>Sale or transportation of explosive or combustible substance
without conspicuous marking: Penalty.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Every
person who offers for sale, or who delivers to any warehouseman, dock, depot or
common carrier any package, cask or can containing benzine, gasoline, naphtha,
nitroglycerine, dynamite, powder or other explosive or combustible substance,
without having printed thereon in a conspicuous place in large letters the word
ï¿½Explosive,ï¿½ is guilty of a misdemeanor.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1911 C&amp;P ï¿½ 301; RL ï¿½ 6566; NCL ï¿½ 10249]—(NRS A1971,
1460;1979,
1482)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_476-060">
          <num>476.060</num>
          <heading>Procedure for prohibition of storage of explosive or combustible
materials in city or town: Petition; order; publication; exceptions; penalties.</heading>
          <subsection eId="476-060__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Whenever there is filed with the board
of county commissioners of any county a petition signed by 10 percent of the
residents of any town or incorporated city within the county, the 10 percent to
be computed from the number of persons paying taxes in the town or incorporated
city according to the last preceding assessment roll, praying that the storage
of gunpowder, explosive or combustible materials be prohibited within the
limits of such town or city, the board shall, at the meeting of such board when
the petition is filed, make and enter on the minutes of its proceedings an
order prohibiting the storage of explosives or combustible materials within
such distance of the town or city as the board may deem safe and proper, but
the distance named in the order for such storage shall not be less than one-fourth
of a mile from the limits of the town or city.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-060__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The order mentioned in subsection 1 to
be made by the board may be published by the clerk of the board of county
commissioners for 2 weeks successively in some newspaper published and printed
in the town or city to which the order applies, or a copy of the order shall be
posted conspicuously in three public places in the town or city. The
publication or posting shall constitute due notice to all concerned.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-060__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>This section does not prohibit or
prevent:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="476-060__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The storage by any person, firm or
corporation within the limit prescribed by the order of any board, of not more
than 100 pounds of black and smokeless gunpowder or rifle powder, and not more
than 500 gallons of kerosene oil.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-060__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The keeping within such limit of shotgun or
rifle shells and cartridges and cartridge percussion caps by any business firm
or individual.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-060__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The storing of powder underground in mines.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-060__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any board of county commissioners, or
any member thereof, failing, neglecting or refusing to comply with all of the
provisions of subsection 1 is guilty of a misdemeanor, and proceedings shall at
once be instituted by the district attorney, or may be instituted by any
citizen of the county against such board, or against any member thereof. Such
conviction shall ipso facto remove such board, or any member thereof so
convicted, from office. Notice of the vacancy thereby created shall be
certified by the district attorney to the Governor. Within 20 days from the
receipt of such notice, the Governor shall make appointments to fill such vacancy
as may be created.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-060__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person, firm, company or
corporation continuing to store any explosive or combustible materials within
the limit prescribed by such order and notice, after 2 weeks subsequent to the
giving of notice, or after 3 weeks subsequent to the making of such order, is
guilty of a misdemeanor.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ [1:101:1905; RL ï¿½ 1946; NCL ï¿½ 2885] + [2:101:1905; RL
ï¿½ 1947; NCL ï¿½ 2886] + [3:101:1905; RL ï¿½ 1948; NCL ï¿½ 2887]—(NRS A1967,
591;1971,
1460;1979,
1482)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_476-070">
          <num>476.070</num>
          <heading>ischarge of tracer or incendiary ammunition within certain
areas; penalty; exceptions.</heading>
          <subsection eId="476-070__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person who discharges any bullet,
projectile or ammunition of any kind which is tracer or incendiary in nature on
any grass, brush, forest or crop-covered land is guilty of a misdemeanor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-070__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>This section does not apply to:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="476-070__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any member of the Armed Forces of the United
States or the Nevada National Guard while such member is on active duty;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-070__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any law enforcement officer of this State or
the United States; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-070__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The possession or use of such ammunition on
land owned or leased by the United States when possessed or used at the
direction of an authorized official of the United States.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by1967,
1078; A1971,
1461;1979,
1483)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_476-080">
          <num>476.080</num>
          <heading>Requirements for marking container used to store explosives.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Any container used to store an explosive must
be marked in accordance with all applicable state and federal laws and
regulations.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2007,
1009)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_476-090">
          <num>476.090</num>
          <heading>Unusual sale, purchase, theft or loss of explosive: Report
required; penalty; exceptions; rebuttable presumption.</heading>
          <subsection eId="476-090__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 3, any person who has knowledge of an unusual sale, purchase, theft
or loss of any explosive shall, within 24 hours after the discovery, report the
sale, purchase, theft or loss to the local law enforcement agency and local
fire department in whose jurisdiction the sale, purchase, theft or loss
occurred. The report must contain, when possible:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="476-090__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The name, birth date and address of the
persons involved.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-090__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The amount and type of explosive involved.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-090__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any other information the person making the
report believes to be useful.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-090__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person who violates the provisions
of this section is guilty of a gross misdemeanor.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-090__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of this section do not
apply with respect to a person who is acting in his or her official capacity as
an owner, officer or employee of a company, corporation or partnership engaged
in the business of mining.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-090__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the purposes of this section, there
is a rebuttable presumption that a sale, purchase, theft or loss of any
explosive is ï¿½unusualï¿½ if that type of sale, purchase, theft or loss does not
regularly occur in the ordinary course of business.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2007,
1009)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_476-100">
          <num>476.100</num>
          <heading>Applicability ofNRS 476.010to476.100,
inclusive.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>If the provisions ofchapter 40of Title 18 of the United States Code
do not apply to an activity, substance or item pursuant to 18 U.S.C. ï¿½ 845(a),
the provisions ofNRS 476.010to476.100, inclusive, do not apply to the activity,
substance or item.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2007,
1010; A2009,
686)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_476-110">
          <num>476.110</num>
          <heading>Definitions.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>As
used inNRS 476.110to476.210, inclusive, unless the context
otherwise requires, the words and terms defined inNRS 476.120to476.160, inclusive, have the meanings
ascribed to them in those sections.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2009,
683)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_476-120">
          <num>476.120</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Bomb squad commanderï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Bomb
squad commanderï¿½ means a bomb technician who serves as the point of contact for
and speaks on behalf of a public safety bomb squad.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2009,
684)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_476-130">
          <num>476.130</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Bomb technicianï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <subsection eId="476-130__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Is certified as a bomb technician by
the Federal Bureau of Investigation; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-130__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Is an active member of a public safety
bomb squad.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2009,
684)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_476-140">
          <num>476.140</num>
          <heading>ï¿½National Guidelines for Bomb Techniciansï¿½defined.</heading>
          <subsection eId="476-140__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The requirements for certifying a bomb
technician;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-140__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The requirements for accrediting a
public safety bomb squad; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-140__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The fundamental operational doctrine of
the bomb squad profession, including, without limitation, minimum principles of
safety for that profession.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2009,
684)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_476-150">
          <num>476.150</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Public safety bomb squadï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <subsection eId="476-150__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Consists of members who are bomb
technicians; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-150__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Is accredited as a bomb squad by the
Federal Bureau of Investigation.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2009,
684)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_476-160">
          <num>476.160</num>
          <heading>ï¿½Suspected improvised explosive deviceï¿½ defined.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>ï¿½Suspected improvised explosive deviceï¿½ means
any item that, based on training, experience or circumstances, would cause a
reasonable person to believe that the item may pose an immediate threat of an
explosive or destructive nature.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2009,
684)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_476-170">
          <num>476.170</num>
          <heading>Applicability.</heading>
          <subsection eId="476-170__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions ofNRS 476.110to476.210, inclusive, apply in each county in
this State:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="476-170__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In which there is a public safety bomb squad;
and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-170__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In the absence of a memorandum of
understanding setting forth the responsibilities of each public safety bomb
squad in the county.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-170__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>In a county in which there is no public
safety bomb squad, the sheriff of the county or the sheriffï¿½s designee shall
carry out those duties of a public safety bomb squad which he or she determines
are appropriate in that county.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2009,
684)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_476-180">
          <num>476.180</num>
          <heading>Primary responsibilities of public safety bomb squads.</heading>
          <subsection eId="476-180__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Make safe any area and remove from the
area any:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="476-180__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Actual or suspected improvised explosive
device;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-180__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Explosive; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-180__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Incendiary device.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-180__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Provide legal and safe transportation,
disposal and storage of any item specified in subsection 1.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-180__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Assist the primary law enforcement
agency with the investigation of each crime where a bombing occurs or where any
improvised explosive device has been rendered safe.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-180__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Store, maintain and prepare an
inventory of all equipment used by the public safety bomb squad.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-180__subsec_5">
            <num>5.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Upon request, provide technical support
for any law enforcement agency, including, without limitation, providing
protection for any dignitary in this State.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-180__subsec_6">
            <num>6.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Prepare and participate in a program of
training relating to explosives.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-180__subsec_7">
            <num>7.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Maintain and be familiar with a library
of technical publications and other information concerning explosives.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-180__subsec_8">
            <num>8.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Maintain professional and training
liaisons with:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="476-180__subsec_8__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Other state and local bomb squads;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-180__subsec_8__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Law enforcement agencies;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-180__subsec_8__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Military units;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-180__subsec_8__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Federal agencies; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-180__subsec_8__subsec_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Professional associations.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-180__subsec_9">
            <num>9.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Compile and report to the appropriate
persons all technical data obtained by the public safety bomb squad concerning
explosive devices and incidents involving explosives that occur within the
jurisdiction of the public safety bomb squad.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-180__subsec_10">
            <num>10.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Develop programs for members of the
general public and private organizations concerning safety and awareness during
a bomb threat.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-180__subsec_11">
            <num>11.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Report to the appropriate military
unit any military ordnance which is found or recovered by the public safety
bomb squad.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2009,
684)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_476-190">
          <num>476.190</num>
          <heading>Responsibility of public safety bomb squad for certain
procedures and provision of safety for members of general public; airport
security programs.</heading>
          <subsection eId="476-190__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 2, each public safety bomb squad:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="476-190__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Is responsible for all render-safe procedures
for all actual or suspected improvised explosive devices to which the public
safety bomb squad responds; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-190__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Shall, to the extent practicable in
conducting its activities, provide maximum safety for members of the general
public and any other public safety bomb squad in accordance with theNational
Guidelines for Bomb Techniciansand theNational Strategic Plan for U.S.
Bomb Squadspublished by the National Bomb Squad Commanders Advisory Board.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-190__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>At an airport that has an airport
security program or airport emergency plan approved by the Federal Aviation
Administration of the United States Department of Transportation or the
Transportation Security Administration of the United States Department of
Homeland Security, the public safety bomb squad shall carry out the primary
responsibilities specified inNRS 476.180in accordance with the approved airport security program or airport emergency
plan.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2009,
685)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_476-200">
          <num>476.200</num>
          <heading>Plan for notification of public safety bomb squad.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Each law enforcement agency in this State
shall establish a plan to ensure the timely notification of the appropriate
public safety bomb squad of any actual or suspected improvised explosive
device.</p>
          </content>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2009,
685)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_476-210">
          <num>476.210</num>
          <heading>Duties of bomb squad commander; retention of final authority.</heading>
          <subsection eId="476-210__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Is responsible for the activities of
the public safety bomb squad concerning responses to actual or suspected
improvised explosive devices;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-210__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Shall establish policies and tactical
plans consistent with theNational Guidelines for Bomb Technicians;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-210__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Shall work cooperatively with the
appropriate law enforcement agencies to remediate any incident involving an
explosive to which the public safety bomb squad responds; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-210__subsec_4">
            <num>4.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Retains final authority for the
render-safe procedures for any incident involving an explosive to which the
public safety bomb squad responds.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2009,
685)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
        <section eId="sec_476-220">
          <num>476.220</num>
          <heading>Distribution of black powder or smokeless gunpowder to persons
under certain age; penalties.</heading>
          <subsection eId="476-220__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as otherwise provided in
subsection 2, any person who distributes:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="476-220__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Black powder to a person under the age of 18
years; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-220__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Smokeless gunpowder to a person:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="476-220__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_1">
                <num>(1)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Under the age of 18 years; or
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="476-220__subsec_1__subsec_b__subsec_2">
                <num>(2)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Under the age of 21 years, if the
smokeless gunpowder is intended for use other than in a rifle or shotgun,
ï¿½is guilty of
a misdemeanor and shall be punished by a fine of not more than $500.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-220__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person shall be deemed to be in
compliance with the provisions of subsection 1 if, before the person
distributes black powder or smokeless gunpowder to another person, the person:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="476-220__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Asks the other person to declare the intended
use for the black powder or smokeless gunpowder;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-220__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Demands that the other person present a valid
driverï¿½s license, permanent resident card, tribal identification card or other
written or documentary evidence which shows that the other person meets the
appropriate age requirement set forth in subsection 1;
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-220__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Is presented a valid driverï¿½s license,
permanent resident card, tribal identification card or other written or
documentary evidence which shows that the other person meets the appropriate
age requirement set forth in subsection 1; and
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-220__subsec_2__subsec_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Reasonably relies upon the declaration of
intended use by the other person and the driverï¿½s license, permanent resident
card, tribal identification card or other written or documentary evidence
presented by the other person.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="476-220__subsec_3">
            <num>3.</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="476-220__subsec_3__subsec_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Distributeï¿½ has the meaning ascribed to it
inNRS 476.010.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-220__subsec_3__subsec_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Permanent resident cardï¿½ means a Permanent
Resident Card issued by the United States Citizenship and Immigration Services
of the Department of Homeland Security.
ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="476-220__subsec_3__subsec_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>ï¿½Tribal identification cardï¿½ means an
identification card issued by a tribal government which satisfies the
requirements of subsection 3 ofNRS 232.006.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <authorialNote marker="history">
            <p>ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ï¿½ (Added to NRS by2011,
469; A2017,
95,1627,2276)</p>
          </authorialNote>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>